const arr = [{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"What does a 'cobweb' appearance of the CSF indicate?","answers":[{"option":"Tuberculous meningitis","bool":true},{"option":"Viral meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Viral encephalitis","bool":false},{"option":"Neurosyphilis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute pyogenic meningitis","bool":false}],"id":0},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is an indolamine derived from tryptophan?","answers":[{"option":"Leukotriene","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Chitin","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":true},{"option":"Prostaglandin","bool":false}],"id":1},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is associated with an enlargement of the posterior cranial fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Holoprosencephaly","bool":false},{"option":"Arnold-Chiari type I","bool":false},{"option":"Arnold-Chiari type II","bool":false},{"option":"Agenesis of the corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Dandy-walker syndrome","bool":true}],"id":2},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Serotonin or 5-hydroxytryptamine is synthesized from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Tri-carboxylic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Taurine","bool":false},{"option":"Tri-acyl glycerol","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":false},{"option":"Tryptophan","bool":true}],"id":3},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Agenesis of the corpus callosum is associated with which of the following symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Mental retardation","bool":true},{"option":"Loss of sensory control","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of coordination","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of speech","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of motor contrtol","bool":false}],"id":4},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"The brain magnetic resonance image (MRI) of an 8-year-old child shows a bat-wing deformity. Which condition is the most likely cause of this?","answers":[{"option":"Lissencephaly","bool":false},{"option":"Holoprosencephaly","bool":false},{"option":"Polymicrogyria","bool":false},{"option":"Neuronal heterotopia","bool":false},{"option":"Agenesis of corpus callosum","bool":true}],"id":5},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"What is dopamine synthesized from?","answers":[{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":true},{"option":"Tryptophan","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylalanine","bool":false},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":false}],"id":6},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is an autoimmune disease affecting the nicotinic acetylcholine receptors?","answers":[{"option":"Duchenne muscular dystrophy (DMD)","bool":false},{"option":"Myasthenia gravis","bool":true},{"option":"Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Guillain-Barr√© syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple sclerosis","bool":false}],"id":7},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which one of the following forms the blood-brain barrier?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Osteocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth muscle cells","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":true}],"id":8},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is not a superficial reflex?","answers":[{"option":"Plantar reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Conjunctival reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Corneal reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Abdominal reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Patellar reflex","bool":true}],"id":9},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is not a deep tendon reflex?","answers":[{"option":"Patellar reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Biceps reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Ankle reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Brachioradialis reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Conjunctival reflex","bool":true}],"id":10},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which statement is inappropriate regarding the dorsal horn of the grey matter of the spinal cord?","answers":[{"option":"It receives and processes sensory inputs","bool":false},{"option":"It is found in all levels of spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"It is less bulky in size than ventral horn of grey matter","bool":false},{"option":"It includes substantia gelatinosa which is homologous to spinal trigeminal nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"It is found in cervical region only","bool":true}],"id":11},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Lesion of the dorsal column results in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Loss of temperature sensation","bool":false},{"option":"Motor ataxia","bool":false},{"option":"Sensory ataxia","bool":true},{"option":"Loss of pain sensations","bool":false},{"option":"Apraxia","bool":false}],"id":12},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following sensations are spared in anterior cord syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Vibration, crude touch, and pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Crude touch and two point discrimination","bool":false},{"option":"Proprioception, two point discrimination, and vibration","bool":true},{"option":"Pain and temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Fine touch and pressure","bool":false}],"id":13},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Sympathetic stimulation results in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Constriction of blood vessels in the skin","bool":true},{"option":"Puppillary constriction","bool":false},{"option":"Defecation","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased force of heart contraction","bool":false},{"option":"Increased peristalsis","bool":false}],"id":14},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following nerve cell groups do not form a part of the auditory pathway?","answers":[{"option":"Trapezoid body","bool":false},{"option":"Medial geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Superior colliculi","bool":true},{"option":"Cochlear nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Spiral ganglion","bool":false}],"id":15},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"The internal cerebral vein is formed by the union of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial and deep middle cerebral vein","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cerebral vein and striate vein","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamostriate and choroidal veins","bool":true},{"option":"Superior cerebral vein and the great cerebral vein","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial cerebral vein and the basal vein","bool":false}],"id":16},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Gliosis is a process in which there is hyperplasia or hypertrophy of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Myelin sheath","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroblasts","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Fibers","bool":false}],"id":17},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Encephalocele most commonly involves which cranial fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Medial cranial fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cranial fossa","bool":true},{"option":"Middle cranial fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cranial fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral cranial fossa","bool":false}],"id":18},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What does uncal herniation cause?","answers":[{"option":"Breathing cessation","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor paralysis","bool":true},{"option":"Crescent shaped lesion","bool":false},{"option":"Kidney disease","bool":false},{"option":"Chewing difficulties","bool":false}],"id":19},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"In bacterial meningitis, compared to normal cerebrospinal fluid, which of the following is found to be typically decreased?","answers":[{"option":"Proteins","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":true},{"option":"Chloride","bool":false}],"id":20},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Cardiac and vasomotor centers are located in which of the following structures of the central nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":true},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false}],"id":21},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which structure does not pass through the foramen magnum of the skull?","answers":[{"option":"Spinal root of XI cranial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Dura mater","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":false},{"option":"Vertebral veins","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior spinal arteries","bool":false}],"id":22},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which peripheral nerve is myelinated by oligodendrocytes?","answers":[{"option":"Ophthalmic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Hypoglossal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false}],"id":23},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which cranial nerve will most likely be injured in an anterior cranial fossa fracture?","answers":[{"option":"Olfactory nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false}],"id":24},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following cavities is present in the midbrain?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral ventricles","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Third ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral aqueduct","bool":true},{"option":"Foramen of Monro","bool":false}],"id":25},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Neurotransmitters (catecholamines) are mainly derived from which amino acid?","answers":[{"option":"Tryptophan","bool":false},{"option":"Alanine","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylalanine","bool":false},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":true}],"id":26},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Where does the superior sagittal sinus drain into?","answers":[{"option":"Ethmoidal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Longitudinal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Right transverse sinus","bool":true},{"option":"Straight sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Sinusoidal sinus","bool":false}],"id":27},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following structures are constituents of the limbic system?","answers":[{"option":"Cingulate gyrus and the uncus","bool":false},{"option":"Amygdaloid nucleus, red nucleus, and vestibular nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocampal formation","bool":false},{"option":"Pulvinar of the thalamus and substantia nigra","bool":false},{"option":"Subcallosal, cingulate and parahippocampal gyri, hippocampal formation, amygdaloid nucleus, mammillary body and anterior thalamic nuclei","bool":true}],"id":28},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"In neonates, what causes acute pyogenic meningitis?","answers":[{"option":"Toxoplasma gondii","bool":false},{"option":"Necator americanus","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":true},{"option":"Neisseria meningitidis","bool":false},{"option":"Listeria monocytogenes","bool":false}],"id":29},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Damage to which of the following results in the loss of pain sensation?","answers":[{"option":"Corticospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Cuneocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal column medial lemniscal pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":true}],"id":30},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Light touch sensations are lost when which of the following is damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Rubrospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal column medial lemniscus pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Cuneocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":true}],"id":31},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following does not form the roof of the inferior horn of the lateral ventricle?","answers":[{"option":"Stria terminalis","bool":false},{"option":"Tapetum of corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Amygdala","bool":false},{"option":"Pes hippocampus","bool":true},{"option":"Tail of caudate nucleus","bool":false}],"id":32},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following structures is not part of the sub limbic cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Septal nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Epithalamus","bool":true},{"option":"Amygdala","bool":false}],"id":33},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following pairs of muscles is involved in shrugging of the shoulders and the movement of the neck?","answers":[{"option":"Trapezius and platysma","bool":false},{"option":"Trapezius and levator scapulae","bool":false},{"option":"Scalene and platysma","bool":false},{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid and longus capitus","bool":false},{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid and trapezius","bool":true}],"id":34},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A 30-year-old man reported to the emergency department with a complaint of a dog bite on the right arm. The casualty is conscious but the wound is bleeding. No previous medical or surgical history is reported. After history taking, what is the first step of management?","answers":[{"option":"Testing the dog for rabies","bool":false},{"option":"Administration of anti-rabies immunoglobulin","bool":false},{"option":"Administration of IV saline","bool":false},{"option":"Administration of anti-rabies vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Washing and debridement of the wound","bool":true}],"id":35},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following key enzymes is required for the synthesis of acetylcholine?","answers":[{"option":"Choline acetyltransferase","bool":true},{"option":"Choline acetylsynthetase","bool":false},{"option":"Choline synthetase","bool":false},{"option":"Choline acyltransferase","bool":false},{"option":"Acetyl cholineaminase","bool":false}],"id":36},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"What is another name for the hemisection of the spinal cord?","answers":[{"option":"Weber syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Brown-Sequard syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Syringomyelia","bool":false},{"option":"Wallenburg sydnrome","bool":false},{"option":"Benedikt syndrome","bool":false}],"id":37},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What is the function of Renshaw cells?","answers":[{"option":"Act as inhibitory interneurons","bool":true},{"option":"Formation of cerebrospinal fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Form a part of blood-brain barrier","bool":false},{"option":"Facilitate phagocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Act as excitatory interneurons","bool":false}],"id":38},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"A person has lost two-point discrimination in their right hand. A finding such as this is present due to a lesion in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Left medial lemniscus at medulla","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral lemniscus","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Right medial lemniscus at medulla","bool":false}],"id":39},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"The dorsal column in the spinal cord carries which of the following sensations?","answers":[{"option":"Proprioception, fine touch, and crude touch","bool":false},{"option":"Pain and temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Vibrations and touch sensations with a high degree of localization","bool":true},{"option":"Proprioception and crude touch","bool":false},{"option":"Proprioception only","bool":false}],"id":40},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is not true regarding the white matter?","answers":[{"option":"Contains mainly unmyelinated nerve fivers","bool":true},{"option":"Contains fibrous astrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Does not contain nerve cell bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Contains mainly myelinated nerve fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Contains oligodendrocytes and microglial cells","bool":false}],"id":41},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What does a positive Romberg test indicate?","answers":[{"option":"Lesion of lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Lesion of dorsal column‚Äìmedial lemniscus pathway","bool":true},{"option":"Lesion of anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Lesion of lateral corticospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Lesion of dorsal spinocerebellar tract","bool":false}],"id":42},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What does the term hyperalgesia mean?","answers":[{"option":"Loss of taste sensation","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased sensitivity to pain","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased sensation in limbs","bool":false},{"option":"Increased sensitivity to pain","bool":true},{"option":"Increased sensitivity to heat","bool":false}],"id":43},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following indicates an upper motor neuron lesion?","answers":[{"option":"Fasciculations","bool":false},{"option":"Flaccid paralysis","bool":false},{"option":"Positive Babinski sign","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased muscle tone","bool":false},{"option":"Muscle atrophy","bool":false}],"id":44},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following indicates a lesion of the lateral spinothalamic tract?","answers":[{"option":"Ipsilateral loss of pain and temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Ipsilateral loss of fine touch and two point discrimination","bool":false},{"option":"Ipsilateral loss of crude touch","bool":false},{"option":"Contralateral loss of crude touch","bool":false},{"option":"Contralateral loss of pain and temperature","bool":true}],"id":45},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What decreases in tuberculous meningitis?","answers":[{"option":"Glucose","bool":true},{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrospinal fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Proteins","bool":false}],"id":46},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What is spina bifida meningomyelocele?","answers":[{"option":"Protrusion of meninges","bool":false},{"option":"Depression of meninges and vertebral arch","bool":false},{"option":"Protrusion of meninges and spinal cord","bool":true},{"option":"Depression of meninges and spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Protrusion of spinal cord","bool":false}],"id":47},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"In developing countries, which of the following age groups is most likely to have a stroke?","answers":[{"option":"Children","bool":false},{"option":"Adolescents","bool":false},{"option":"Teenagers","bool":false},{"option":"Young adults","bool":false},{"option":"Older adults","bool":true}],"id":48},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"A single axon terminal has how many acetylcholine vesicles?","answers":[{"option":"2,000","bool":true},{"option":"300,000","bool":false},{"option":"500","bool":false},{"option":"70","bool":false},{"option":"10,000","bool":false}],"id":49},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What is the difference in ionic concentration across a membrane called?","answers":[{"option":"Diffusion potential","bool":true},{"option":"Osmolarity","bool":false},{"option":"Action potential","bool":false},{"option":"Ionizing potential","bool":false},{"option":"Concentration gradient","bool":false}],"id":50},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"The refractory period after an action potential is due to what?","answers":[{"option":"Inactivated potassium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Activated sodium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Activated potassium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Inactivated sodium channels","bool":true},{"option":"Activated calcium channels","bool":false}],"id":51},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is a predisposing factor of a saccular aneurysm?","answers":[{"option":"Infections","bool":false},{"option":"Viral infections","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial infections","bool":false},{"option":"Tumors","bool":false},{"option":"Cigarette smoking","bool":true}],"id":52},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What receptor(s) does scopolamine bind to?","answers":[{"option":"Binds reversibly to muscarinic receptors","bool":true},{"option":"Binds irreversibly to both muscarinic and nicotinic receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Binds irreversibly to muscarinic receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Binds irreversibly to nicotinic receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Binds reversibly to nicotinic receptors","bool":false}],"id":53},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What drug inhibits the storage of norepinephrine into synaptic vesicles?","answers":[{"option":"Monoamine oxidase","bool":false},{"option":"Catechol-O-methyl transferase","bool":false},{"option":"Guanethidine","bool":false},{"option":"Reserpine","bool":true},{"option":"Imipramine","bool":false}],"id":54},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Hemisection of the spinal cord will not present with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Ipsilateral loss of all sensations at the level of the lesion","bool":false},{"option":"Ipsilateral loss of dorsal column sensations below the level of the lesion","bool":false},{"option":"Contralateral pain and temperature loss below the level of the lesion","bool":false},{"option":"Ipsilateral upper motor neuron (UMN) signs at the level of the lesion","bool":true},{"option":"Ipsilateral upper motor neuron (UMN) signs below the level of the lesion","bool":false}],"id":55},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following infections causes tabes dorsalis?","answers":[{"option":"Bacillus cereus","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pyogenes","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria gonorrhoeae","bool":false},{"option":"Treponema pallidum","bool":true}],"id":56},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following structures hold the spinal cord in place?","answers":[{"option":"Denticulate ligaments and filum terminale","bool":true},{"option":"Filum terminale and conus medullaris","bool":false},{"option":"Cauda equina and conus medullaris","bool":false},{"option":"Denticulate ligaments and cauda equina","bool":false},{"option":"Denticulate ligaments and conus medullaris","bool":false}],"id":57},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following arteries do not contribute to the blood supply of midbrain?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery and its peduncular branch","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior choroidal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior cerebellar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Interpeduncular branches of the basilar artery","bool":false}],"id":58},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Pontocerebellar fibers continue as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Superior cerebellar peduncle","bool":false},{"option":"Crus Cerebri","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior cerebellar peduncle","bool":false},{"option":"Tegmentum","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebellar peduncle","bool":true}],"id":59},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Where is the pneumotaxic center located?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Lower medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":true},{"option":"Upper medulla","bool":false}],"id":60},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Hyperalgesia and allodynia signify which of the following statements?","answers":[{"option":"Tissue repair","bool":false},{"option":"No release of chemicals","bool":false},{"option":"Increased sensitivity of pain","bool":true},{"option":"Release of coagulation factors","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased sensitivity of pain","bool":false}],"id":61},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"In lower motor neuron lesions, patient develops which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperesthesia","bool":false},{"option":"Spasticity","bool":false},{"option":"Positive babinski's sign","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperreflexia","bool":false},{"option":"Muscular wasting, hypotonia","bool":true}],"id":62},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is involved in waking up the cerebral cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Substantia nigra","bool":false},{"option":"Reticular formation","bool":true},{"option":"Nucleus ambiguous","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":false}],"id":63},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following separates crus cerebri from tegmentum?","answers":[{"option":"Trapezoid body","bool":false},{"option":"Superior colliculus","bool":false},{"option":"Pontine nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Substantia nigra","bool":true},{"option":"Locus coeruleus","bool":false}],"id":64},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"A boy is trying to shoot a basketball. Which area in his brain will be assisting in bringing about this complex pattern of motor activity?","answers":[{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Globus pallidus","bool":true}],"id":65},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"The superior cerebral veins drain into which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Diploic veins","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior sagittal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Straight sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior sagittal sinus","bool":true},{"option":"Carotid sinus","bool":false}],"id":66},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following nerves is present on the lateral wall of the cavernous sinus?","answers":[{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Mandibular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Occulomotor nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Olfactory nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false}],"id":67},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What is the rate limiting enzyme of dopamine synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Monoamine oxidase","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine hydroxylase","bool":true},{"option":"Aromatic l-amino acid decarboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Catechol-O-methyltransferase","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine beta-hydroxylase","bool":false}],"id":68},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What is the effect of dopamine?","answers":[{"option":"Excitatory at D1 and D2 receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Excitatory at D1 receptor, inhibitory at D2 receptor","bool":true},{"option":"Excitatory at D2 receptor, inhibitory at D1 receptor","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibitory at D1 and D2 receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibitory at D1 receptor","bool":false}],"id":69},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"A person presents to the clinic and has difficulty in balancing and has slurred speech. The lesion is present in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":true},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrum","bool":false}],"id":70},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which enzyme converts serotonin to 5-hydroxy-3-indoleacetic acid (5-HIAA)?","answers":[{"option":"Monoamine oxidase","bool":true},{"option":"Histidine decarboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Aromatic amino acid decarboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Catechol-O-methyl transferase","bool":false},{"option":"Hydroxylase","bool":false}],"id":71},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What does acetylcholinesterase break acetylcholine into?","answers":[{"option":"Amino acid and chlorine","bool":false},{"option":"Amino acid and choline","bool":false},{"option":"Acetic acid and chlorine","bool":false},{"option":"Acetaminophen and glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Acetic acid and choline","bool":true}],"id":72},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"If a needle is placed between the third and fourth lumbar vertebra, which of the following structures will it reach?","answers":[{"option":"Sacral nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrospinal fluid","bool":true},{"option":"Coccygeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Stria terminalis","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":false}],"id":73},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017"],"question":"Which of the following structures is involved in sleep and awakening?","answers":[{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Reticular formation","bool":true},{"option":"Substantia nigra","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus ambiguus","bool":false}],"id":74},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"What enzyme degrades acetylcholine?","answers":[{"option":"Tyrosine hydroxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Thioesterase","bool":false},{"option":"Endoribonuclease","bool":false},{"option":"Pectinesterase","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholinesterase","bool":true}],"id":75},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which cranial nerve nucleus is present at the level of the superior colliculus?","answers":[{"option":"Trochlear nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal nucleus of vagus","bool":false},{"option":"Facial motor nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nucleus","bool":true}],"id":76},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which one of the following is a function of the sympathetic nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Vasoconstriction","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased heart rate","bool":false},{"option":"Increased GIT motility","bool":false},{"option":"Defecation","bool":false},{"option":"Pupil constriction","bool":false}],"id":77},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which one of the following structures is the largest component of the diencephalon?","answers":[{"option":"Epithalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":true},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":78},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"The molecular layer of the cerebellar cortex does not contain which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Neuroglia","bool":false},{"option":"Parallel fibers of granular cells axons","bool":false},{"option":"Stellate cells","bool":false},{"option":"Purkinje cells","bool":true},{"option":"Basket cells","bool":false}],"id":79},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following regarding oligodendroglia is true?","answers":[{"option":"Can myelinate more than one axon per cell","bool":true},{"option":"Helps in forming pia meningeal layer","bool":false},{"option":"Supporting cells of PNS","bool":false},{"option":"Helps in blood brain barrier formation/maintenance","bool":false},{"option":"Phagocytic cells","bool":false}],"id":80},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"What signs and symptoms will be observed as a consequence of a lesion in Wernicke's area?","answers":[{"option":"Inability to produce fluent speech","bool":false},{"option":"Inability to understand written or spoken words","bool":true},{"option":"Inability to appreciate texture of objects","bool":false},{"option":"Inability to read or write","bool":false},{"option":"Inability to interpret sounds","bool":false}],"id":81},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"What is another name for the hindbrain?","answers":[{"option":"Rhombencephalon","bool":true},{"option":"Metencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Diencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Myelencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Mesencephalon","bool":false}],"id":82},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is the most common and dangerous site of thrombosis?","answers":[{"option":"Superior saggital sinus","bool":true},{"option":"Cavernous sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior petrosal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Straight sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior saggital sinus","bool":false}],"id":83},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Subdural space is located between which of the following layers?","answers":[{"option":"Dura mater and pia mater","bool":false},{"option":"Arachnoid mater and dura mater","bool":true},{"option":"Pia mater and arachnoid mater","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":84},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is the most common disease in extrapyramidal tracts?","answers":[{"option":"Fragile X syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Huntington's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Alzheimer's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Parkinson's disease","bool":true},{"option":"Wilson's disease","bool":false}],"id":85},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following nerve cell bodies is NOT present in the posterior gray column of the spinal cord?","answers":[{"option":"Phrenic nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Substantia gelatinosa","bool":false},{"option":"Visceral afferent nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus proprius","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus dorsalis","bool":false}],"id":86},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following hypothalamic nuclei regulates circadian rhythms?","answers":[{"option":"Supraoptic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Ventromedial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Arcuate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false}],"id":87},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which part of the brain must be blocked to produce an enlargement of the third and lateral ventricles on a child's radiograph?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":true},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrum","bool":false}],"id":88},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Lacunar infarcts may occur due to the occlusion of which of the following vessels?","answers":[{"option":"Small arteries","bool":true},{"option":"Venules","bool":false},{"option":"Jugular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Basilar artery","bool":false}],"id":89},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of these is a sign of Huntington's disease?","answers":[{"option":"Cogwheel rigidity","bool":false},{"option":"Enlarged posterior fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Hallucinations","bool":false},{"option":"Resting tremors","bool":false},{"option":"Chorea","bool":true}],"id":90},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following structures cannot be appreciated at the level of the decussation of pyramids?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior spinocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal tract of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Medial lemniscus","bool":true},{"option":"Accessory nucleus","bool":false}],"id":91},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of these is not an opioid receptor?","answers":[{"option":"Œº","bool":false},{"option":"Œ¥","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha","bool":true},{"option":"Zeta","bool":false},{"option":"Œ∫","bool":false}],"id":92},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Morphine is used for relief from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Pain in limbs","bool":false},{"option":"Migraine","bool":false},{"option":"Pain in kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Referred pain","bool":false},{"option":"Chest pain","bool":true}],"id":93},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Where does the cerebellum receive information concerning muscle movement from?","answers":[{"option":"Caudate","bool":false},{"option":"Putamen","bool":false},{"option":"Macula","bool":false},{"option":"Proprioceptors","bool":true},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false}],"id":94},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What are the phagocytotic cells of the central nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Microglial cells","bool":true},{"option":"Oligodendrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Ependymal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Satellite cells","bool":false}],"id":95},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following secretes cerebrospinal fluid?","answers":[{"option":"Dura mater","bool":false},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Pia mater","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Choroid plexus","bool":true}],"id":96},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following tracts is spared in anterior cord syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Corticobulbar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Corticospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal column","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false}],"id":97},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Pyramids in the medulla are formed by which of the following fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Corticopontine fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Corticospinal fibers","bool":true},{"option":"Corticobulbar fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Rubrospinal fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibulospinal fibers","bool":false}],"id":98},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Parkinson's disease involves degeneration of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Substantia nigra","bool":true},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Corpus striatum","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false}],"id":99},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is responsible for normal maintenance of tone and equilibrium?","answers":[{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Substantia nigra","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":true},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":false}],"id":100},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"What is the function of the vestibular nucleus present in the brainstem?","answers":[{"option":"Muscle spasm","bool":false},{"option":"REM sleep and non-REM sleep","bool":false},{"option":"Antigravity muscles to maintain equilibrium","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory system","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiovascular system","bool":false}],"id":101},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"According to the World Health Organization, how long is the loss of cerebral function for it to be called a stroke?","answers":[{"option":"More than 3 minutes","bool":false},{"option":"Less than 1 hour","bool":false},{"option":"More than 1 hour","bool":false},{"option":"Atleast 3 days","bool":false},{"option":"More than 24 hours","bool":true}],"id":102},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding dural venous sinuses?","answers":[{"option":"They are present between the arachnoid and dura mater","bool":true},{"option":"The flow is bidirectional","bool":false},{"option":"They are devoid of smooth muscles","bool":false},{"option":"They are lined by endothelium","bool":false},{"option":"They have no valves","bool":false}],"id":103},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A patient presents with right-sided hemiplegia and loss of speech. Upon examination, both of his eyes deviate to the left. Damage to which artery can present with these symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior communicating artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior communicating artery","bool":false}],"id":104},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Where is the sensory nucleus of the trigeminal nerve present?","answers":[{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"C5 spinal level","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":true},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false}],"id":105},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following structures is present at the level of the oculomotor nerve nucleus?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral lemniscus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior cerebellar peduncles","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior colliculus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior colliculus","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior olivary nucleus","bool":false}],"id":106},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Facial colliculus is formed by which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Facial nerve as it loops over hypoglossal nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nerve as it loops over facial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve as it loops over principal nucleus of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve as it loops over the abducens nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Trochlear nerve as it loops over facial nerve","bool":false}],"id":107},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which artery is not part of the circle of Willis?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior communicating artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior communicating artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior cerebellar artery","bool":true}],"id":108},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which sinus does not drain at the occipital confluence?","answers":[{"option":"Straight sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior sagittal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior petrosal sinus","bool":true},{"option":"Transverse sinus","bool":false}],"id":109},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following are the only climbing fibers in the cerebellum?","answers":[{"option":"Rubrocerebellar fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Reticulocerebellar fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Cuneocerebellar fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Pontocerebellar fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Olivocerebellar fibers","bool":true}],"id":110},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is a precursor of epinephrine?","answers":[{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":true},{"option":"Histamine","bool":false},{"option":"Lysine","bool":false},{"option":"Monoamine oxidase","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":false}],"id":111},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"In what form does the brain mainly utilize energy?","answers":[{"option":"Heat","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":true},{"option":"Fats","bool":false},{"option":"Proteins","bool":false},{"option":"DNA","bool":false}],"id":112},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Lesion of the supraoptic nucleus results in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Increased oxytocin production","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased volume of urine","bool":false},{"option":"Increased volume of urine","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased prolactin production","bool":false},{"option":"Hypersexuality","bool":false}],"id":113},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which cranial nerve damage will cause respiratory issues?","answers":[{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Occulomotor nerve","bool":false}],"id":114},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What is the function of the hypothalamus?","answers":[{"option":"Sense of proprioception","bool":false},{"option":"Coordination of motor functions","bool":false},{"option":"Speech control","bool":false},{"option":"Memory formation","bool":false},{"option":"Sympathetic control","bool":true}],"id":115},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which nerve passes through foramen rotundum?","answers":[{"option":"Lesser petrosal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Ophthalmic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Mandibular nerve","bool":false}],"id":116},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following hypothalamic nucleus acts as an osmoreceptor?","answers":[{"option":"Supraoptic nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Paraventricular nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Preoptic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus","bool":false}],"id":117},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is the correct statement regarding the cerebral cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Broca area is area 3, 1, and 2","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary auditory cortex relates perception of sound with past experiences","bool":true},{"option":"Somatosensory area 1 is located in the precentral gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Widespread damage to bilateral somatosensory area 1 causes astereognosis","bool":false},{"option":"The visual cortex lies in the temporal lobe","bool":false}],"id":118},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following terms refers to disease constantly present in a small population?","answers":[{"option":"Epidemic","bool":false},{"option":"Pandemic","bool":false},{"option":"Endemic","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Outbreak","bool":false}],"id":119},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"What is the rate of production of cerebrospinal fluid (CSF)?","answers":[{"option":"250-300 ml/day","bool":false},{"option":"500-550 ml/day","bool":true},{"option":"350-400 ml/day","bool":false},{"option":"150-200 ml/day","bool":false},{"option":"50-150 ml/day","bool":false}],"id":120},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"What is the function of the reticular activating system?","answers":[{"option":"Control of emotion and behavior","bool":false},{"option":"Control of the autonomic functions","bool":false},{"option":"Alertness and wakefulness","bool":true},{"option":"Sensory relay","bool":false},{"option":"Memory","bool":false}],"id":121},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following hypothalamic nucleus is responsible for increasing the heart rate and blood pressure?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberomamillary nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Supraoptic nucleus","bool":false}],"id":122},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"A 25-year-old man develops thrombosis of the anterior spinal artery. Which of the following regions will be affected the most?","answers":[{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":true},{"option":"Mid-brain","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false}],"id":123},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following organisms causes chronic bacterial meningoencephalitis?","answers":[{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis","bool":true},{"option":"Neisseria meningitidis","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium falciparum","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes simplex","bool":false}],"id":124},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Regarding myelin sheath around axons, what is correct?","answers":[{"option":"Myelin sheath is proportional to the diameter of axon","bool":false},{"option":"Neurons in peripheral nervous system is myelinated by oligodendrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Starts developing in fetal life and continues till one year","bool":true},{"option":"Formed by astrocytes in brain","bool":false},{"option":"Nodes of ranvier are not present in CNS","bool":false}],"id":125},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Where are the cell bodies of postganglionic neurons of parasympathetic fibers located?","answers":[{"option":"Cell bodies in central nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Sympathetic trunk","bool":false},{"option":"Autonomic ganglia in pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"Ganglion in the visceral walls","bool":true},{"option":"Autonomic ganglia in abdomen","bool":false}],"id":126},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Histamine is synthesized from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Methionine","bool":false},{"option":"Proline","bool":false},{"option":"Histidine","bool":true},{"option":"Serine","bool":false},{"option":"Valine","bool":false}],"id":127},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"What is the rate limiting enzyme in serotonin synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Mono amine oxidase","bool":false},{"option":"Tryptophan hydroxylase","bool":true},{"option":"5-hydroxy tryptophane decarboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Dopa decarboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Aldehyde dehydrogenase","bool":false}],"id":128},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following nerves is not present at the lateral wall of the cavernous sinus?","answers":[{"option":"Ophthalmic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"6th cranial nerve","bool":true},{"option":"3rd cranial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"4th cranial nerve","bool":false}],"id":129},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which one of the following is formed by cells in the alar plate?","answers":[{"option":"Autonomic ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Motor neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior gray horn","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior gray horn","bool":false}],"id":130},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which neurotransmitter is secreted by the Raphe nuclei that also plays a role in non-REM sleep?","answers":[{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Noradrenaline","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":true},{"option":"Adrenaline","bool":false},{"option":"Gamma-aminobutyric acid (GABA)","bool":false}],"id":131},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which neurotransmitter is most commonly released by pre-ganglionic sympathetic neurons?","answers":[{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Gamma-aminobutyric acid (GABA)","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":true},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false}],"id":132},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following cavities is present in the diencephalon?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral ventricles","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Third ventricle","bool":true},{"option":"Fourth ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral aqueduct","bool":false}],"id":133},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"The neostriatum consists of which of the following pairs of structures?","answers":[{"option":"Putamen and lentiform nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Lentiform and globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Putamen and globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Lentiform and caudate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Putamen and caudate nucleus","bool":true}],"id":134},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"The suprachiasmatic nucleus is responsible for which of the following functions?","answers":[{"option":"Thermoregulation","bool":false},{"option":"Regulation of body's circadian rhythym","bool":true},{"option":"Release of oxytocin","bool":false},{"option":"Release of anti-diuretic hormone (ADH)","bool":false},{"option":"Control of feeding impulses","bool":false}],"id":135},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is the corpus striatum a part of?","answers":[{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Limbic system","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":true},{"option":"Reticular formation","bool":false}],"id":136},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which one of the following is not a dural fold?","answers":[{"option":"Falx cerebelli","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragma sellae","bool":false},{"option":"Tentorium cerebelli","bool":false},{"option":"Falx cerebri","bool":false},{"option":"Hypophysis cerebri","bool":true}],"id":137},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A newborn baby was brought to the neurology outpatient department because the large size of the fetal head-MRI shows fluid in the lateral ventricle. The appropriate part of the lateral ventricle formed by the head of the caudate nucleus is?","answers":[{"option":"Superior horn","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior horn","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior horn","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior horn","bool":false},{"option":"Medial horn","bool":false}],"id":138},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A 36-year-old man fell from a height of 10 feet. As a consequence, he now suffers from incontinence and weakness in the lower limbs. Which of the following statements is correct?","answers":[{"option":"Imaging of dorsal spine should be done","bool":false},{"option":"Imaging of lumbosacral region should be done","bool":true},{"option":"Involvement of cervical spine C4 level","bool":false},{"option":"The middle cerebral artery is involved","bool":false},{"option":"The posterior cerebral artery is involved","bool":false}],"id":139},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which types of cells are not present in the cerebellar cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Granule cells","bool":false},{"option":"Stellate cells","bool":false},{"option":"Golgi cells","bool":false},{"option":"Basket cells","bool":false},{"option":"Pyramidal cells","bool":true}],"id":140},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"The caudate nucleus, putamen, and the globus pallidus collectively make up which structure?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Limbic system","bool":false},{"option":"Basal nuclei","bool":true},{"option":"Reticular formation","bool":false},{"option":"Amygdala","bool":false}],"id":141},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which nucleus of the hypothalamus contains the satiety center?","answers":[{"option":"Paraventricular nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Ventromedial nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Supraoptic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Posterolateral nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus","bool":false}],"id":142},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following brain structures is responsible for emotional memory?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocampus","bool":false},{"option":"Amygdala","bool":true},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false}],"id":143},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following characterizes upper motor neuron lesions?","answers":[{"option":"Fasiculations","bool":false},{"option":"Disuse atrophy","bool":true},{"option":"Hypoactive muscle stretch reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased muscle tone","bool":false},{"option":"Flaccid paralysis","bool":false}],"id":144},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which receptors receive stimuli immediate from external surroundings?","answers":[{"option":"Proprioreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Chemoreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Exteroreceptors","bool":true},{"option":"Enteroreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Teloreceptors","bool":false}],"id":145},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"The nerve endings at the end of the receptor have a receptor potential due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Change in potential","bool":true},{"option":"Adaptation","bool":false},{"option":"Excitatory post synaptic potential","bool":false},{"option":"End plate potential","bool":false},{"option":"Accommodation","bool":false}],"id":146},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"In a T2WI section magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), the cerebrospinal fluid appears as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Bright","bool":true},{"option":"Grey","bool":false},{"option":"Jet black","bool":false},{"option":"Dark","bool":false},{"option":"Black","bool":false}],"id":147},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is responsible for dynamic and static control of muscle spindles?","answers":[{"option":"Withdrawal reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Gamma motor neurons","bool":true},{"option":"Intrafusal nuclear chain","bool":false},{"option":"Beta motor neuron","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha motor neurons","bool":false}],"id":148},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following happens in Parkinson's disease?","answers":[{"option":"D3 receptors are destroyed","bool":false},{"option":"D1 receptors are destroyed","bool":false},{"option":"D2 receptors are destroyed","bool":false},{"option":"Dopaminergic neurons are destroyed","bool":true},{"option":"All of these","bool":false}],"id":149},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"REM sleep is characterized by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"High voltage, low frequency EEG activity","bool":false},{"option":"Rapid conjugate movements of the eye balls","bool":true},{"option":"Alpha waves of EEG","bool":false},{"option":"70% - 80% of the total sleeping period","bool":false},{"option":"Absence of dreams","bool":false}],"id":150},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A 34-year-old man complains of hemisensory loss and hemiparesis of the leg and foot of the contralateral side of the body. He also has difficulty in identifying objects and has developed personality changes. His MRI shows a compromised area with reduced blood supply. Which artery is responsible for these losses?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior inferior cerebellar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cerebral artery","bool":true}],"id":151},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"L-DOPA is converted to dopamine by which of the following enzymes?","answers":[{"option":"DOPA decarboxylase","bool":true},{"option":"DOPA carboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"DOPA hydroxylase","bool":false},{"option":"DOPA reductase","bool":false},{"option":"DOPA oxidase","bool":false}],"id":152},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Damage to which part of the brain results in a condition called athetosis?","answers":[{"option":"Globus pallidus","bool":true},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Putamen","bool":false},{"option":"Caudate","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":153},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"What is the biologically active amine form of phenylalanine?","answers":[{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":false},{"option":"Valine","bool":false},{"option":"Tryptamine","bool":false},{"option":"Taurine","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":true}],"id":154},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which structure is present deep in the lateral sulcus?","answers":[{"option":"Insula","bool":true},{"option":"Primary motor cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary motor cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Primary sensory cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Supplementary motor area","bool":false}],"id":155},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the essential amino acids is used to synthesize L-DOPA?","answers":[{"option":"Arachidonic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylalanine","bool":true},{"option":"Linoleic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":false},{"option":"Linolenic acid","bool":false}],"id":156},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following sensations is detected by nociceptors?","answers":[{"option":"Taste","bool":false},{"option":"Pain","bool":true},{"option":"Temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Vibration","bool":false}],"id":157},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which nucleus of the hypothalamus is involved in the regulation of thirst and hunger?","answers":[{"option":"Paraventricular nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Supraoptic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Ventromedial nucleus","bool":false}],"id":158},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is the first choice of modality for diagnosing and examining suspected spinal cord lesions in patients who have suffered trauma?","answers":[{"option":"Positron emission tomography scan","bool":false},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging","bool":true},{"option":"X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Computed tomography scan","bool":false},{"option":"Electroencephalography","bool":false}],"id":159},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A patient is suffering from wakefulness and narcolepsy. Which one of the following is affected?","answers":[{"option":"Reticular formation","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebelllum","bool":false},{"option":"Spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Medial lemniscus","bool":false},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false}],"id":160},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which one of the following innervates intrafusal muscle fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Both alpha and gamma fibers","bool":false},{"option":"B fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Unmyelinated fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Gamma fibers","bool":true}],"id":161},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which one of the fibers are used by sensory receptors to carry impulse from the periphery to the central nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Efferent fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Preganglionic","bool":false},{"option":"Free nerve endings","bool":false},{"option":"Postganglionic","bool":false},{"option":"Afferent fibers","bool":true}],"id":162},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is responsible for fine hand movements?","answers":[{"option":"Premotor cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrum","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Sensory association centre","bool":false},{"option":"Primary motor cortex","bool":true}],"id":163},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following waves are seen when a person is awake and is alert?","answers":[{"option":"Theta waves","bool":false},{"option":"Delta waves","bool":false},{"option":"Beta waves","bool":true},{"option":"Low voltage spindles","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha waves","bool":false}],"id":164},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Association fibers are the nerve fibers that connect different regions within the same hemisphere. Which of the following is categorized as the association fiber?","answers":[{"option":"Fornix","bool":false},{"option":"Internal capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Cingulum","bool":true},{"option":"External capsule","bool":false}],"id":165},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"To which of the following classes do the endorphins belong?","answers":[{"option":"Amine","bool":false},{"option":"Steroids","bool":false},{"option":"Catecholamines","bool":false},{"option":"Monoamine","bool":false},{"option":"Peptide","bool":true}],"id":166},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is associated with increased dopamine levels?","answers":[{"option":"Global aphasia without hemiparesis","bool":false},{"option":"Schizophrenia","bool":true},{"option":"Parkinson's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Agnosia","bool":false},{"option":"Alzheimer's disease","bool":false}],"id":167},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is not derived from tyrosine?","answers":[{"option":"Serotonin","bool":true},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenaline","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false}],"id":168},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Acetylcholine increases the permeability of which of the following ions when it binds to nicotinic receptors at the postsynaptic neuron?","answers":[{"option":"Sodium","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Magnesium","bool":false}],"id":169},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Damage to which structure causes Parkinson's disease?","answers":[{"option":"Globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Substantia nigra","bool":true},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Putamen","bool":false},{"option":"Caudate","bool":false}],"id":170},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Hemiballismus is caused due to damage to which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Putamen","bool":false},{"option":"Globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Corpus striatum","bool":false},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":true},{"option":"Caudate","bool":false}],"id":171},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016"],"question":"What is the frequency range of beta waves?","answers":[{"option":"14-80 cycles per second","bool":true},{"option":"35-140 cycles per second","bool":false},{"option":"Less than 3.5 cycles per second","bool":false},{"option":"8-13 cycles per second","bool":false},{"option":"4-7 cycles per second","bool":false}],"id":172},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016"],"question":"In which of the following states do beta waves occur?","answers":[{"option":"Deep sleep","bool":false},{"option":"Resting state","bool":false},{"option":"Increased mental activity","bool":true},{"option":"Brain disorders","bool":false},{"option":"Emotional stress","bool":false}],"id":173},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016"],"question":"Where are the cell bodies of postganglionic parasympathetic neurons located?","answers":[{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Central nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Brainstem","bool":false},{"option":"Near the target organs","bool":true}],"id":174},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016"],"question":"Which enzyme is involved in the breakdown of serotonin?","answers":[{"option":"Catechol-O-methyl transferase","bool":false},{"option":"Aromatic amino acid decarboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Monoamine oxidase","bool":true},{"option":"Hydroxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Histidine decarboxylase","bool":false}],"id":175},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016"],"question":"Floor of inferior horn of lateral ventricle is formed by?","answers":[{"option":"Amygdaloid nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Caudate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocampus","bool":true},{"option":"Corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Septum pellucidum","bool":false}],"id":176},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016"],"question":"Hemisection of the spinal cord produces motor loss on the side of the lesion. Where will the loss of temperature and pain sensation take place?","answers":[{"option":"Contralateral side","bool":true},{"option":"No sensory loss","bool":false},{"option":"Ipsilateral side","bool":false},{"option":"Ipsilateral upper limbs, contralateral lower limbs","bool":false},{"option":"Sensory loss on both sides","bool":false}],"id":177},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2016"],"question":"Where does the third order neuronal cell body of the spinothalamic tract lie?","answers":[{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":false},{"option":"Contralateral thalamus","bool":true},{"option":"Ipsilateral thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus gracilis","bool":false}],"id":178},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding Kluver-Bucy syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Hyper-sexuality","bool":false},{"option":"Hyper-orality","bool":false},{"option":"Bilateral paralysis","bool":true},{"option":"Hyperphagia","bool":false},{"option":"Lack of emotions","bool":false}],"id":179},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017"],"question":"The visual pathway passes through which part of the internal capsule?","answers":[{"option":"Sublenticular part","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior limb","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior limb","bool":false},{"option":"Genu","bool":false},{"option":"Retrolenticular part","bool":true}],"id":180},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017"],"question":"The auditory pathway is linked to which part of the internal capsule?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior limb","bool":false},{"option":"Genu","bool":false},{"option":"Sublentiform part","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior limb","bool":false},{"option":"Retrolentiform part","bool":false}],"id":181},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017"],"question":"What are the cardinal signs of Parkinson‚Äôs disease?","answers":[{"option":"Resting tremor, bradykinesia, muscle rigidity","bool":true},{"option":"Myoclonus, athetosis, muscle rigidity","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Essential tremor, bradykinesia, chorea","bool":false},{"option":"Resting tremor, postural instability, and hemiballismus","bool":false}],"id":182},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is true regarding the lateral medullary syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"There may be analgesia and thermoanesthesia on the contralateral side of the face","bool":false},{"option":"The nucleus ambiguus of the same side may be damaged","bool":true},{"option":"There may be evidence of seizures","bool":false},{"option":"Ipsilateral trunk and extremity hypalgesia and thermoanesthesia","bool":false},{"option":"May be caused by a thrombosis of the anterior inferior cerebellar artery","bool":false}],"id":183},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017"],"question":"Histamine is formed in which of the following steps?","answers":[{"option":"Decarboxylation of histidine","bool":true},{"option":"Deamination of methionine","bool":false},{"option":"Hydroxylation of proline","bool":false},{"option":"Methylation of serine","bool":false},{"option":"Glycosylation of glycine","bool":false}],"id":184},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is most likely to result from a disruption of blood supply to the brain?","answers":[{"option":"Vascular dementia","bool":true},{"option":"Frontotemporal dementia","bool":false},{"option":"Alzheimer's dementia","bool":false},{"option":"Dementia with Lewy bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Idiopathic dementia","bool":false}],"id":185},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017"],"question":"Which of the following neurotransmitters is involved in the conduction of superficial pain?","answers":[{"option":"Tryptophan","bool":false},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Vasoactive intestinal peptide","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":true},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":false}],"id":186},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017"],"question":"Weakness of the lateral rectus occurs from damage to which nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false}],"id":187},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017"],"question":"Which of the following statement is correct regarding nerve fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Blood vessels run in the endoneurium","bool":true},{"option":"The perineurium surrounds many nerve bundles into one nerve fiber (called the nerve proper)","bool":false},{"option":"The toughest part is the perineurium","bool":false},{"option":"The epineurium encloses a single nerve fiber and adheres it to other nerve fibers to form a nerve bundle","bool":false},{"option":"The endoneurium surrounds the nerve bundles","bool":false}],"id":188},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is not a normal constituent of cerebrospinal fluid?","answers":[{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":true},{"option":"K+","bool":false},{"option":"Na+","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma proteins","bool":false}],"id":189},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017"],"question":"Which nucleus receives information about proprioception from the head and neck?","answers":[{"option":"Mesencephalic nucleus of the trigeminal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Facial nerve nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal nucleus of the trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Principal pontine nucleus of the trigeminal nerve","bool":false}],"id":190},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017"],"question":"Which region is compressed in tonsillar herniation?","answers":[{"option":"Lumbar spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Diencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical spinal cord","bool":false}],"id":191},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017"],"question":"Which of the following symptoms are not observed in cerebellar disease?","answers":[{"option":"Slurred speech","bool":false},{"option":"Rigidity","bool":true},{"option":"Unsteady gait","bool":false},{"option":"Dysarthria","bool":false},{"option":"Impaired coordination","bool":false}],"id":192},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is not true about the hypothalamus?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior nucleus controls sympathetic system","bool":false},{"option":"Preoptic nucleus releases GnRH","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus controls circadian rhythms","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior nucleus controls sympathetic system","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral nucleus controls hunger","bool":false}],"id":193},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Lesions in which of the following results in sensory ataxia?","answers":[{"option":"Dorsal column-medial lemniscus pathway","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Corticospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal spinocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Ventral spinocerebellar tract","bool":false}],"id":194},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Where does an action potential begin?","answers":[{"option":"Neuronal body","bool":false},{"option":"Axon hillock","bool":true},{"option":"Soma","bool":false},{"option":"Dendrite","bool":false},{"option":"Synapse","bool":false}],"id":195},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which glucose transporter is seen in the brain?","answers":[{"option":"GLUT-2","bool":false},{"option":"GLUT-5","bool":false},{"option":"GLUT-4","bool":false},{"option":"SGLT-1","bool":false},{"option":"GLUT-3","bool":true}],"id":196},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following, in cerebrospinal fluid (CSF), is a marker for bacterial infection?","answers":[{"option":"Markedly decreased glucose level","bool":true},{"option":"Negative gram stain","bool":false},{"option":"Clear appearance of CSF","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased protein level","bool":false}],"id":197},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following findings in the CSF indicates viral infection?","answers":[{"option":"Cloudy appearance","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Increased protein","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Increased glucose","bool":false}],"id":198},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What is the oscillation or permanent rhythmic contraction of skeletal muscles referred to?","answers":[{"option":"Clonus","bool":true},{"option":"Rigidity","bool":false},{"option":"Tonic spasm","bool":false},{"option":"Athetosis","bool":false},{"option":"Chorea","bool":false}],"id":199},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of these cerebrovascular diseases is not because of hypertension?","answers":[{"option":"Slit hemorrage","bool":false},{"option":"Meningitis","bool":true},{"option":"Hyaline arteriolar sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Lacunar infarcts","bool":false},{"option":"Acute hypertensive encephalopathy","bool":false}],"id":200},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What condition involves deprivation of oxygen to brain tissue?","answers":[{"option":"Hydrocephalus","bool":false},{"option":"Meningocele","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperalgesia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoxia","bool":true},{"option":"Hyperoxia","bool":false}],"id":201},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of these is a risk factor for saccular aneurysms?","answers":[{"option":"Parkinson's","bool":false},{"option":"Alzheimer's","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes","bool":false},{"option":"Poliomyelitis","bool":false},{"option":"Ehler-Dahlos syndrome","bool":true}],"id":202},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of these most accurately describes stroke?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebrovascular diseases caused by damage to blood vessels","bool":true},{"option":"Accumulation of excess CSF","bool":false},{"option":"Increased number of glial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Genetic malformations of the brain","bool":false},{"option":"Infection of the brain","bool":false}],"id":203},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of these occurs in viral meningitis?","answers":[{"option":"Neutrophils decrease","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose increases","bool":false},{"option":"Proteins decrease","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocytes increase","bool":true},{"option":"Bacteria infection","bool":false}],"id":204},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is not a feature of acute bacterial meningitis?","answers":[{"option":"Headache","bool":false},{"option":"Neck stiffness","bool":false},{"option":"Clouding of consciousness","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrospinal fluid with increased glucose content","bool":true},{"option":"Photophobia","bool":false}],"id":205},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What abnormality leads to Parkinson disease?","answers":[{"option":"Lack of sleep","bool":false},{"option":"Trinucleotide repeats","bool":false},{"option":"Deficiency in iron","bool":false},{"option":"Damage to subtantia nigra","bool":true},{"option":"Damage to spinal cord","bool":false}],"id":206},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of these is not a sign of Parkinson's disease?","answers":[{"option":"Rigidity","bool":false},{"option":"Tremors","bool":false},{"option":"Chorea","bool":true},{"option":"Postural instability","bool":false},{"option":"Bradykinesia","bool":false}],"id":207},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What is the preferred imaging modality in spinal cord lesions?","answers":[{"option":"X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"MRI","bool":true},{"option":"PET/CT","bool":false},{"option":"Myelography","bool":false},{"option":"CT scan","bool":false}],"id":208},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What type of hydrocephalus is produced by stenosis of cerebral aqueduct?","answers":[{"option":"Non obstructive hydrocephalus","bool":false},{"option":"Non communicating hydrocephalus","bool":true},{"option":"Communicating hydrocephalus","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocephalus ex vacuo","bool":false},{"option":"Normal pressure hydrocephalus","bool":false}],"id":209},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Regarding Guillain-Barre syndrome, which of the following is true?","answers":[{"option":"It is an acute demyelinating polyradiculoneuropathy","bool":true},{"option":"It is a non inflammatory disorder","bool":false},{"option":"It is an infective polyneuropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Miller Fisher is a common variant","bool":false},{"option":"It is a chronic demyelinating mononeuropathy multiplex","bool":false}],"id":210},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What part of corpus callosum is related to visual association?","answers":[{"option":"Rostrum","bool":false},{"option":"Body","bool":false},{"option":"Isthmus","bool":false},{"option":"Splenium","bool":true},{"option":"Genu","bool":false}],"id":211},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What part of the brain is the Papez circuit associated with?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebral cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Brainstem","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Limbic system","bool":true},{"option":"Reticular formation","bool":false}],"id":212},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What occurs when you tap a muscle tendon with a clinical hammer?","answers":[{"option":"The hammer breaks","bool":false},{"option":"Nothing","bool":false},{"option":"The tendon snaps","bool":false},{"option":"Stretch reflex","bool":true},{"option":"Muscle relaxation","bool":false}],"id":213},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following statements regarding action potentials is incorrect?","answers":[{"option":"Potassium channels open more slowly than sodium channels","bool":false},{"option":"During depolarization, the potassium ions diffuse into the axon","bool":true},{"option":"Potassium leaks through leak channels at resting state","bool":false},{"option":"During the resting state, the sodium channels are closed","bool":false},{"option":"During depolarization, the sodium ions diffuse into the axon","bool":false}],"id":214},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Monoamine oxidase (MAO) and catechol-O-methyltransferase (COMT) are primarily responsible for which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Activation of acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Inactivation of aldosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Activation of catecholamines","bool":false},{"option":"Inactivation of catecholamines","bool":true},{"option":"Activation of non-catecholamines","bool":false}],"id":215},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is not part of the pathway of visual reflex?","answers":[{"option":"Main motor nucleus of 3rd cranial nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Pretectal nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Edinger-Westphal nucleus of 3rd cranial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Short ciliary nerve","bool":false}],"id":216},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"If you inserted a needle between the 3rd and 4th lumbar vertebra, you would probably hit which structure?","answers":[{"option":"Filum terminale","bool":false},{"option":"Sacral enlargement","bool":false},{"option":"Cauda equina","bool":true},{"option":"Femoral nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Conus medularis","bool":false}],"id":217},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of these statements is incorrect regarding sleep disorder?","answers":[{"option":"Nocturia - waking up multiple times in the night to urinate","bool":false},{"option":"Nighttime enuresis - voluntary urination during sleep","bool":true},{"option":"Sleep apnea - interrupted breathing while sleeping","bool":false},{"option":"Insomnia - difficulty falling asleep","bool":false},{"option":"Bed wetting - involuntary urination during sleep","bool":false}],"id":218},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What is the other name for flexor reflex?","answers":[{"option":"Nociceptor/pain reflex","bool":true},{"option":"Muscle stretch reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Pupillary reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Golgi tendon reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Accomodation reflex","bool":false}],"id":219},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What does the myogram of a crossed extensor reflex show?","answers":[{"option":"Slow onset and prolonged predischarge","bool":false},{"option":"Fast onset and prolonged predischarge","bool":false},{"option":"Slow onset and fast predischarge","bool":false},{"option":"Fast onset and prolonged predischarge","bool":false},{"option":"Slow onset and prolonged afterdischarge","bool":true}],"id":220},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What is a tract?","answers":[{"option":"A bundle of neurons that transmit nerve impulses between the ventral and dorsal parts of the body","bool":false},{"option":"A bundle of axons that transmit nerve impulses between the superior and inferior parts of the body","bool":true},{"option":"A bundle of axons that transmit nerve impulses between the left and right sides of the body","bool":false},{"option":"A bundle of neurons that transmit nerve impulses between the superior and inferior parts of the body","bool":false},{"option":"A bundle of axons that transmit nerve impulses between the anterior and posterior parts of the body","bool":false}],"id":221},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"A circuit receives a collateral axon from the output neuron, thus re-stimulating its own dendrites. What is this circuit called?","answers":[{"option":"Relay circuit","bool":false},{"option":"Excitatory circuit","bool":false},{"option":"Divergence circuit","bool":false},{"option":"Reverbratory circuit","bool":true},{"option":"Electrical circuit","bool":false}],"id":222},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Hemisection of the spinal cord produces motor loss on the same side of the body as the lesion. Where does the loss of two-point discrimination occur?","answers":[{"option":"No sensory loss occurs","bool":false},{"option":"Ipsilateral side below the lesion","bool":true},{"option":"Upper limbs only","bool":false},{"option":"Ipsilateral side of the face, contralateral side of the trunk","bool":false},{"option":"Contralateral side at the level of the lesion","bool":false}],"id":223},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What is the pain radiating to the shoulder due to myocardial infarction called?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic pain","bool":false},{"option":"Slow pain","bool":false},{"option":"Visceral pain","bool":false},{"option":"Referred pain","bool":true},{"option":"Fast pain","bool":false}],"id":224},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which is the correct sequence of components of a reflex arc?","answers":[{"option":"Receptor ‚ûú sensory neuron ‚ûú motor neuron ‚ûú association ‚ûú effector","bool":false},{"option":"Sensory neuron ‚ûú receptor ‚ûú association ‚ûú Sensory neuron ‚ûú effector","bool":false},{"option":"Sensory neuron ‚ûú receptor ‚ûú association ‚ûú motor neuron ‚ûú effector","bool":false},{"option":"Sensory neuron ‚ûú receptor ‚ûú association ‚ûú effector ‚ûú motor neuron","bool":false},{"option":"Receptor ‚ûú sensory neuron ‚ûú association ‚ûú motor neuron ‚ûú effector","bool":true}],"id":225},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following tests is most suitable for the diagnosis of spinal cord lesions?","answers":[{"option":"Complete blood count (CBC) report","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Computed tomography scan","bool":false},{"option":"Electroencephalography (EEG)","bool":false},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging","bool":true}],"id":226},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following arteries supply blood to the spinal cord?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior and posterior spinal artery, branches of the ascending spinal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinal artery, branch of the vertebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior and posterior spinal artery, branch of the basilar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior spinal artery, branch of the basilar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior and posterior spinal artery, branches of the internal carotid","bool":false}],"id":227},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is an appropriate statement regarding medulla oblongata?","answers":[{"option":"Cuneate tubercle is medial to gracile tubercle","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebellar peduncle connects medulla to the cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Cuneate tubercle is lateral to gracile tubercle","bool":true},{"option":"Houses principal nucleus of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Olives are present medial to the pyramids","bool":false}],"id":228},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is the most appropriate statement regarding pons?","answers":[{"option":"The trapezoid body is made of fibers from the cochlear nuclei and the nuclei of the trapezoid body","bool":true},{"option":"Fibers of the facial nerve wrap around the nucleus of the trochlear nerve, forming the facial colliculus","bool":false},{"option":"The fibers from the motor nucleus of the trigeminal nerve exit the pons posteriorly","bool":false},{"option":"The motor nucleus of the trigeminal nerve lies lateral to the sensory nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"The vestibular area lies medial to the sulcus limitans","bool":false}],"id":229},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding the functions of medulla oblongata?","answers":[{"option":"Conscious control of breathing","bool":true},{"option":"Regulation of digestion","bool":false},{"option":"Passing information between brain and spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Regulation of heartbeat","bool":false},{"option":"Unconscious control of breathing","bool":false}],"id":230},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"The human reticular system has which of the following features?","answers":[{"option":"The reticular inhibitory area is located in the pons","bool":false},{"option":"Has connections with the basal nuclei","bool":true},{"option":"Do not have an association with the limbic system","bool":false},{"option":"Locus coeruleus secretes dopamine and epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"The raphe nuclei are large nuclei situated in the lateral portion of the medulla and cerebellum","bool":false}],"id":231},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is inappropriate regarding Sydenham's chorea?","answers":[{"option":"It is a typical exaggeration of associated movements during voluntary activity","bool":false},{"option":"It is accompanied by muscular hypertonia","bool":true},{"option":"It is a complication of rheumatic fever","bool":false},{"option":"Patient usually recovers spontaneously in 1 to 4 months","bool":false},{"option":"It is characterized by fine, disorganized and random movements of extremities, face and tongue","bool":false}],"id":232},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is appropriate regarding the blood supply of the brain?","answers":[{"option":"The internal carotid artery has no branches other than cerebral arteries","bool":false},{"option":"The visual cortex is supplied by the posterior cerebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"The posterior inferior cerebellar artery is a branch of the basilar artery","bool":false},{"option":"The anterior cerebral artery occlusion may lead to aphasia if the left hemisphere is affected","bool":false},{"option":"The internal capsule is supplied by the lenticulostriate arteries, branches of the anterior cerebral artery","bool":false}],"id":233},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which structure lies posterior to the olives?","answers":[{"option":"Superior cerebellar peduncle","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebellar peduncle","bool":false},{"option":"Pontomedullary junction","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior cerebellar peduncle","bool":true},{"option":"Pyramid","bool":false}],"id":234},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Damage to which nucleus presents as loss of touch sensations on the face?","answers":[{"option":"Nucleus of facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus of hypoglossal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Sensory nucleus of trigeminal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Motor nucleus of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus of abducens nerve","bool":false}],"id":235},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which dural venous sinus is located on the floor of the middle cranial fossa at the side of the sphenoid bone?","answers":[{"option":"Superior petrosal","bool":false},{"option":"Sigmoid","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital","bool":false},{"option":"Straight","bool":false},{"option":"Cavernous","bool":true}],"id":236},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Regarding serotonin, which of these is the best statement?","answers":[{"option":"Almost all of the serotonin in the body is stored in platelets","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin is also called 6-HT","bool":false},{"option":"It does not play a role in pain perception","bool":false},{"option":"It causes a feeling of happiness and well-being","bool":true},{"option":"It is synthesized from tyrosine","bool":false}],"id":237},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which receptors work via activation of adenyl cyclase and an increase in intracellular cAMP?","answers":[{"option":"Alpha 1 adrenergic receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha 2 adrenergic receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Nicotinic receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Muscarinic receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Beta 1 adrenergic receptors","bool":true}],"id":238},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of these is the best statement regarding bio-molecules?","answers":[{"option":"Serotonin causes migraines","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin is used to treat hypercoagulability","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin and dopamine are synthesized from the same precursor","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine is used to treat hypotension","bool":true},{"option":"Dopamine is used in psychiatric disorders","bool":false}],"id":239},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of these statements regarding acetylcholine is correct?","answers":[{"option":"It is broken down by acetylcholinesterase","bool":true},{"option":"It is not released by presynaptic neurons","bool":false},{"option":"It is made by chlorine-acetyl transferase","bool":false},{"option":"It is a carbohydrate","bool":false},{"option":"It is not recycled","bool":false}],"id":240},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What is the functional unit of a cerebellar hemisphere?","answers":[{"option":"Purkinje and golgi cells","bool":false},{"option":"Pyramidal cell and deep cerebellar nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Purkinje cell and deep cerebellar nuclei","bool":true},{"option":"Pyramidal and granular cells","bool":false},{"option":"Purkinje and granular cells","bool":false}],"id":241},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which is the best statement regarding vitamin A?","answers":[{"option":"It exists in various forms","bool":true},{"option":"It is not used by the body","bool":false},{"option":"It is a water soluble vitamin","bool":false},{"option":"Its deficiency leads to beriberi","bool":false},{"option":"It is a free radical","bool":false}],"id":242},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which group do catecholamines, histamine, and serotonin belong to?","answers":[{"option":"Biogenic amines","bool":true},{"option":"Neuropeptides","bool":false},{"option":"Amino acids","bool":false},{"option":"Gasses","bool":false},{"option":"Purines","bool":false}],"id":243},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of these is the most accurate statement regarding brain development?","answers":[{"option":"The corpus callosum is not a commissure","bool":false},{"option":"The anterior commissure is the last one to appear","bool":false},{"option":"Fornix is the 3rd commissure to develop","bool":false},{"option":"Fornix is the 2nd commissure to develop","bool":true},{"option":"Commissures are axon bundles that run anteriorly/posteriorly","bool":false}],"id":244},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which nerve is derived from the 1st pharyngeal arch?","answers":[{"option":"Trigeminal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Ulnar nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false}],"id":245},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What does the cartilage of the 3rd pharyngeal arch develop into?","answers":[{"option":"Outer ear","bool":false},{"option":"Lesser horn of hyoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Patella","bool":false},{"option":"Greater horn of hyoid bone","bool":true},{"option":"Styloid process","bool":false}],"id":246},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What does the third pharyngeal pouch develop into?","answers":[{"option":"Middle ear cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Superior parathyroid gland","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior parathyroid glands","bool":true},{"option":"Tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"Auditory tube","bool":false}],"id":247},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Lesion of which hypothalamic nucleus causes abnormal circadian rhythm?","answers":[{"option":"Paraventricular","bool":false},{"option":"Supraoptic","bool":false},{"option":"Preoptic","bool":false},{"option":"Mammillary","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic","bool":true}],"id":248},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"A tumor of the pituitary gland exerting pressure on the optic chiasm would result in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Left nasal hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Contralateral homonymous hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Total blindness","bool":false},{"option":"Bitemporal hemianopia","bool":true},{"option":"Left-sided circumferential blindness","bool":false}],"id":249},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Occlusion of the posterior cerebral artery would result in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Total blindness","bool":false},{"option":"Contralateral homonymous hemianopia","bool":true},{"option":"Bitemporal hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Left-sided circumferential blindness","bool":false},{"option":"Left nasal hemianopia","bool":false}],"id":250},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is true regarding the subarachnoid space?","answers":[{"option":"It does not contain cerebral arteries or veins","bool":false},{"option":"It extends inferiorly as far as the fourth sacral vertebra","bool":false},{"option":"Cisterna magna is continuous with the spinal epidural space","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial nerves lie outside it in sheaths derived from dura mater","bool":false},{"option":"Arachnoid villi project into the venous sinuses as small outpouchings of subarachnoid space","bool":true}],"id":251},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Regarding memory, which is the appropriate statement?","answers":[{"option":"Damage to amygdala block the ability to form new long-term memories","bool":false},{"option":"Short-term memory involve structural changes","bool":false},{"option":"Long-term memory involve synaptic changes","bool":false},{"option":"Short-term memory lasts for seconds and minutes unless converted to long term memory","bool":true},{"option":"Short-term memory is more stable","bool":false}],"id":252},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What is the normal count of lymphocytes in cerebrospinal fluid?","answers":[{"option":"0-10 cells/mm3","bool":false},{"option":"50-100 cells/mm3","bool":false},{"option":"5-10 cells/mm3","bool":false},{"option":"10-20 cells/mm3","bool":false},{"option":"0-3 cells/mm3","bool":true}],"id":253},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"During a cesarean section, where is the anesthetic injected?","answers":[{"option":"Subarachnoid space","bool":true},{"option":"Subdural space","bool":false},{"option":"Pudendal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lumbar puncture for spinal anesthesia","bool":false},{"option":"Epidural space","bool":false}],"id":254},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is not included in the visual pathway?","answers":[{"option":"Optic chiasm","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerves (CN II)","bool":false},{"option":"Optic radiation","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Pretectal nucleus","bool":true}],"id":255},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is an example of fibers that connect the two cerebral hemispheres?","answers":[{"option":"The uncinate fasciculus","bool":false},{"option":"The stria terminalis","bool":false},{"option":"The hippocampal commissure","bool":true},{"option":"The cingulum","bool":false},{"option":"The geniculocalcarine tract","bool":false}],"id":256},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which statement is the most accurate regarding the internal capsule?","answers":[{"option":"Retrolentiform part contains fibres form medial geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Contralateral spastic hemiplegia can result from infarction of the lenticulostriate artery","bool":true},{"option":"The posterior limb separates the caudate nucleus from the lentiform nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Genu contains corticospinal fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Optic radiation are found in sublentiform part","bool":false}],"id":257},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What is the language deficit accompanying cerebral stroke called?","answers":[{"option":"Insomnia","bool":false},{"option":"Dysphagia","bool":false},{"option":"Aphasia","bool":true},{"option":"Agraphia","bool":false},{"option":"Anosognosia","bool":false}],"id":258},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"Which of these is correct regarding motor functions?","answers":[{"option":"Damage to Broca‚Äôs area causes inability to speak","bool":true},{"option":"Voluntary eye movement area in cerebral cortex lies in premotor area below the Broca's area","bool":false},{"option":"Coordinated muscle activity only needs coordination of cerebral cortex and spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Motor cortex is located posterior to the central sulcus of cerebrum","bool":false},{"option":"Broca‚Äôs area lies immediately posterior to the primary motor cortex above the Sylvian fissure","bool":false}],"id":259},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What happens when a lesion occurs in the non-dominant hemisphere?","answers":[{"option":"Sensory loss","bool":false},{"option":"Abnormal speech","bool":false},{"option":"Visual disturbances","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of perception of language","bool":false},{"option":"Hemineglect","bool":true}],"id":260},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What would damage to the ventral root of a spinal nerve result in?","answers":[{"option":"Degeneration of dorsal root ganglion cells at the same spinal cord level","bool":false},{"option":"Atrophy of skeletal muscle innervated by that nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Regeneration of the cut axons as their myelin sheaths are formed by Schwann cells","bool":false},{"option":"Increased activity of the muscle stretch reflexes in the innervated muscles","bool":false},{"option":"A positive Babinski sign","bool":false}],"id":261},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"The optic foramen transmits which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Oculomotor nerve and internal carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibular nerve and ophthalmic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve and basilar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve and ophthalmic artery","bool":true},{"option":"Optic nerve and middle cerebral artery","bool":false}],"id":262},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"What is the best statement regarding the role of biomolecules in various diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Norepinephrine controls normal sleep and eating patterns","bool":false},{"option":"Selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors aggravate depression","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine deficiency can present as a psychiatric disorder","bool":true},{"option":"The neurotransmitter involved in controlling mood and behavior is acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"There should be a balance between serotonin and dopamine in the basal ganglia in order to maintain control of body movements","bool":false}],"id":263},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2018"],"question":"The inferior cerebellar peduncles (to the medulla) do not compose of afferent fibers from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebellovestibular tract","bool":true},{"option":"Spinocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Olivocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Cuneocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":264},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which neurotransmitter acts on the presynaptic membrane as an inhibitor?","answers":[{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":false},{"option":"Gamma-aminobutyric acid (GABA)","bool":true},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false}],"id":265},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which dural reflection separates the cerebrum from the cerebellum?","answers":[{"option":"Tentorium cerebelli","bool":true},{"option":"Falx cerebelli","bool":false},{"option":"Falx cerebri","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragma sellae","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":266},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"What is the main chemical constituent of the insulating sheaths on myelinated neurons?","answers":[{"option":"Galactocerebroside","bool":false},{"option":"Cholestrol","bool":false},{"option":"Choline","bool":false},{"option":"Sphingomyelin","bool":true},{"option":"Phosphagen","bool":false}],"id":267},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"A 56-year-old man presents to the outpatient department with facial and limb paralysis. An examination also reveals that he has pupils reduced to the size of pinpoints. A hemorrhage is suspected. A computed tomography (CT) scan is performed. The CT image will show a hemorrhage at which of the following regions?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebrum","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":true},{"option":"Mid-brain","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false}],"id":268},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which statement is false regarding axon structure and function?","answers":[{"option":"Transmit action potential","bool":false},{"option":"Axons can arise from dendrites","bool":false},{"option":"Axons can arise from soma","bool":false},{"option":"Nissl substance is present","bool":true},{"option":"Axons can arise from hillock","bool":false}],"id":269},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"What is a motor neuron, along with the skeletal muscle fibers innervated by that particular neuron, collectively called?","answers":[{"option":"Motor unit","bool":true},{"option":"Primary motor area","bool":false},{"option":"Muscle spindle","bool":false},{"option":"Motor complex","bool":false},{"option":"Golgi tendon organ (GTO)","bool":false}],"id":270},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following amino acids is serotonin derived from?","answers":[{"option":"Arginine","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylalanine","bool":false},{"option":"Tryptophan","bool":true},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":false}],"id":271},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"What is the sensitivity to the stimuli outside the body called?","answers":[{"option":"Kinesthesia","bool":false},{"option":"Interoception","bool":false},{"option":"Exteroception","bool":true},{"option":"Nociception","bool":false},{"option":"Proprioception","bool":false}],"id":272},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"A 26-year-old man comes to the outpatient department (OPD) with a high fever and cold sores around the mouth. Lab investigations reveal lymphocytosis, red blood cells (RBCs), and normal glucose in the cerebrospinal fluid (CSF). What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Herpes encephalitis","bool":true},{"option":"Fungal encephalitis","bool":false},{"option":"West Nile fever","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial encephalitis","bool":false},{"option":"Protozoal encephalitis","bool":false}],"id":273},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Holoprosencephaly is a malformation characterized by an inability of the cerebral hemispheres to separate at the midline. Which genetic disorder is this malformation associated with?","answers":[{"option":"Trisomy 13","bool":true},{"option":"Trisomy 21","bool":false},{"option":"Trisomy 17","bool":false},{"option":"Trisomy 15","bool":false},{"option":"Trisomy 18","bool":false}],"id":274},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"What is the cerebellum embryologically derived from?","answers":[{"option":"Rhombencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Telencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Diencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Myelencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Metencephalon","bool":true}],"id":275},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which one of the following nerves passes through foramen rotundum?","answers":[{"option":"Lesser petrosal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Mandibular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":true}],"id":276},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"A lesion in which structure will cause athetosis?","answers":[{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Substantia nigra","bool":false},{"option":"Globus pallidus","bool":true},{"option":"Caudate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Putamen","bool":false}],"id":277},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which hypothalamic nuclei are responsible for decreasing heart rate and blood pressure, and increasing the contraction of the urinary bladder?","answers":[{"option":"Ventromedial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior and preoptic nuclei","bool":true},{"option":"Supraoptic and paraventricular nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral hypothalamic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior and lateral nuclei","bool":false}],"id":278},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which one of the following is not true about the cerebellar cortex?","answers":[{"option":"It has six distinct layers","bool":true},{"option":"It has a middle Purkinje layer","bool":false},{"option":"It has three distinct layers","bool":false},{"option":"It has an inner granular layer","bool":false},{"option":"It has an outer molecular layer","bool":false}],"id":279},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following amino acids is required for the synthesis of dopamine, epinephrine and norepinephrine?","answers":[{"option":"Valine","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":true},{"option":"Methionine","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":false},{"option":"Tryptophan","bool":false}],"id":280},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"What is the frequency range of alpha waves?","answers":[{"option":"14-80 cycles per second","bool":false},{"option":"Less than 3.5 cycles per second","bool":false},{"option":"4-7 cycles per second","bool":false},{"option":"8-13 cycles per second","bool":true},{"option":"35-140 cycles per second","bool":false}],"id":281},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"What is the rate of nerve regeneration after an injury?","answers":[{"option":"100 mm/day","bool":false},{"option":"200 mm/day","bool":false},{"option":"8 mm/day","bool":false},{"option":"0.1 mm/day","bool":false},{"option":"3 mm/day","bool":true}],"id":282},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which statement is incorrect about pyramidal cell morphology?","answers":[{"option":"The axon arises from the base of the cell body","bool":false},{"option":"Betz cells are present in the superficial layer","bool":true},{"option":"Dendrites from the apex are highly branched and extend to the surface","bool":false},{"option":"Short lateral dendrites extend from the base","bool":false},{"option":"The apices point towards the pial surface of the cortex","bool":false}],"id":283},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following structures is NOT present on the medial side of the cerebrum?","answers":[{"option":"Insula","bool":true},{"option":"Corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Paracentral lobule","bool":false},{"option":"Cuneus","bool":false},{"option":"Precuneus","bool":false}],"id":284},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Ischemia of the dorsal and lateral parts of the medulla will not present with which of the following symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Paralysis of tongue","bool":true},{"option":"Gait and limb ataxia","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of pain","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of temperature sensation","bool":false},{"option":"Dysarthria","bool":false}],"id":285},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is formed by efferent fibers from the red nucleus to the spinal cord?","answers":[{"option":"Corticospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Olivospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibulospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Rubrospinal tract","bool":true},{"option":"Reticulospinal tract","bool":false}],"id":286},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is inappropriate regarding Kluver-Bucy syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Lack of emotions","bool":false},{"option":"Placidity","bool":false},{"option":"Bilateral motor paralysis","bool":true},{"option":"Increased sexual drive","bool":false},{"option":"Increased hunger","bool":false}],"id":287},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"What is Parkinson's disease characterized by?","answers":[{"option":"Agitation","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperkinesia","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellar tremor","bool":false},{"option":"Both bradykinesia and hyperkinesia","bool":true},{"option":"Hypokinesia","bool":false}],"id":288},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following visual reflexes involves the cerebral cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Corneal reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Direct pupillary reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Consensual reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Accommodation reflex","bool":true},{"option":"Visual body reflex","bool":false}],"id":289},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which anatomical feature is present on the anterior surface of the pons?","answers":[{"option":"Sulcus limitans","bool":false},{"option":"Basilar groove","bool":true},{"option":"Vestibular area","bool":false},{"option":"Facial colliculus","bool":false},{"option":"Median sulcus","bool":false}],"id":290},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"A 78-year-old man presents to the outpatient department with a tremor that disappears on movement. The doctor suspects the possibility of a lesion in his brain. Where is the lesion most likely to be located?","answers":[{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":true}],"id":291},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is a reflex that develops over time?","answers":[{"option":"Abdominal reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Watering of mouth","bool":true},{"option":"Plantar reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Corneal reflex","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":292},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Where is the choroid plexus located?","answers":[{"option":"Floor of lateral ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Floor of fourth ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Floor of third ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Roof of third ventricle","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral boundary of fourth ventricle","bool":false}],"id":293},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"The medial geniculate body (MGB) receives input from which of the following sensory pathways?","answers":[{"option":"Olfactory","bool":false},{"option":"Auditory","bool":true},{"option":"Tactile","bool":false},{"option":"Optic","bool":false},{"option":"Gustatory","bool":false}],"id":294},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Lesions of the supraoptic and paraventricular nuclei would result in which of the following disorders?","answers":[{"option":"Kallman syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Korsakoff syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes insipidus","bool":true},{"option":"Kluver-Bucy syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Disturbances in circadian rhythms","bool":false}],"id":295},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"The dorsal column pathway is best tested by checking which of the following sensations?","answers":[{"option":"Vibration","bool":true},{"option":"Temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Unconscious proprioception","bool":false},{"option":"Light touch","bool":false},{"option":"Pain","bool":false}],"id":296},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"A 25-year-old-man comes to the outpatient department with complaints of an altered sense of smell after sustaining an injury to the area of the brain where the hypothalamus is located. In which associated structure is the lesion most likely to be located?","answers":[{"option":"Mamillothalamic fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Medial forebrain bundle","bool":true},{"option":"Thalamohypothalamic fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Amygdalohypothalamic fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Tegmental fibers","bool":false}],"id":297},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Suckling causes the release of oxytocin from which of the hypothalamus nuclei?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior","bool":false},{"option":"Supraoptic","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic","bool":false},{"option":"Paraventricular","bool":true}],"id":298},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"The ventral lateral nucleus of the thalamus is concerned with which of the following functions?","answers":[{"option":"Circadian rhythm","bool":false},{"option":"Alertness","bool":false},{"option":"Sensory control","bool":false},{"option":"Consciousness","bool":false},{"option":"Motor activity","bool":true}],"id":299},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following structures is responsible for the production of cerebrospinal fluid?","answers":[{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Choroid plexus","bool":true},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false}],"id":300},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"How is the level of consciousness of a patient tested?","answers":[{"option":"Glasgow coma scale","bool":true},{"option":"Higher mental function","bool":false},{"option":"Gait disturbances","bool":false},{"option":"Pupillary reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Deep tendon reflexes","bool":false}],"id":301},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Hyperorality, hypersexuality, and decreased emotions are all associated with which syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Dandy-Walker syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Kl√ºver-Bucy syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Guillain-Barr√© syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Wernicke-Korsakoff syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamic pain syndrome","bool":false}],"id":302},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"The blood-brain barrier is formed by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Tight junctions between capillary endothelial cells","bool":true},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Pericytes present around the capillaries","bool":false},{"option":"The impermeable, non-fenestrated, basement membrane of the capillaries","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudopods of the astrocytes","bool":false}],"id":303},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Pain and temperature sensations are carried by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":true},{"option":"Rubrospinal pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal column","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Spinocerebellar pathway","bool":false}],"id":304},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"What is the function of the Golgi tendon organ?","answers":[{"option":"Damage the contractile forces","bool":false},{"option":"Prevent extreme contraction","bool":false},{"option":"Equalize forces between individual muscle fibers","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibit the force","bool":false},{"option":"Nullify the contractile forces","bool":false}],"id":305},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is a neuron that forms synaptic junctions with intrafusal skeletal muscle fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Purkinje cell","bool":false},{"option":"Granule cell","bool":false},{"option":"Gamma motor neuron","bool":true},{"option":"Alpha motor neuron","bool":false},{"option":"Pyramidal cell","bool":false}],"id":306},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which statement is incorrect about Wallerian degeneration?","answers":[{"option":"It occurs in the peripheral nervous system (PNS)","bool":false},{"option":"It is retrograde","bool":true},{"option":"The axon and the myelin sheath disappear","bool":false},{"option":"It occurs in the central nervous system (CNS)","bool":false},{"option":"Schwann cells proliferate","bool":false}],"id":307},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which structure(s) acts as the second-order neuron of the dorsal column?","answers":[{"option":"Nucleus cuneatus and gracilis","bool":true},{"option":"Clarke's column","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus dorsalis","bool":false},{"option":"Superior colliculus","bool":false}],"id":308},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Increased protein in cerebrospinal fluid occurs in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Increased intracranial pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial infection","bool":true},{"option":"Repeated lumbar puncture","bool":false},{"option":"Acute water intoxication","bool":false}],"id":309},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which structure acts as the second-order neuron for the spinothalamic tract?","answers":[{"option":"Nucleus gracilis","bool":false},{"option":"Substantia gelatinosa","bool":true},{"option":"Nucleus cuneatus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior colliculus","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus dorsalis","bool":false}],"id":310},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following clinical features will be seen in a lesion of the cerebellar hemisphere?","answers":[{"option":"Negative Romberg sign","bool":true},{"option":"Tremors in the right hand","bool":false},{"option":"Swaying left to right with eyes closed","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased muscle tone in the right upper and lower limbs","bool":false},{"option":"Person falls to the right","bool":false}],"id":311},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"What is the function of acetylcholinesterase?","answers":[{"option":"To esterify acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"To synthesize acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"To add acetyl group to choline","bool":false},{"option":"To add ester group to choline","bool":false},{"option":"To hydrolyze acetylcholine","bool":true}],"id":312},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Glucose enters the brain through which of the following transporters?","answers":[{"option":"GLUT-4","bool":false},{"option":"GLUT-2","bool":false},{"option":"GLUT-13","bool":false},{"option":"GLUT-1","bool":true},{"option":"SGLT-1","bool":false}],"id":313},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is correct regarding a watershed infarct?","answers":[{"option":"It is seen after hypotensive episodes","bool":false},{"option":"It may occur at the borderzone between anterior and middle cerebral arteries","bool":true},{"option":"It occurs when there is liquefactive necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"A paradoxical occurrence in which ischemic area becomes infused with cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) and life-threatening cerebral edema ensues","bool":false},{"option":"It occurs due to hyperviscosity of blood","bool":false}],"id":314},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following symptoms will be the result of a lesion of the intermediate zone of the cerebellum?","answers":[{"option":"Vertigo","bool":false},{"option":"Nystagmus","bool":false},{"option":"Dysarthia","bool":false},{"option":"Resting tremor","bool":false},{"option":"Dysdiadochokinesia","bool":true}],"id":315},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"What is the pathophysiology behind schizophrenia?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Increased glutamate","bool":false},{"option":"Increased dopamine","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased serotonin","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":316},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"The cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) leaves the lateral ventricles to flow into the third ventricle through which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Cisterna Magna","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen of Magendie","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen of Luschka","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen of Monro","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebral aqueduct","bool":false}],"id":317},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is incorrect about alpha fibers?","answers":[{"option":"They are inhibited by Renshaw cells","bool":false},{"option":"They attach to intrafusal fibers","bool":true},{"option":"They are greater than gamma fibers","bool":false},{"option":"They are efferent fibers of the lower motors neuron","bool":false},{"option":"They attach to extrafusal fibers","bool":false}],"id":318},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"In a T2WI section magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), the intervertebral disc appears as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Grey","bool":false},{"option":"Black","bool":false},{"option":"Jet black","bool":false},{"option":"Dark","bool":false},{"option":"Bright","bool":true}],"id":319},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following terms correctly describes the degeneration of the distal cut end of the neuron?","answers":[{"option":"Synaptic stripping","bool":false},{"option":"Chromatolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Retrograde degeneration","bool":false},{"option":"Wallerian degeneration","bool":true}],"id":320},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"An autopsy of the brain of a 40-year-old man reveals transtentorial herniation. Further examination reveals flame-shaped lesions in the midbrain and pons. Which term best describes this?","answers":[{"option":"Saccular aneurysm","bool":false},{"option":"Duret hemorrhages","bool":true},{"option":"Intraparenchymal hemorrhages","bool":false},{"option":"Slit hemorrhages","bool":false},{"option":"Lacunar infarcts","bool":false}],"id":321},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is incorrect about the central nervous system gray matter?","answers":[{"option":"It is only present in the cerebral region","bool":true},{"option":"It is present in all segments","bool":false},{"option":"Gray matter is unmyelinated","bool":false},{"option":"It surrounds the central canal","bool":false},{"option":"It is H-shaped","bool":false}],"id":322},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Agenesis of the corpus callosum is characterized by which of the following observations?","answers":[{"option":"Commissural fibres are not connected","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased gray matter bundles","bool":false},{"option":"Increased white matter bundles","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral hemispheres are not connected","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased white matter bundles","bool":false}],"id":323},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is correct about the cerebellar cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Mossy fibers travel through the inferior cerebellar peduncle","bool":true},{"option":"Golgi type I cells are found in the granular layer","bool":false},{"option":"Climbing fibers terminate in glomeruli of granular layer and synapse with both granule cells and Golgi type II cells","bool":false},{"option":"Climbing fibers originate from the superior olivary nucleus of the pons","bool":false},{"option":"Dendrites of Golgi type II extend throughout the cerebellar cortex","bool":false}],"id":324},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following statements regarding the blood-brain barrier is true?","answers":[{"option":"It is well-developed in infants and children and becomes less efficient with age","bool":false},{"option":"It allows restricted passage of water and gases","bool":false},{"option":"The structure of the blood-brain barrier is identical in all areas of the nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"It is absent in aggressive tumors of the brain","bool":true},{"option":"Drugs that are highly protein-bound can easily cross the blood-brain barrier","bool":false}],"id":325},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Neurons after injury become red because of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Eosinophilia","bool":true},{"option":"Infiltration","bool":false},{"option":"Hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Amyloid deposition","bool":false},{"option":"Shrinkage of nucleus","bool":false}],"id":326},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Sensory feedback helps the motor cortex to control which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Precise muscle movements","bool":true},{"option":"Eye movement","bool":false},{"option":"Hormones secretion from the hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Oscillation of vestibular system","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":327},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"A lesion in which of the following is responsible for the symptoms of a man with resting tremors which disappear when working?","answers":[{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrum","bool":false}],"id":328},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"The limbic cortex is a part of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Rhombencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Diencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Prosencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Telencephalon","bool":true},{"option":"Mesencephalon","bool":false}],"id":329},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Where is the respiratory center located?","answers":[{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebrum","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false}],"id":330},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following structures is related to the auditory system in pons?","answers":[{"option":"Medial geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Trapezoid body","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior colliculus","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Spiral ganglion","bool":false}],"id":331},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following statements is correct regarding the Schwann cells?","answers":[{"option":"One Schwann cell covers 30 nerve fibers","bool":false},{"option":"They are produced in the central nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple sclerosis is a demyelinating disorder that affects the Schwann cells","bool":false},{"option":"Schwann cells cover all cranial nerves","bool":false},{"option":"They are produced in the peripheral nervous system","bool":true}],"id":332},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is a sign of lower motor neuron (LMN) lesions?","answers":[{"option":"Spasticity","bool":false},{"option":"Clasp-knife response","bool":false},{"option":"Flaccid paralysis","bool":true},{"option":"Hyperactive stretch reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Disuse atrophy","bool":false}],"id":333},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Inhibitory postsynaptic potential is caused by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Chloride influx","bool":true},{"option":"Bicarbonate influx","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium influx","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium influx","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium influx","bool":false}],"id":334},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"The cerebrospinal fluid leaves the fourth ventricle through which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Arachnoid villi","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen of Monro","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral aqueduct","bool":false},{"option":"Central canal","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen of Magendie","bool":true}],"id":335},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Lacunar infarcts are caused by hypertension in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Large sized artery","bool":false},{"option":"Medium sized artery","bool":false},{"option":"Communicating artery","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Penetrating artery","bool":true}],"id":336},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"An old man was having difficulty in walking and maintaining his posture. A lesion in which of the following structures will cause these symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior lobe of cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior lobe of cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Flocculonodular lobe","bool":true},{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":false}],"id":337},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"An obese woman suffers from a mid-hypothalamic lesion. Which of the following nuclei is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Supraoptic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior hypothalamic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Ventromedial hypothalamic nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Preoptic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus","bool":false}],"id":338},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"What is meant by paresthesia?","answers":[{"option":"Loss of sensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of pain sensation","bool":false},{"option":"Pins and needles sensation","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased sensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Increased sensitivity","bool":false}],"id":339},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"What is the function of muscle spindles?","answers":[{"option":"Detect dynamic and static changes in muscle length","bool":true},{"option":"Detect muscle tension","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Detect muscle strength","bool":false},{"option":"Detect muscle shape","bool":false}],"id":340},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"In adults, 40-60% energy is provided by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Lipids","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamins","bool":false},{"option":"Minerals","bool":false},{"option":"Carbohydrates","bool":true},{"option":"Nucleic acids","bool":false}],"id":341},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"A 6-month-old child suffering from encephalocele has a 6 x 6 cm protrusion on his head. Which of the following would be present in the protrusion?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Meninges","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Blood","bool":false},{"option":"Brain and meninges","bool":true}],"id":342},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Where are beta waves commonly observed?","answers":[{"option":"Temporal lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal and occipital lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal and frontal lobe","bool":true},{"option":"Occipital lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal lobe","bool":false}],"id":343},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following sends signals to the primary motor area?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Premotor area","bool":true},{"option":"Olfactory bulb","bool":false},{"option":"Visual cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Cingulate cortex","bool":false}],"id":344},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is the main input unit of basal ganglia?","answers":[{"option":"Globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Caudate and putamen","bool":true},{"option":"Subthalamic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Substantia nigra","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":345},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Where is the neuropil of the spinal cord most abundant?","answers":[{"option":"Perikarya","bool":false},{"option":"Synapsis","bool":false},{"option":"Gray matter","bool":true},{"option":"Neuroglia","bool":false},{"option":"Unmyelinated axons","bool":false}],"id":346},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"What does the white matter of the spinal cord consist of?","answers":[{"option":"Perikarya","bool":false},{"option":"Myelinated axon","bool":true},{"option":"Dendrites","bool":false},{"option":"Neuroglia","bool":false},{"option":"Blood vessels","bool":false}],"id":347},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following statements refers to red neurons?","answers":[{"option":"Abnormal vacuolization of neuron","bool":false},{"option":"Structural loss along with functional loss of the neuron","bool":false},{"option":"Reactive astrogliosis","bool":false},{"option":"Neurons having bright pink cytoplasm with large nucleus and numerous stout ramifying processes","bool":false},{"option":"Shrinkage of cell body, loss of nissl substance or pyknosis of nucleus","bool":true}],"id":348},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A 15-year-old boy presents with a fall and fracture of the temporal bone of the skull. On computed tomography (CT) scan, he is found to have an epidural hematoma. What is the most common cause of the hematoma?","answers":[{"option":"Ehlers-Danlos syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Rupture of bridging veins","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Rupture of middle meningeal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Autosomal polycystic kidney disease","bool":false}],"id":349},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A 29-year-old man steps on a broken bottle with the base of his right foot. His right leg immediately flexes and his left leg extends. What is this reflex called?","answers":[{"option":"Walking reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Stretch reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Patellar reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Golgi tendon reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Crossed extensor reflex","bool":true}],"id":350},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A 50-year-old patient with a history of hypertension is brought to the outpatient department. Examination reveals weakness and loss of sensation mainly affecting right leg, right foot, and perineum. Which one of the following arteries is occluded?","answers":[{"option":"Left middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Right middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Right anterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left anterior cerebral artery","bool":true}],"id":351},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A 79-year-old woman was driving when she had a sudden severe headache. She drove to a service station, stopped the car and slumped over the wheel. She was taken to emergency, where she remained comatose and died 6 hours later. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebral hematoma","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral ischemia","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral edema","bool":false},{"option":"Thromboembolism along with cerebral infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Rupture of berry aneurysm","bool":true}],"id":352},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following is the major part of the limbic system?","answers":[{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Opioid receptor","bool":false},{"option":"Pineal body","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":true}],"id":353},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A child presented to the emergency department with a complaint of a dog bite in the right arm. He was conscious but bleeding from the wound site. The child has completed the EPI vaccination and no significant past medical or surgical history. After documenting the detail of the dog bite, what is the vaccination plan for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Anti-rabies vaccine and appropriate antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-rabies vaccine and usage of immunoglobulin","bool":true},{"option":"Anti-rabies vaccine of both the dog and the child","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-rabies vaccine and cleaning the wound","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-rabies vaccine infiltration into the wound","bool":false}],"id":354},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following best defines memory?","answers":[{"option":"Skills of learning","bool":false},{"option":"Ability to store, retain, and recall information","bool":true},{"option":"Genetic control of brain","bool":false},{"option":"Ability to rest ourselves","bool":false},{"option":"Forgetting a movie","bool":false}],"id":355},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which structure is present superior to the pons and inferior to the thalamus?","answers":[{"option":"Midbrain","bool":true},{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral ventricle","bool":false}],"id":356},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which is the most safest site for collecting cerebrospinal fluid?","answers":[{"option":"Thoraco lumbar region","bool":false},{"option":"Thoracic vertebrae","bool":false},{"option":"Sacro iliac region","bool":false},{"option":"Illiac region","bool":false},{"option":"Lumbar region","bool":true}],"id":357},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is the most inappropriate statement about malformation and developmental diseases of CNS?","answers":[{"option":"May occur due to deficiency of vitamin D","bool":true},{"option":"Many toxic compounds have teratogenic effects","bool":false},{"option":"Mutation of genes that control body patterning","bool":false},{"option":"Aberration of signaling molecules that control body patterning","bool":false},{"option":"Many infectious agents have teratogenic effects","bool":false}],"id":358},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Myasthenia gravis is primarily a pathology of which structure?","answers":[{"option":"Motor neuron","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Peripheral nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Neuromuscular junction","bool":true}],"id":359},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"The dura mater does not receive innervation from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"C3","bool":false},{"option":"C1","bool":false},{"option":"C2","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal","bool":false},{"option":"C4","bool":true}],"id":360},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Use of which of the following prevents the occurrence of neural tube defects?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin D","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin C","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin A","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin K","bool":false},{"option":"Folic acid","bool":true}],"id":361},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is NOT shown by the neuroglial cells?","answers":[{"option":"Capable to divide through life","bool":false},{"option":"Can be best studied with routine staining techniques","bool":true},{"option":"They are non-neuronal cells of CNS","bool":false},{"option":"Arise mostly from neuroectoderm","bool":false},{"option":"They are five to ten times more abundant than neurons","bool":false}],"id":362},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Degeneration of nigrostriatal dopaminergic neurons occurs in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Epilepsy","bool":false},{"option":"Migraine","bool":false},{"option":"Huntington's chorea","bool":false},{"option":"Alzheimer's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Paralysis agitans","bool":true}],"id":363},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A 25-year-old female had a head injury. She is diagnosed with a case of Kluver Bucy syndrome. Which one of the following signs is not present?","answers":[{"option":"Paralysis of one side of body","bool":true},{"option":"Increased sexuality","bool":false},{"option":"Compulsive tendency to place things in mouth","bool":false},{"option":"Changes in eating behavior","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease emotionality","bool":false}],"id":364},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Obstruction of the flow of cerebrospinal fluid leads to which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Parkinsonism","bool":false},{"option":"Tumor formation","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocephalus","bool":true}],"id":365},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"At what rate does peripheral nerve fiber regenerate?","answers":[{"option":"3 mm/day","bool":true},{"option":"200 mm/day","bool":false},{"option":"0.1 mm/day","bool":false},{"option":"400 mm/day","bool":false},{"option":"100 mm/day","bool":false}],"id":366},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"What hormone is synthesized by the pineal gland?","answers":[{"option":"Melatonin","bool":true},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenaline","bool":false},{"option":"Endorphin","bool":false}],"id":367},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following features is not present in the Purkinje cells?","answers":[{"option":"Arranged as single row between molecular and granular layer","bool":false},{"option":"Having branching dendrites that ascent at molecular layer","bool":false},{"option":"Largest output neuron of cerebellar cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Can be best studied by routine staining techniques","bool":true},{"option":"Collateral axon that enters the white mater","bool":false}],"id":368},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is wrong regarding the hypothalamus?","answers":[{"option":"Weights around 4gms","bool":false},{"option":"Preoptic area lies infront of hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamic sulcus separates hypothalamus from thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Extends from optic chiasm to mamillary bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior to hypothalamus lies third ventricle","bool":true}],"id":369},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following histological characteristics is not part of the cerebral cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Contains six layers in all areas of cortex","bool":true},{"option":"Neocortex shows alternate dark and light bands on histological appearance","bool":false},{"option":"Paleocortex is heterogenous","bool":false},{"option":"Isocortex is homogenetically typical","bool":false},{"option":"Archicortex has hetrogenous, three layers","bool":false}],"id":370},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Reticular formation nuclei concerned with autonomic regulation of respiration pressure are present in?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral group","bool":true},{"option":"Paramedian group","bool":false},{"option":"Medial group","bool":false},{"option":"Raphe group","bool":false},{"option":"Intermediate group","bool":false}],"id":371},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A 54-year-old man got a head injury during a road traffic accident. He was treated by a neurosurgeon in a tertiary care hospital. On examination, his reflexes are slow, there is a loss of power in the muscles and when he starts movement he feels difficulty turning off his movements. The presenting symptoms present when which one of the following parts of CNS is damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Reticular formation","bool":false},{"option":"Primary motor area of cerebral cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":true},{"option":"Pyramid of Medulla oblongata","bool":false}],"id":372},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Under the morphological classification of the neurons, the bipolar neurons are the ones that bear a single axon and a single dendrite that emerges from the opposite poles of the spindle-shaped body. Which one of the following is an example of a bipolar neuron?","answers":[{"option":"Purkinje cells of the cerebral cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal root ganglion of the spinal nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Neurons in the cochlear and vestibular ganglia","bool":true},{"option":"Sensory ganglia of cranial nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Mesencephalic nucleus of trigeminal nerve","bool":false}],"id":373},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Serotonergic innervations of suprachiasmatic nuclei of the hypothalamus involve which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Hallucinations","bool":false},{"option":"Deep sleep","bool":false},{"option":"Euphoria","bool":false},{"option":"Circadian rhythm","bool":true},{"option":"Insomnia","bool":false}],"id":374},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"The lower border of septum pellucidum rests upon the upper border of which structure?","answers":[{"option":"Lentiform nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Putamen","bool":false},{"option":"Caudate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Fornix","bool":true},{"option":"Internal capsule","bool":false}],"id":375},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following neurotransmitters decreases the pain perception in the brain?","answers":[{"option":"Cellulose","bool":false},{"option":"Substance P","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":true},{"option":"Insulin","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false}],"id":376},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"What is the significance of gate control system in pain transmission?","answers":[{"option":"Basis for relief of pain through rubbing","bool":true},{"option":"For release of dopamine from hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"For better pain conduction","bool":false},{"option":"To activate thalamic nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"To increase pain sensation","bool":false}],"id":377},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Contralateral hemiparesis in a patient was attributed to a disorder in the internal capsule. What part of the internal capsule is concerned with related tract?","answers":[{"option":"Genu","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior limb","bool":true},{"option":"Sublentiform part","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior limb","bool":false},{"option":"Retrolenticular part","bool":false}],"id":378},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which fibers interconnect the two cerebral hemispheres?","answers":[{"option":"Arcuate fasiciculus","bool":false},{"option":"Stria terminalis","bool":false},{"option":"Fornix","bool":true},{"option":"The cingulum","bool":false},{"option":"Geniculo-calcarine tract","bool":false}],"id":379},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is a voluntary reflex?","answers":[{"option":"Flexion of the arm following a painful stimulus","bool":false},{"option":"Defecation","bool":true},{"option":"Acceleration of the heart","bool":false},{"option":"Salivatory secretion","bool":false},{"option":"Micturition","bool":false}],"id":380},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following, upon release from the nerve terminal, causes the opening of anionic channels in the postsynaptic neuron?","answers":[{"option":"Glutamate","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Nitric oxide","bool":false},{"option":"GABA","bool":true}],"id":381},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which structure in the CNS acts like valves to pour the cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) into the blood?","answers":[{"option":"Choroid plexus","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphatic vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Arachnoid villi","bool":true},{"option":"Tela choroidea","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral arteries","bool":false}],"id":382},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following is not a feature of a vein of a brain?","answers":[{"option":"Pierce endosteal layer of dura mater","bool":true},{"option":"No valves","bool":false},{"option":"Pierce arachnoid mater","bool":false},{"option":"No muscular tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Lie in subarachnoid space","bool":false}],"id":383},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A young patient after a motorcycle accident was brought into emergency. After investigations, a diagnosis of fracture of the middle cranial fossa was made. The fractured fossa is not formed by which one of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Petrous part of temporal","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous part of temporal","bool":false},{"option":"Basilar part of occipital","bool":true},{"option":"Greater wing of sphenoid","bool":false},{"option":"Body of sphenoid","bool":false}],"id":384},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following elicits inhibitory post synaptic potential?","answers":[{"option":"Calcium influx","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium influx","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium influx","bool":false},{"option":"Chloride influx","bool":true},{"option":"Bicarbonate influx","bool":false}],"id":385},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"The majority of afferent fibers in basal ganglia come from which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Motor cortex","bool":true},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Associate cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Brain stem","bool":false}],"id":386},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"What is the most common type of stroke encountered?","answers":[{"option":"Ischemic attack","bool":true},{"option":"Subdural hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Intracerebral hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic type","bool":false},{"option":"Hemorrhagic attack","bool":false}],"id":387},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A picture of the cerebrospinal fluid in acute pyogenic meningitis shows which of the following characteristics?","answers":[{"option":"Neutrophils not more than 10,000/cubic mm","bool":false},{"option":"Increased glucose concentration","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Clear fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Increased protein concentration","bool":true}],"id":388},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which structure is not innervated by the nerve emerging from the groove between pons and medulla?","answers":[{"option":"Buccinator muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Orbicularis oculi","bool":false},{"option":"Sublingual gland","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal gland","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid gland","bool":true}],"id":389},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Thermal nociceptors are activated by skin temperature above what value?","answers":[{"option":"20 celsius","bool":false},{"option":"11 celsius","bool":false},{"option":"13 celsius","bool":false},{"option":"45 celsius","bool":true},{"option":"29 celsius","bool":false}],"id":390},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following tract is concerned with voluntary discrete and skilled movements, especially of distal parts of limbs?","answers":[{"option":"Tectospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Reticulospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Ruberospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Corticospinal tract","bool":true},{"option":"Vestibulospinal tract","bool":false}],"id":391},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Weber syndrome is caused by the occlusion of a branch of which artery?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior inferior cerebellar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior inferior cerebellar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior cerebellar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Basilar artery","bool":false}],"id":392},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which cranial nerve motor nuclei are present in the pons?","answers":[{"option":"I and II","bool":false},{"option":"IX, X, and XII","bool":false},{"option":"VIII","bool":false},{"option":"III and IV","bool":false},{"option":"V, VI, and VII","bool":true}],"id":393},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is not a feature of meperidine?","answers":[{"option":"It produces mydriasis","bool":false},{"option":"It is a synthetic compound","bool":false},{"option":"It produces miosis","bool":true},{"option":"It has no antitussive effect","bool":false},{"option":"It can cause convulsions in large doses","bool":false}],"id":394},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following chemical neurotransmitters are present in neurons that have cell bodies in the brainstem projecting to the hypothalamus, limbic system, neocortex, cerebellum, and spinal cord?","answers":[{"option":"Serotonin","bool":true},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Dopa","bool":false}],"id":395},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following cranial nerves emerges from the dorsal aspect of the midbrain?","answers":[{"option":"Facial","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear","bool":true},{"option":"Occulomotor","bool":false},{"option":"Abducent","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal","bool":false}],"id":396},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"What is the approximate pH of anaerobically collected cerebrospinal fluid?","answers":[{"option":"7.10","bool":false},{"option":"7.31","bool":true},{"option":"7.15","bool":false},{"option":"7.01","bool":false},{"option":"7.20","bool":false}],"id":397},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Surgery was planned for a 14-year-old student for his atrial septal defect. On the day of his surgery, he was very anxious. The doctor examined his eyes with an ophthalmoscope and subsequently gave him anxiolytics for his nervousness. Contraction of which of the following eye muscles is the result of the sympathetic effect of anxiety?","answers":[{"option":"Longitudinal muscles causing miosis","bool":false},{"option":"Constrictor pupillae causing miosis","bool":false},{"option":"Dilator pupillae causing miosis","bool":false},{"option":"Dilator pupillae causing mydriasis","bool":true},{"option":"Constrictor pupillae causing mydriasis","bool":false}],"id":398},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"On ultrasonography, the amniotic fluid around the embryo seems to be in excess. The cavity containing this fluid is lined by cells derived from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Hypoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Cytotrophoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Epiblast","bool":true},{"option":"Syncytiotrophoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Extraembryonic mesoderm","bool":false}],"id":399},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Mr. Arshad, a 45-year-old diabetic man, is referred to the surgical unit for the dressing of a wound on the sole of his left foot. He says that when he took his shoes off at night there was a small stone inside the shoe which had wounded the foot, making it bleed. However, surprisingly, he did not feel pain at all. Conscious perception of this sensation is most likely carried by which one of the following tracts?","answers":[{"option":"Spinocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal column medial lemniscus system","bool":false},{"option":"Corticospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":true}],"id":400},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"What is the central metabolite of norepinephrine?","answers":[{"option":"Vanillylmandelic acid (VMA)","bool":true},{"option":"Gamma-aminobutyric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Homovallinic acid (HVA)","bool":false},{"option":"5-Hydroxyindoleacetic acid (5-HIAA)","bool":false},{"option":"3-Methoxy-4-hydroxyphenylglycol (MHPG)","bool":false}],"id":401},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A 65-year-old man came to the outpatient department. Physical examination revealed that his eyeball deviated laterally because of paralysis of the medial rectus muscle, with the pupil dilated and loss of accommodation. Which structure of the brain is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Mid brain","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false}],"id":402},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Damage to the basal ganglia occurs in Parkinson's disease. Which of the following tremors is present in the disease?","answers":[{"option":"Resting tremors","bool":true},{"option":"Flapping tremors","bool":false},{"option":"Intention tremors","bool":false},{"option":"Fine tremors","bool":false},{"option":"Voluntary tremors","bool":false}],"id":403},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following is the structural precursor molecule of sphingolipids?","answers":[{"option":"Ceramide","bool":true},{"option":"Palmityl CoA","bool":false},{"option":"Cellulose","bool":false},{"option":"Inulin","bool":false},{"option":"Glycerol","bool":false}],"id":404},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A 70-year-old man has a 2-day history of a generalized, progressively worsening headache and increasing obtundation. He now complains of stiffness in his neck. On physical examination, vital signs include a temperature of 37¬∞C, a pulse of 85/minute, respiration 23/minute, and blood pressure 130/85 mm Hg. A CBC reveals a WBC count of 16,850/microliter. A lumbar puncture yields cloudy cerebrospinal fluid with raised glucose, decreased protein, cell count of 3800 WBCs (95% polymorphonuclear leukocytes (PMNs) and 5% mononuclear), and 122 RBCs. He receives antibiotic therapy and improves. Which of the following is the most likely long-term complication from this man's current disease?","answers":[{"option":"Hydrocephalus","bool":true},{"option":"Encephalitis","bool":false},{"option":"Subdural hematoma","bool":false},{"option":"Tonsillar herniation","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellar herniation","bool":false}],"id":405},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"An 8-month-old baby is brought to the pediatric emergency with a history of high-grade fever, fits, and refusal to take feed. On examination, he has a 102 ¬∞F temperature with altered consciousness. On cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) examination, cells are 1200/ml and mostly polymorphonuclear neutrophils. Which type of meningitis is it most likely to be?","answers":[{"option":"Viral meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial meningitis","bool":true},{"option":"Aspetic meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Subacute meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculous meningitis","bool":false}],"id":406},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"The binding of acetylcholine to its nicotinic receptor increases the permeability of the cell membrane to which one of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Ca++","bool":false},{"option":"K+","bool":false},{"option":"Cl‚àí","bool":false},{"option":"Na+","bool":true},{"option":"Se+","bool":false}],"id":407},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A 38-year-old patient comes to the outpatient department with the complaint of shaking hands while buttoning clothes, writing, or shaving. The doctor asked him to stand still with his eyes closed and noted a negative Romberg test. Vibration senses are normal in all of the four limbs on examination. Based on the clinical picture, which area is most likely to be damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebral peduncles","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":true},{"option":"Dorsal column","bool":false},{"option":"Ventral horns of spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior limb of internal capsule","bool":false}],"id":408},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Gracilis and cuneatus tubercles are seen on the surface of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":true},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Mid brain","bool":false}],"id":409},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Stimulation of the lateral hypothalamus causes an animal to develop which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Fear","bool":false},{"option":"Tranquility","bool":false},{"option":"Rage","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased eating","bool":false},{"option":"Calmness","bool":false}],"id":410},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"The nuclear bag fibers of muscle spindles are innervated by which of the following sensory afferent fibers?","answers":[{"option":"AŒ≥ fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Aùõø fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Ia fibers","bool":true},{"option":"Ib fibers","bool":false},{"option":"AŒ≤ fibers","bool":false}],"id":411},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"The most severe form of cranial neural tube defects (NTD) is characterized by: 1) major portions of the cranium and intracranial structures being absent, 2) orbits and face being present (bulging eyes) 3) polyhydramnios 4) macroglossia 5) very short neck. What type of neural tube defect is this likely to be?","answers":[{"option":"Meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Anencephaly","bool":true},{"option":"Encephalocele","bool":false},{"option":"Acrania","bool":false},{"option":"Iniencephaly","bool":false}],"id":412},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Hypothalamus releases which of the following substances to induce wakefulness?","answers":[{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenaline","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Orexin","bool":true},{"option":"Muramyl peptide","bool":false}],"id":413},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A patient comes with a lenticulostriate artery block due to chronic hypertension. Which of the following structures is supplied by it?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior limb of internal capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Whole internal capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior limb of internal capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior limb of internal capsule","bool":true},{"option":"Both anterior and inferior limb of internal capsule","bool":false}],"id":414},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A child is having a tickling sensation. Which tract would be involved?","answers":[{"option":"Dorsal spinothalamic","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic","bool":true},{"option":"Pontomedullary","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinocerebellar","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic","bool":false}],"id":415},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following are the most sensitive cells of the central nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Renshaw cells","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Microglial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Neurons","bool":true},{"option":"Schwann cells","bool":false}],"id":416},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A patient comes to the neurology department with a complaint of dryness of the mouth and irritation in the eyes. It is diagnosed that there is a lesion in the lacrimal and salivary glands. Which of the nerves is most likely to get affected?","answers":[{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false}],"id":417},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"During lumbar puncture, where is the cerebrospinal fluid withdrawn from?","answers":[{"option":"Ventricles","bool":false},{"option":"Subarachnoid and subdural space","bool":false},{"option":"Central canal","bool":false},{"option":"Subdural space","bool":false},{"option":"Subarachnoid space","bool":true}],"id":418},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"What is the total volume of cerebrospinal fluid present in the central nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"15 ml","bool":false},{"option":"150 ml","bool":true},{"option":"50 ml","bool":false},{"option":"100 ml","bool":false},{"option":"250 ml","bool":false}],"id":419},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Electrical recordings from the surface of the head demonstrate that there is continuous electrical activity in the brain which can be recorded in the form of multiple waves. One of these waves is an alpha wave. Which area of the brain does it originate from?","answers":[{"option":"Epithalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamocortical system","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebral cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellocortical system","bool":false},{"option":"Pontocerebellar connection system","bool":false}],"id":420},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A patient comes to the neurology department with a complaint of loss of fine touch in his right upper limb. He is also unable to feel the vibration of his phone. The patient also states that he had a roadside accident a few days back. Which tract is affected?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior spinocerebellar","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior spinocerebellar","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal column‚Äìmedial lemniscus pathway","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false}],"id":421},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following does the vestibulocochlear nerve pass through?","answers":[{"option":"Internal auditory meatus","bool":true},{"option":"Foramen ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen spinosum","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen rotundum","bool":false},{"option":"Jugular foramen","bool":false}],"id":422},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Absence of alpha waves indicates damage to which tract?","answers":[{"option":"Pontomedullary fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamocortical fibers","bool":true},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Corticospinal fibers","bool":false}],"id":423},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A student is studying intracerebellar lesions and wants to find out what nucleus is involved if there is a lesion in the vermis. Which nucleus is involved in this lesion?","answers":[{"option":"Dentate","bool":false},{"option":"Fastigial","bool":true},{"option":"Emboliform","bool":false},{"option":"Clarke","bool":false},{"option":"Globose","bool":false}],"id":424},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"What is the inability to perform alternating movements known as?","answers":[{"option":"Dysdiadochokinesia","bool":true},{"option":"Athetosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hyporeflexia","bool":false},{"option":"Chorea","bool":false},{"option":"Hemiballismus","bool":false}],"id":425},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Human chorionic gonadotropin (HCG) in a woman's blood indicates pregnancy. It is secreted by which one of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Syncytiotrophoblast","bool":true},{"option":"Placenta","bool":false},{"option":"Epiblast","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Cytotrophoblast","bool":false}],"id":426},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which nuclei of the hypothalamus are connected to the posterior pituitary gland?","answers":[{"option":"Arcuate and preoptic","bool":false},{"option":"Supraoptic and paraventricular","bool":true},{"option":"ventromedial and paraventricular","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral hypothalamic and ventromedial","bool":false},{"option":"Supraoptic and preoptic","bool":false}],"id":427},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"What does the ventromedial nucleus of the hypothalamus control?","answers":[{"option":"Hunger","bool":false},{"option":"Circadian rhythm","bool":false},{"option":"Water balance","bool":false},{"option":"Temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Satiety","bool":true}],"id":428},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Where does the trochlear nerve emerge from?","answers":[{"option":"Superior surface of midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior surface of midbrain","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior surface of midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior surface of midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral surface of midbrain","bool":false}],"id":429},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following is an inhibitory cell in the spinal cord?","answers":[{"option":"Renshaw cells","bool":true},{"option":"Granule cells","bool":false},{"option":"Amacrine cells","bool":false},{"option":"Purkinje cells","bool":false},{"option":"Muller cells","bool":false}],"id":430},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A 50-year-old patient presents with tuberculous meningitis for the past 10 years. Which of the following is most likely to be his viral history?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatitis C","bool":false},{"option":"Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)","bool":true},{"option":"Herpes simplex virus (HSV)","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatitis A","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatitis B","bool":false}],"id":431},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following receptors detects pressure?","answers":[{"option":"Meissner's corpuscle","bool":false},{"option":"Pacinian corpsule","bool":true},{"option":"Merkel's disc","bool":false},{"option":"Free nerve ending","bool":false},{"option":"Krause end bulb","bool":false}],"id":432},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Nitric oxide (NO) is one of the neurotransmitters that cause vasodilation. Which of the following is correct regarding nitric oxide?","answers":[{"option":"Catecholamine derivative","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate derivative","bool":false},{"option":"Gaseous neurotransmitter","bool":true},{"option":"Glycine derivative","bool":false},{"option":"Peptide derivative","bool":false}],"id":433},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A patient presents to the clinic. He is diagnosed with chronic meningitis and has acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS) for the past 14 years. Which organism is the most likely cause for this?","answers":[{"option":"Toxoplasma gondii","bool":false},{"option":"Candida albicans","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium marinum","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium scrofulaceum","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium avium intracellulare","bool":true}],"id":434},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Somatosensory information relays in which nucleus of thalamus?","answers":[{"option":"Mediodorsal nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Ventroposteriolateral nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Ventro lateral nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior nuclear","bool":false},{"option":"Ventro anterior nucleus","bool":false}],"id":435},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A research student is given a task to find out the results of electrical stimulation of different parts of the hypothalamus of a rat. On stimulation of the anterior hypothalamic area and preoptic area, what response is likely to be seen?","answers":[{"option":"Sympathetic response","bool":false},{"option":"Cessation of peristalsis","bool":false},{"option":"Pupillary dilation","bool":false},{"option":"Parasympathetic response","bool":true},{"option":"Elevation of blood pressure","bool":false}],"id":436},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following is involved in the anticipation of postural equilibrium?","answers":[{"option":"Primary sensory area","bool":false},{"option":"Spinocerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Premotor area","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibulocerebellum","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebrocerebellum","bool":false}],"id":437},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is incorrect about the cells of the cerebellar cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Purkinje cells in middle purkinje layer","bool":false},{"option":"Granules cells in inner granular layer","bool":false},{"option":"Basket cell in outer molecular layer","bool":false},{"option":"Stellate cells in granular layer","bool":true},{"option":"Golgi cells in inner granular layer","bool":false}],"id":438},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"About the myelin sheath of the peripheral nerve, which of the following is correct?","answers":[{"option":"In the central nervous system, myelinating cells myelinate several internodes of different axons","bool":false},{"option":"It is produced by Schwann cells","bool":true},{"option":"It is produced by oligodendrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"It is produced by microglia","bool":false},{"option":"In the peripheral nervous system, myelinating cell myelinate only one internode","bool":false}],"id":439},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Regarding myelination in peripheral nervous system, what is the correct statement?","answers":[{"option":"Myelinating fibers have slow conduction velocity","bool":false},{"option":"It is also produced by fibroblasts as well","bool":false},{"option":"It is produced by Schwann cells","bool":true},{"option":"A Schwann cell can myelinate upto 30 axons","bool":false},{"option":"Oligodendrocytes are myelinating cells of peripheral nervous system","bool":false}],"id":440},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following will not result with stimulation of periventricular and lateral nuclei of the hypothalamus?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Thirst","bool":false},{"option":"Feeling of rage","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased appetite","bool":true},{"option":"Increased appetite","bool":false}],"id":441},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"About the axons of the peripheral nerve, which of the following is incorrect?","answers":[{"option":"It may arise from axon hillock","bool":false},{"option":"It transmits action potential","bool":false},{"option":"It may arise from the perikyon (Soma)","bool":false},{"option":"It may arise from a dendrite","bool":false},{"option":"It contains nissl substance","bool":true}],"id":442},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Where does absorption of cerebrospinal fluid occur?","answers":[{"option":"Epidural space","bool":false},{"option":"Arachnoid villi","bool":true},{"option":"3rd ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Aqueduct of Sylvius","bool":false}],"id":443},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Damage to which of the following results in lesion of the oculomotor nerve nucleus in the midbrain?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Basilar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Vertebral artery","bool":false}],"id":444},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is an ascending tract in the posterior white column?","answers":[{"option":"Spino-olivary tract","bool":false},{"option":"Fasciculus gracilis tract","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior spinocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior spinocerebellar tract","bool":false}],"id":445},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which is NOT true about Betz cells?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"They are present in the 6th layer of cerebral cortex","bool":true},{"option":"They are present in the 5th layer of cerebral cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Their axons pass to the spinal cord as corticospinal fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Largest cells of the central nervous system","bool":false}],"id":446},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"What is the rate of formation of cerebrospinal fluid?","answers":[{"option":"100 millilitre/each day","bool":false},{"option":"1000 millilitre/each day","bool":false},{"option":"2000 millilitre/each day","bool":false},{"option":"10 millilitre/each day","bool":false},{"option":"500 millilitre/each day","bool":true}],"id":447},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following tracts starts from the red nucleus, decussates in the midline, and descends down?","answers":[{"option":"Rubrospinal","bool":true},{"option":"Corticospinal","bool":false},{"option":"Tectospinal","bool":false},{"option":"Corticobulbar","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibulospinal","bool":false}],"id":448},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is correct for the function of the blood-brain barrier (BBB)?","answers":[{"option":"Provides nourishment and prevents toxic substances from entering the brain","bool":true},{"option":"Allows plasma proteins to enter","bool":false},{"option":"Synthesizes fibroblasts","bool":false},{"option":"Does not maintain a constant environment in the brain","bool":false},{"option":"Allows the big molecules to enter the brain","bool":false}],"id":449},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following accurately describes the action of cimetidine on warfarin?","answers":[{"option":"Affects the activity of the platelets","bool":false},{"option":"Increases the metabolism of warfarin","bool":false},{"option":"Decreases the affinity of warfarin for vitamin K epoxide reductase","bool":false},{"option":"Decreases the metabolism of warfarin","bool":true},{"option":"Increases the affinity of warfarin for vitman K epoxide reductase","bool":false}],"id":450},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following contains respiratory center in the brain?","answers":[{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":true},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false}],"id":451},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Chronic hypertension is the most critical risk factor for developing which of the following types of brain aneurysms?","answers":[{"option":"Traumatic aneurysm","bool":false},{"option":"Charcot-Bouchard aneurysm","bool":true},{"option":"Sacular aneurysm","bool":false},{"option":"Dissecting aneurysm","bool":false},{"option":"Mycotic aneurysm","bool":false}],"id":452},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"An 8-year-old boy fractured his skull during his fall. What is the first modality to be used for the examination of the fracture of the skull?","answers":[{"option":"X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"PET scan","bool":false},{"option":"MRI","bool":false},{"option":"Myelography","bool":false},{"option":"CT scan","bool":true}],"id":453},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following cranial nerve nuclei are present in the midbrain?","answers":[{"option":"III and IV","bool":false},{"option":"IV only","bool":false},{"option":"III, IV, and V","bool":true},{"option":"V, VI, and IV","bool":false},{"option":"III only","bool":false}],"id":454},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Damage to which one of the following structures of the midbrain produces auditory disturbance?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior colliculi","bool":true},{"option":"Superior colliculi","bool":false},{"option":"Superior brachium","bool":false},{"option":"Medial geniculate body","bool":false}],"id":455},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"The extrapyramidal motor system includes the pathway stemming from which of the following points of origin?","answers":[{"option":"Primary motor cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary motor cortex","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior colliculus","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Areas 3, 1, and 2","bool":false}],"id":456},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following signs and symptom occurs in Wernicke's sensory area lesion?","answers":[{"option":"Inability to read","bool":false},{"option":"Inability to write","bool":false},{"option":"Inability to understand and read only","bool":false},{"option":"Inability to speech","bool":false},{"option":"Inability to understand, read and write","bool":true}],"id":457},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"What is glycine in the brainstem characterized as?","answers":[{"option":"Amine derivative","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibitory neurotransmitter","bool":true},{"option":"Glycoprotein derivative","bool":false},{"option":"Excitatory neurotransmitter","bool":false},{"option":"Choline derivative","bool":false}],"id":458},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following correctly describes the Golgi tendon organs?","answers":[{"option":"Intrafusal fibers contractor","bool":false},{"option":"Neurotransmitters","bool":false},{"option":"Proprioceptors","bool":true},{"option":"Muscle spindles","bool":false},{"option":"Muscle relaxer","bool":false}],"id":459},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is not present in the granular cell layer of the cerebellum?","answers":[{"option":"Soma and axons of Golgi cells","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellar glomeruli","bool":false},{"option":"Axons of purkinje cells","bool":false},{"option":"Soma and dendrites of granule cells","bool":false},{"option":"Granule cell axons","bool":true}],"id":460},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"What is the most likely cause of an increase in proteins in cerebrospinal (CSF)?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperuricemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperglycemia","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglycemia","bool":false},{"option":"Breach in blood brain barrier","bool":true}],"id":461},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following is the histological feature of a peripheral nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Epineurium is a thin, regular collagenous coat","bool":false},{"option":"Around Schwann cells is a thin layer called the perineurium, consisting of reticular fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Each fascicle in invested by collagenous covering called perineurium","bool":true},{"option":"Epineurium does not extend deeply to fill the space between fascicles","bool":false},{"option":"Axons and Schwann cells are not enclosed within layers of connective tissue","bool":false}],"id":462},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Histologically, the neurons of the cerebral cortex do not include which of the following cells?","answers":[{"option":"Pyramidal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Purkinje cells","bool":true},{"option":"Fusiform cells","bool":false},{"option":"Betz cell","bool":false},{"option":"Granule cell","bool":false}],"id":463},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following is the distinguishing feature of the midbrain at the superior colliculus level?","answers":[{"option":"Fourth ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral aqueduct","bool":false},{"option":"Red nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Third ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Third and fourth ventricle","bool":false}],"id":464},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which nucleus is not present on the floor of the fourth ventricle?","answers":[{"option":"7 cranial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"9 cranial nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"6 cranial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"10 cranial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"12 cranial nucleus","bool":false}],"id":465},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"The insula lies at the bottom of which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Precentral gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Central sulcus","bool":false},{"option":"Calcarine sulcus","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral sulcus","bool":true},{"option":"Parieto-occipital sulcus","bool":false}],"id":466},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Lack of dopamine and degeneration of substantia nigra leads to abnormal movement and is referred to as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Parkinson disease","bool":true},{"option":"Athetosis","bool":false},{"option":"Huntington chorea","bool":false},{"option":"Wilson disease","bool":false},{"option":"Chorea","bool":false}],"id":467},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Lesion in cerebellum causes which of the following clinical conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Athermia","bool":false},{"option":"Aphasia","bool":false},{"option":"Aphagia","bool":false},{"option":"Difficulty in balance and gait","bool":true},{"option":"Mental retardation","bool":false}],"id":468},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is a  major relay centre for sensory afferents?","answers":[{"option":"Red nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":true},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Basal nucleus","bool":false}],"id":469},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A 60-year-old elderly male comes to the emergency department while becoming gradually unconscious. Upon conducting magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), there is no clear finding but it is reported by his family that he is fond of eating beef. Creutzfeldt-Jacob disease is suspected. What are the histopathological findings in Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease?","answers":[{"option":"Demyelination","bool":false},{"option":"Hemorrhagic infarcts","bool":false},{"option":"Granulomas","bool":false},{"option":"Intracytoplasmic vacuoles","bool":true},{"option":"Necrotizing inflammation","bool":false}],"id":470},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following statements is not true about the posterior horn of the lateral ventricle?","answers":[{"option":"Superior swelling of medial wall is caused by splenial fibers of corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Medial to tapetum optic radiations are present","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior swelling is produced by calcarine sulcus","bool":false},{"option":"Medial wall has 2 elevations","bool":false},{"option":"Roof and lateral wall formed by tapetum of corpus callosum","bool":false}],"id":471},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A 40-year-old man had an accident. He was initially fine but then started developing behavioral changes after few days. On examination, he had a contusion in the frontal lobe where he hit his head in the airbag. This happened due to?","answers":[{"option":"Excessive bleeding","bool":false},{"option":"Hematoma","bool":false},{"option":"Coup","bool":true},{"option":"Contrecoup","bool":false},{"option":"Fracture","bool":false}],"id":472},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is not a derivative of neuroectoderm?","answers":[{"option":"Macroglia","bool":false},{"option":"Microglia","bool":true},{"option":"Ependyma","bool":false},{"option":"Oligodendrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":false}],"id":473},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Damping of the motor movements is done by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Reticular system","bool":false},{"option":"Limbic system","bool":false},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":true}],"id":474},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is not a characteristic of midbrain when a transverse section is taken at the level of superior colliculus?","answers":[{"option":"Occulomotor nerve fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nerve fibers","bool":true},{"option":"Red nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Mesencephalic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral aqueduct","bool":false}],"id":475},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Facial colliculus is formed due to the looping around which of the following nuclei?","answers":[{"option":"Abducens nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Facial motor nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus ambiguous","bool":false},{"option":"Salivatory nucleus","bool":false}],"id":476},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which nucleus supplies soft palate and pharynx and has fibers from the glossopharyngeal and vagus nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Facial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus ambiguous","bool":true}],"id":477},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Fracture of which one of the following can damage facial nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior cranial fossa","bool":true},{"option":"Middle cranial fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cranial fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Jugular Foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Ethmoid bone","bool":false}],"id":478},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Before entering the tricarboxylic acid cycle, glucose is metabolized into pyruvate which enters the mitochondria of neurons and glial cells in the form of?","answers":[{"option":"Citrate","bool":false},{"option":"Lactate","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Oxaloacetate","bool":false},{"option":"Acetyl CoA","bool":true}],"id":479},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"How many layers are present in the cerebrum and cerebellum respectively?","answers":[{"option":"3 layers, 6 layers","bool":false},{"option":"4 layers, 6 layers","bool":false},{"option":"3 layers, 3 layers","bool":false},{"option":"3 layers, 1 layer","bool":false},{"option":"6 layers, 3 layers","bool":true}],"id":480},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is the main function of blood-brain barrier?","answers":[{"option":"Supplies nutrients while preventing hazardous chemicals from reaching the brain","bool":true},{"option":"Provides another layer of cerebrospinal fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Transmits electrical signals between neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Secretes neurotransmitters","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":481},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Pulsatile pain is transmitted through which of the following pathways?","answers":[{"option":"Fasciculus gracilis","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":true},{"option":"Fasciculus cuneatus","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Ventral spinothalamic tract","bool":false}],"id":482},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following is the function of ascending reticular system?","answers":[{"option":"Gastrointestinal motility","bool":false},{"option":"Alertness, wakefulness","bool":true},{"option":"Endocrine","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory","bool":false},{"option":"Vasomotor","bool":false}],"id":483},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following statements is incorrect about the central sulcus?","answers":[{"option":"Separates frontal lobe from temporal lobe","bool":true},{"option":"Present between two parallel gyri","bool":false},{"option":"Dents the super medial border of brain","bool":false},{"option":"Motor area is in front of the sulcus","bool":false},{"option":"Sensory area is behind the sulcus","bool":false}],"id":484},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A boy was pushed down the hill during the fight with his friends. As a result, he acquired a head injury. On examination, a hematoma is seen between the skull base and dura mater. Which of the following arteries is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior meningeal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Internal carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Vertebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle meningeal artery","bool":true}],"id":485},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following is best for the diagnosis of seizures?","answers":[{"option":"Electroencephalogram (EEG)","bool":true},{"option":"Myelography","bool":false},{"option":"Electroencephalogram (EEG) and Electromyography (EMG)","bool":false},{"option":"Nerve conduction","bool":false},{"option":"Electromyography (EMG)","bool":false}],"id":486},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following conditions is a neurosurgical emergency?","answers":[{"option":"Subarachnoid hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Subdural hematoma","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocephalus","bool":false},{"option":"Epidural hematoma","bool":true},{"option":"Intraparenchymal hemorrhage","bool":false}],"id":487},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following bone structures is related to pons?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior clinoid process","bool":false},{"option":"Sella turcica","bool":false},{"option":"Meckel's cave","bool":false},{"option":"Clivus","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior clinoid process","bool":false}],"id":488},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Non-REM sleep is most commonly associated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Tranquilizers","bool":false},{"option":"Bed wetting","bool":true},{"option":"Nightmares","bool":false},{"option":"Increased systolic blood pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Frequent dreaming","bool":false}],"id":489},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Central canal of spinal cord is continuous with:","answers":[{"option":"Cerebral aqueduct","bool":false},{"option":"Subarachnoid space","bool":false},{"option":"4th ventricle","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"3rd ventricle","bool":false}],"id":490},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"What is the enlargement of the medulla formed by the cortical motor tract?","answers":[{"option":"Trapezoid body","bool":false},{"option":"Olives","bool":false},{"option":"Pyramids","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior olivary nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus cuneatus","bool":false}],"id":491},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Using morphine to treat pain may cause following adverse effect:","answers":[{"option":"Addiction","bool":false},{"option":"Miosis","bool":true},{"option":"Increase blood pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Mydriasis","bool":false},{"option":"Stimulation of respiratory centres","bool":false}],"id":492},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Axons of the optic nerve are formed by central processes of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Ganglion cells","bool":true},{"option":"Pretectal nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Rods and cons","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Bipolar cells","bool":false}],"id":493},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Odd statement regarding heparin:","answers":[{"option":"Major side effect is bleeding","bool":false},{"option":"Does not cause bruising","bool":true},{"option":"Activity measured by PTT","bool":false},{"option":"Activity measured by aPTT","bool":false},{"option":"Depends on antithrombin III levels","bool":false}],"id":494},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"Rhombic alar lips of metencephalon form which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebrum","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":true}],"id":495},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2020"],"question":"A patient has weakness and difficulty in moving the contralateral lower limb. Which of the following arteries is responsible for this?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior cerebral","bool":true},{"option":"Middle cerebral","bool":false},{"option":"Middle meningeal","bool":false},{"option":"Vertebral","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cerebral","bool":false}],"id":496},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Lesion of which of the following would cause loss of vibration in the upper limbs?","answers":[{"option":"Dorsal white column on left side","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal lemniscus","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal white column on right side","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal white columns on both sides","bool":true}],"id":497},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A 21-year-old male got into an accident after which he could not move his body, except for the head, and the weak shrugging of the shoulders. He also lost all senses below the neck level. At which of the following levels is the lesion most likely to have occurred?","answers":[{"option":"Below T3","bool":false},{"option":"Below C7","bool":false},{"option":"Below T1","bool":false},{"option":"Below L1","bool":false},{"option":"Below C3","bool":true}],"id":498},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"In complete cord transection at the cervical level, what would be observed on checking for reflexes of the limbs?","answers":[{"option":"Absent reflexes","bool":false},{"option":"Initial hyporeflexia followed by hyperreflexia","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased reflexes","bool":false},{"option":"Exaggerated reflexes","bool":false},{"option":"Normal reflexes","bool":false}],"id":499},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A 21-year-old male got into an accident and is unable to move his body, except for the weak shrugging of his shoulders and the movement of his head. Which of the following nerves must be intact to allow this movement of the shoulders?","answers":[{"option":"Infrascapular nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Brachial plexus","bool":false},{"option":"Suprascpular nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical plexus","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":true}],"id":500},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"What would be observed in complete cord transection at the cervical level?","answers":[{"option":"Hemiplegia of right side","bool":false},{"option":"Hemiplegia of left side","bool":false},{"option":"Monoplegia of right upper limb","bool":false},{"option":"Paraplagia","bool":false},{"option":"Tetraplegia","bool":true}],"id":501},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Damage to which of the following nerves is responsible for the labored breathing in a patient with complete cord transection at cervical level?","answers":[{"option":"Hypoglossal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Phrenic nerve","bool":true}],"id":502},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A person had an accident after which he is unable to move his body, except for his head, and the weak shrugging of the shoulders. He has also lost all his senses including light touch, pain, and temperature senses below the neck level, and is now unable to perceive his position in space. The doctor immediately provides him with ventilation as he was not able to breathe properly. Which of the following is suspected?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior cord syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Brown-Sequard syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Complete cord transection syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Central cord syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Poliomyelitis","bool":false}],"id":503},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is responsible for carrying vibratory and proprioceptive information from the lower parts of the body?","answers":[{"option":"Rubrospinal pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior white column","bool":true},{"option":"Spinotectal pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false}],"id":504},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A person has lost sense of vibration, proprioception, and discriminative touch on the right upper limb. Lesion of which of the following is responsible for this loss?","answers":[{"option":"Medial lemniscus","bool":false},{"option":"Right fasciculus cuneatus","bool":true},{"option":"Left fasciculus gracilis","bool":false},{"option":"Left fasciculus cuneatus","bool":false},{"option":"Right fasciculus gracilis","bool":false}],"id":505},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Slow-wave sleep is concerned with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Increase in peripheral vascular tone","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in respiratory sleep","bool":false},{"option":"Dreams with less muscle involvement","bool":true},{"option":"Increase in blood pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in basal metabolic rate","bool":false}],"id":506},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following terms is used for fibers that connect different regions in the same cerebral hemisphere?","answers":[{"option":"Ventricles","bool":false},{"option":"Association fibers","bool":true},{"option":"Sinuses","bool":false},{"option":"Projection fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Commissural fibers","bool":false}],"id":507},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following arteries provides collateral vascular supply to the macular region of the occipital lobe?","answers":[{"option":"Labyrinthine artery","bool":false},{"option":"Basilar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior inferior cerebellar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cerebellar artery","bool":false}],"id":508},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"The corpora quadrigemina is a region present on the posterior surface of the midbrain. Which part of it is involved in the visual pathway?","answers":[{"option":"Optic chiasma","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral geniculate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior colliculus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior colliculus","bool":true},{"option":"Medial geniculate nucleus","bool":false}],"id":509},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following cells secrete nerve growth factors?","answers":[{"option":"Microglial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Oligodendrocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Ependymal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Schwann cells","bool":false}],"id":510},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following structures forms the medial wall of the lateral ventricle?","answers":[{"option":"Corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Body of the caudate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Head of the caudate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral margin of the thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Septum pellucidum","bool":true}],"id":511},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following would not be affected by a fracture involving the posterior cranial fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Occipital bone","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous part of the temporal lobe","bool":true},{"option":"Petrous part of the temporal lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Mastoid part of the temporal bone","bool":false}],"id":512},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"The consensual light reflex that leads to the constriction of the pupil of the eye with reference to light falling on the opposite eye is mediated via which of the following pathways?","answers":[{"option":"Corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior commissure","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior commissure","bool":false},{"option":"Habenular commissure","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocampal commissure","bool":false}],"id":513},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following substances is responsible for the inhibition of the satiety center and activation of the hunger center?","answers":[{"option":"Leptin","bool":false},{"option":"Ghrelin","bool":true},{"option":"Alpha melanocyte stimulation hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin","bool":false},{"option":"Parathyroid hormone","bool":false}],"id":514},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is a contraindication of a thrombolytic drug?","answers":[{"option":"Deep vein thrombosis","bool":false},{"option":"History of hypertension","bool":true},{"option":"Acute pulmonary thromboembolism","bool":false},{"option":"Acute myocardial infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Acute ischemic stroke","bool":false}],"id":515},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A patient is given an opioid injection after surgery for pain relief. Which of the following statements is correct regarding opioids?","answers":[{"option":"They are local anesthetic agents","bool":false},{"option":"Giving NSAIDs in addition will help provide more relief","bool":true},{"option":"Their action will be enhanced by naloxone","bool":false},{"option":"They will cause placebo effect","bool":false},{"option":"They will cause more respiratory stimulation","bool":false}],"id":516},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following would most likely be affected in the thalamic syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Inferolateral aspect of thalamus","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior aspect of thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Posterosuperior thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior portion of thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Posteroinferior portion of the thalamus","bool":false}],"id":517},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"The pineal gland is associated with which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Epithalamus","bool":true},{"option":"Hypocampus","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false}],"id":518},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following accurately describes the function of the nuclear bag fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Relaxation of muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Relaxation of antagonistic muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Sense the sustained pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Maintaining muscle length","bool":false},{"option":"Sense the onset of stress","bool":true}],"id":519},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A patient presents to the clinic with a degenerative bone disease that is causing narrowing of the foramen magnum. Which of the following structures would not be affected by the above condition?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior and anterior spinal arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Vertebral arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Internal carotid artery","bool":true},{"option":"Basilar arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory spinal nerve","bool":false}],"id":520},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following substances will be seen in nissl substance under the microscope?","answers":[{"option":"Rough endoplasmic reticulum","bool":true},{"option":"Lysosome","bool":false},{"option":"Golgi complex","bool":false},{"option":"Mitochondrion","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false}],"id":521},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"The red nucleus gives rise to the rubrospinal tract that arises from which of the following parts?","answers":[{"option":"Midbrain","bool":true},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false}],"id":522},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following forms the floor of the anterior horn of the lateral ventricle?","answers":[{"option":"Genu of the corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Body of the caudate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Head of the caudate","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior column of the fornix","bool":false},{"option":"Septum pellucidum","bool":false}],"id":523},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following structures is important for the perception of pain in the spinal cord?","answers":[{"option":"Clark's nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus proprius","bool":false},{"option":"Visceral afferent nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Substantia gelatinosa","bool":true},{"option":"Nucleus dorsalis","bool":false}],"id":524},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A patient is admitted to the emergency department due to a sudden feeling of nausea and vomiting. On analysis, gait and posture are normal but right foot movement is impaired. Which of the following parts must be involved in the lesion?","answers":[{"option":"Flocculonodular lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Vermis","bool":false},{"option":"Right cerebellar hemisphere","bool":false},{"option":"Left cerebellar hemisphere","bool":false},{"option":"Intermediate zone","bool":true}],"id":525},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following tracts carries the sensation of crude touch?","answers":[{"option":"Anterolateral spinothalamic pathway","bool":true},{"option":"Spinoreticular tract","bool":false},{"option":"Extrapyramidal pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal white column","bool":false},{"option":"Pyramidal pathway","bool":false}],"id":526},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following pathways is responsible for the transmission of senses of discriminative or fine touch?","answers":[{"option":"Dorsal column-medial lemniscus pathway","bool":true},{"option":"Spinoreticular pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Spinotectal pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false}],"id":527},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Anesthesia was given to the patient in order not to feel the pain during surgery. How does the anesthesia work?","answers":[{"option":"Blockage of voltage gated sodium channels","bool":true},{"option":"Opening of calcium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Blockage of ligand gated sodium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Blockage of voltage gated potassium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Blockage of ligand gated potassium channels","bool":false}],"id":528},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"The limbic system is the body's most important system regarding emotions and behavior, which part of the limbic system is responsible for memory consolidation?","answers":[{"option":"Hippocampus","bool":true},{"option":"Fornix","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Amygdala","bool":false},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false}],"id":529},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Reward and punishment centers are located in which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Limbic system","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":true},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":false}],"id":530},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Somatosensory area-I is highly localized and the somatosensory area-II is poorly localized. An ablation of the somatosensory area-I will significantly impair which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Pain perception","bool":false},{"option":"Crude touch","bool":false},{"option":"Proprioception","bool":false},{"option":"Ability to judge shapes and forms of the objects","bool":true},{"option":"Vibration","bool":false}],"id":531},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"At which of the following structures do the nerve impulses converge to create an action potential?","answers":[{"option":"Axon","bool":false},{"option":"Axon hillock","bool":true},{"option":"Synaptic junction","bool":false},{"option":"Dendrites","bool":false},{"option":"Axolemma","bool":false}],"id":532},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following represents the type of memory that is acquired but becomes unconscious and automatic later on?","answers":[{"option":"Non-associative learning","bool":false},{"option":"Episodic memory","bool":false},{"option":"Procedural memory","bool":true},{"option":"Associative learning","bool":false},{"option":"Priming","bool":false}],"id":533},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following terms accurately describes the condition in which a person is unable to read?","answers":[{"option":"Agraphia","bool":false},{"option":"Prosopagnosia","bool":false},{"option":"Alexia","bool":true},{"option":"Aphasia","bool":false},{"option":"Dysphagia","bool":false}],"id":534},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Lesion of which of the following parts will result in global aphasia?","answers":[{"option":"Wernicke's area","bool":false},{"option":"Broca's area","bool":false},{"option":"Wernicke's and Broca's area","bool":true},{"option":"Association area","bool":false},{"option":"Somatosensory area-I","bool":false}],"id":535},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is responsible for the negative resting membrane potential of -70 millivolts of neurons?","answers":[{"option":"Leaky sodium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Voltage gated potassium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Leaky potassium channels","bool":true},{"option":"Voltage gated sodium channels","bool":false}],"id":536},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A patient presents to the clinic with dementia and involuntary jerking movements of the body. On examination, it is found that the GABA secreting neurons of caudate and putamen are damaged. Which of the following is the most probable condition from which the patient must be suffering?","answers":[{"option":"Athetosis","bool":false},{"option":"Huntington's disease","bool":true},{"option":"Schizophrenia","bool":false},{"option":"Parkinson's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Chorea","bool":false}],"id":537},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Amino acid is converted to an amine by which of the following processes?","answers":[{"option":"Decarboxylation","bool":true},{"option":"Methylation","bool":false},{"option":"Carboxylation","bool":false},{"option":"Hydration","bool":false},{"option":"Deamination","bool":false}],"id":538},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"By which of the following processes does the monoamine oxidase catalyzes the catecholamine catabolism?","answers":[{"option":"Deamination","bool":true},{"option":"Oxidation","bool":false},{"option":"Methylation","bool":false},{"option":"Dehydrogenation","bool":false},{"option":"Decarboxylation","bool":false}],"id":539},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"In which of the following phases would the ketone bodies be utilized?","answers":[{"option":"After meal","bool":false},{"option":"Fasting","bool":true},{"option":"Between meals","bool":false},{"option":"Well fed state","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperglycemic phase","bool":false}],"id":540},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"What is the basic structure of the sphingosine?","answers":[{"option":"A 18-carbon amino alcohol with unsaturated hydrocarbon chain","bool":true},{"option":"A 18-carbon amino alcohol with saturated hydrocarbon chain","bool":false},{"option":"A 16-carbon amino alcohol","bool":false},{"option":"A 12-carbon alcohol","bool":false},{"option":"A 17-carbon amino alcohol with unsaturated hydrocarbon chain","bool":false}],"id":541},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following correctly describes the blood-brain barrier?","answers":[{"option":"Assists accumulation of potentially hazardous chemicals inside CNS","bool":false},{"option":"It is found in peripheral nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Prevents accumulation of potentially hazardous chemicals inside CNS","bool":true},{"option":"Endothelial cells are absent in this region","bool":false},{"option":"It is a freely permeable region","bool":false}],"id":542},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is a common complication of cerebral amyloid angiopathy with hypertension?","answers":[{"option":"Intracranial necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Intracerebral hemorrhage","bool":true},{"option":"Intracerebral clotting","bool":false},{"option":"Intracerebral abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Intracerebral edema","bool":false}],"id":543},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A public health officer ordered his staff to take measures for vector control in order to prevent diseases. Which of the following diseases can be prevented by this project?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebral malaria","bool":true},{"option":"Peptic ulcer","bool":false},{"option":"Diphtheria","bool":false},{"option":"Meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Gastritis","bool":false}],"id":544},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following should be the relationship between the doctor and the patient?","answers":[{"option":"Consumeristic relationship","bool":false},{"option":"Both should be equally involved in consultation as partners","bool":false},{"option":"Mutual relationship","bool":true},{"option":"Default relationship","bool":false},{"option":"Paternalistic relationship","bool":false}],"id":545},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of stroke in young adults?","answers":[{"option":"Smoking","bool":true},{"option":"Alcohol","bool":false},{"option":"Lack of exercise","bool":false},{"option":"Obesity","bool":false},{"option":"Fatty diet","bool":false}],"id":546},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is the best method to detect slipped intervertebral disc or herniated disc?","answers":[{"option":"Computed tomography scan","bool":false},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging","bool":true},{"option":"Electroencephalography","bool":false},{"option":"Electrocardiography","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":false}],"id":547},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is an antagonist of the muscarinic receptor?","answers":[{"option":"Curare","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Atropine","bool":true},{"option":"Botulinum","bool":false},{"option":"Muscarine","bool":false}],"id":548},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is the first complete documented set of rules of ancient ethics?","answers":[{"option":"Nuremberg code","bool":false},{"option":"Alma mater","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocratic oath","bool":true},{"option":"Declaration of Geneva","bool":false},{"option":"Helsinki Declaration","bool":false}],"id":549},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which part of the neuron has the Nissl substance?","answers":[{"option":"Terminal dendrites","bool":false},{"option":"Soma","bool":true},{"option":"Axon","bool":false},{"option":"Synaptic bouton","bool":false},{"option":"Axon hillock","bool":false}],"id":550},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which nucleus is activated upon suckling during breastfeeding?","answers":[{"option":"Paraventricular","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Supraoptic","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior","bool":false}],"id":551},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which part of the internal capsule is involved in a pure motor stroke?","answers":[{"option":"Sublentiform part","bool":false},{"option":"Retrolentiform part","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior limb","bool":true},{"option":"Genu","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior limb","bool":false}],"id":552},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following nuclei is not present in the white matter of the cerebellum?","answers":[{"option":"Fastigial","bool":false},{"option":"Putamen","bool":true},{"option":"Dentate","bool":false},{"option":"Emboliform","bool":false},{"option":"Globose","bool":false}],"id":553},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which artery is involved in the supply of leg and foot areas of the primary motor cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior cerebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior communicating artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior communicating artery","bool":false}],"id":554},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A 58-year-old patient comes to the emergency room with his wife with complaints of inability to speak, weakness in his right upper limb, and is unable to understand what others are saying. The symptoms started 1 hour ago. He is known to have had hypertension for the past 8 years. A physical exam is performed by the doctor and a CT scan is ordered since the doctor suspects a stroke. Which artery is most likely to have the lesion?","answers":[{"option":"Superior cerebellar","bool":false},{"option":"Right anterior cerebral","bool":false},{"option":"Left anterior cerebral","bool":false},{"option":"Right middle cerebral","bool":false},{"option":"Left middle cerebral","bool":true}],"id":555},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which cranial nerve nucleus extends throughout all three structures of the brainstem?","answers":[{"option":"Facial","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglossal","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal","bool":true}],"id":556},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"If a transverse section is taken through the caudal part of the pons, at the level of the facial colliculus, which structure will remain unaffected?","answers":[{"option":"Spinal nucleus of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Pontine nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Medial vestibular nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Mesencephalic nucleus of trigeminal nerve","bool":true}],"id":557},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"What is the initial modality used for fractures?","answers":[{"option":"Myelography","bool":false},{"option":"PET","bool":false},{"option":"CT","bool":false},{"option":"MRI","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray","bool":true}],"id":558},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A reproductive age female reported to the outpatient department with no prior dose of tetanus vaccine. What are the recommended doses by EPI protocol of tetanus for long-term prevention?","answers":[{"option":"Two doses","bool":false},{"option":"Four doses","bool":false},{"option":"Three doses","bool":false},{"option":"Five doses","bool":true},{"option":"Single dose","bool":false}],"id":559},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which structure is not present in the medial wall of the cerebral hemisphere?","answers":[{"option":"Cuneus","bool":false},{"option":"Paracentral lobule","bool":false},{"option":"Precuneus","bool":false},{"option":"Insula","bool":true},{"option":"Corpus callosum","bool":false}],"id":560},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A person has social and emotional changes due to damage to which lobe?","answers":[{"option":"Occipital","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal","bool":true},{"option":"Parietal","bool":false},{"option":"Paracentral lobule","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal","bool":false}],"id":561},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following options is incorrectly matched?","answers":[{"option":"Multipolar Neurons ‚Äì sensory and dorsal nuclei","bool":true},{"option":"Bipolar neurons ‚Äì special senses","bool":false},{"option":"Betz cell ‚Äì motor activity","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudo unipolar ‚Äì dorsal root ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Purkinje cells ‚Äì cerebellar cortex","bool":false}],"id":562},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Viral meningitis is detected by an increase in which of the following components of cerebrospinal fluid?","answers":[{"option":"Protein","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Erythrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false}],"id":563},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"The choroid plexus of the third ventricle is derived from which part of the brain?","answers":[{"option":"Alar plates of diencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Roof plates of diencephalon","bool":true},{"option":"Rathke‚Äôs pouch","bool":false},{"option":"Basal plate of prosencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Floor plate of diencephalon","bool":false}],"id":564},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following does not arise from the neural tube?","answers":[{"option":"Neuroblast","bool":false},{"option":"Oligodendrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Ependymal","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Microglia","bool":true}],"id":565},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"In chronic gliosis, elongated, brightly eosinophilic protein aggregates within astrocyte processes are formed. What are they termed as?","answers":[{"option":"Rosenthal fibers","bool":true},{"option":"Nissl bodies","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Microglial granules","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrillary astrocytes","bool":false}],"id":566},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Obstruction at the foramen of Monro will cause which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Communicating hydrocephalus","bool":false},{"option":"Encephalitis","bool":false},{"option":"Non communicating hydrocephalus","bool":true},{"option":"Meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral edema","bool":false}],"id":567},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which neurotransmitter is released by all preganglionic neurons of autonomic nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Adrenaline","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":true},{"option":"Thyroxine","bool":false},{"option":"Substance P","bool":false}],"id":568},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"The visual cortex is present in the wall of which of the following sulci?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral sulcus","bool":false},{"option":"Central sulcus","bool":false},{"option":"Calcarine sulcus","bool":true},{"option":"Precentral sulcus","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":569},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which fibrinolytic drug also has an antigenic effect?","answers":[{"option":"Urokinase","bool":false},{"option":"Urokinase + Alteplase","bool":false},{"option":"Alteplase","bool":false},{"option":"Streptokinase","bool":true},{"option":"Streptokinase + Alteplase","bool":false}],"id":570},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is incorrect about the glomerulus in the cerebellum?","answers":[{"option":"Present in molecular layer","bool":true},{"option":"Mossy fibers synapse here","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Golgi cells are present here","bool":false},{"option":"Present in granular layer","bool":false}],"id":571},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"The nerve which passes through stylomastoid foramen does not supply which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Sublingual gland","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid gland","bool":true},{"option":"Buccinator","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal gland","bool":false},{"option":"Orbicularis oculi","bool":false}],"id":572},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"An 8-year-old boy presented with sudden neck stiffness, headache, and flu-like symptoms. After three days, his CSF showed mild lymphocytic pleocytosis, slightly decreased glucose, and mildly increased protein. Which organism is likely responsible for this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Treponema pallidum","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Borrelia burgdorferi","bool":false},{"option":"Enterovirus","bool":true},{"option":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis","bool":false}],"id":573},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which artery supplies the choroid plexus of the fourth ventricle?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior inferior cerebellar artery","bool":true},{"option":"Basilar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Pontine arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Superior cerebellar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior inferior cerebellar artery","bool":false}],"id":574},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"The arterial supply of the dorsal and lateral walls of the medulla oblongata is affected. Which of the following will not be observed?","answers":[{"option":"Loss of sense of pain","bool":false},{"option":"Dysphagia","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of sense of temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Paralysis of the tongue","bool":true},{"option":"Dysphonia","bool":false}],"id":575},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A person has lost point discrimination on his left hand. Which structure is affected?","answers":[{"option":"Right fasciculus cuneatus at the level of C2","bool":false},{"option":"Right fasciculus cuneatus at the level of thoracic vertebra","bool":false},{"option":"Left fasciculus gracilis at the level of C2","bool":false},{"option":"Right fasciculus gracilis at the level of thoracic vertebra","bool":false},{"option":"Right medial lemniscus at the level of pons","bool":true}],"id":576},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A person has resting tremors, a stooping posture, and a shuffling gait. Which structure of the brain has undergone neuronal degeneration?","answers":[{"option":"Cortical areas","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Basal nuclei","bool":true}],"id":577},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Right hemisection of the spinal cord at the level of C8 will result in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Flaccid paralysis of left upper limb","bool":false},{"option":"Spastic paralysis of lower face","bool":false},{"option":"Spastic paralysis of right upper limb","bool":false},{"option":"Spastic paralysis of left lower limb","bool":false},{"option":"Spastic paralysis of right lower limb","bool":true}],"id":578},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"In increased thirst, the brain responds to the increased osmolality of the extracellular fluid by activating which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Osmoreceptors","bool":true},{"option":"Ionic receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Mechanoreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Aquaporins","bool":false},{"option":"Chemoreceptors","bool":false}],"id":579},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"The anterior cerebral artery will be compressed as a result of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Transtentorial herniation","bool":false},{"option":"Subfalcine herniation","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebellar herniation","bool":false},{"option":"Uncinate herniation","bool":false},{"option":"Tonsillar herniation","bool":false}],"id":580},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Epithalamus is a structure located on the posterior part of the diencephalon. Which of the following is not a part of the epithalamus?","answers":[{"option":"Glial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Pineal gland","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior commissure","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior commissure","bool":true},{"option":"Habenular commissure","bool":false}],"id":581},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"What is the role of the corticospinal tract?","answers":[{"option":"Sympathetic system control","bool":false},{"option":"Parasympathetic system control","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of voluntary movement","bool":false},{"option":"Voluntary motor control","bool":true},{"option":"Reflex postural movement","bool":false}],"id":582},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is responsible for the dynamic control of muscle spindles?","answers":[{"option":"Nuclear bag fibers","bool":true},{"option":"Intrafusal fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Gamma-s fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Nuclear chain fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Extrafusal fibers","bool":false}],"id":583},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Sense of vibration travels to the central nervous system through which of the following pathways?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior spinocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior spinocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal column","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false}],"id":584},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A patient with right cerebellar dysfunction will most likely present with which of the following signs?","answers":[{"option":"Positive Romberg's sign","bool":false},{"option":"Swaying back and forth with eyes closed","bool":false},{"option":"Dysdiadochokinesia","bool":true},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Person tends to fall to the left","bool":false}],"id":585},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is a pathognomonic feature found in patients with rabies?","answers":[{"option":"Depression","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrophobia","bool":true},{"option":"Convulsions","bool":false},{"option":"Agoraphobia","bool":false},{"option":"Irritation","bool":false}],"id":586},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"The highly vascular layer of the spinal cord forms which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Falx cerebelli","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragm sellae","bool":false},{"option":"Filum terminale","bool":true},{"option":"Tentorium cerebelli","bool":false},{"option":"Cisterna magna","bool":false}],"id":587},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which cranial nerve is concerned with accommodation and light reflex?","answers":[{"option":"III","bool":true},{"option":"V","bool":false},{"option":"IV","bool":false},{"option":"II","bool":false},{"option":"VI","bool":false}],"id":588},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Pinpoint pupils are seen in hemorrhage of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":true},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":false}],"id":589},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Cerebrospinal-filled cavities are lined by ependymal cells. These cells are derived from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Pachymeninges","bool":false},{"option":"Leptomeninges","bool":false},{"option":"Meningovax","bool":false},{"option":"Neuroepithelium","bool":true},{"option":"Marginal Layer","bool":false}],"id":590},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A 60-year-old diabetic patient has numbness in his left foot and leg. Which artery is affected?","answers":[{"option":"Right middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left anterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Right anterior cerebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Left middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left anterior cerebellar artery","bool":false}],"id":591},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which structure controls the function of the motor cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Supplementary motor area","bool":false},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Somatosensory area","bool":false},{"option":"Premotor area","bool":true}],"id":592},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A pathway that consists of the superior olivary nucleus and the trapezoid body connecting to the inferior colliculus and the medial geniculate body is responsible for detecting which sense?","answers":[{"option":"Smell","bool":false},{"option":"Equilibrium","bool":false},{"option":"Vision","bool":false},{"option":"Gustation","bool":false},{"option":"Hearing","bool":true}],"id":593},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which trigeminal nerve nucleus senses touch and pressure from the face?","answers":[{"option":"Mesencephalic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Sensory nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Motor nucleus","bool":false}],"id":594},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Infections from the nasal mucosa can spread to the olfactory bulb in the cranial cavity due to the olfactory nerve passing through which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Crista galli","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen magnum","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior perforated substance","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Cribriform plate","bool":true}],"id":595},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"What is the combination of a motor nerve and all the muscle fibers it innervates called?","answers":[{"option":"Functional unit","bool":false},{"option":"Motor unit","bool":true},{"option":"Motor end plate","bool":false},{"option":"Neuromuscular junction","bool":false},{"option":"Synapse","bool":false}],"id":596},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is a possible side effect of morphine?","answers":[{"option":"Mydriasis","bool":false},{"option":"Blood pressure elevation","bool":false},{"option":"Miosis","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory stimulation","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":597},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Right supranuclear facial nerve damage will result in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Right lower facial motor loss","bool":false},{"option":"Left upper facial motor loss","bool":false},{"option":"Right upper facial motor loss","bool":false},{"option":"Left lower facial motor loss","bool":true},{"option":"Upper and lower facial motor loss","bool":false}],"id":598},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Nerves supplying extraocular muscles of the eye pass through which part of the internal capsule?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior limb","bool":false},{"option":"Retrolentiform","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior limb","bool":false},{"option":"Sublentiform","bool":false},{"option":"Genu","bool":true}],"id":599},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A person stepped on a piece of glass and flexed his right leg to avoid it while his left leg extended. What is this called?","answers":[{"option":"Crossed extensor reflex","bool":true},{"option":"Galloping reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Withdrawal reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Reciprocal inhibition","bool":false},{"option":"Flexor reflex","bool":false}],"id":600},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"What is the function of the vestibulospinal tract?","answers":[{"option":"Facilitates flexor muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Reflex postural movement","bool":false},{"option":"Sympathetic control","bool":false},{"option":"Facilitates extensor muscles","bool":true},{"option":"Rapid, skilled voluntary movement","bool":false}],"id":601},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A patient dies due to cerebellar tonsil herniation through the foramen magnum. What is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Nerve compression","bool":false},{"option":"Subdural hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory failure","bool":true},{"option":"Epidural hemorrhage","bool":false}],"id":602},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is not associated with the fight and flight response?","answers":[{"option":"Paravertebral ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Thoracolumbar outflow","bool":false},{"option":"Prevertebral ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Craniosacral outflow","bool":true},{"option":"Long postganglionic fibers","bool":false}],"id":603},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"A person suffered from a head injury resulting in the damage of the temporal lobe of the dominant hemisphere. The person is unable to understand words. What is this condition called?","answers":[{"option":"Expressive aphasia","bool":false},{"option":"Alexia","bool":false},{"option":"Receptive aphasia","bool":true},{"option":"Global aphasia","bool":false},{"option":"Agraphia","bool":false}],"id":604},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2021"],"question":"The myelin sheath in the central nervous system is made of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Schwann cells","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Oligodendrocyte","bool":true},{"option":"Microglia","bool":false},{"option":"Ependymal cells","bool":false}],"id":605},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"The posterior grey horn of the spinal cord develops from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Floor plate","bool":false},{"option":"Roof plate","bool":false},{"option":"Sulcus limitans","bool":false},{"option":"Basal plate","bool":false},{"option":"Alar plate","bool":true}],"id":606},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following glial cells is not derived from the neuroectoderm?","answers":[{"option":"Ependymal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Microglial cells","bool":true},{"option":"Schwann cells","bool":false},{"option":"Oligodendrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":false}],"id":607},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following thalamic nuclei receives sensory afferents from the face and mouth?","answers":[{"option":"Ventro-posterior lateral","bool":false},{"option":"Ventral anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Ventro-posterior medial","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral dorsal","bool":false},{"option":"Pulvinar","bool":false}],"id":608},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A 60-year-old hypertensive male was taken to the emergency department with complaints of sudden onset of nausea and vomiting. The examination revealed slurred speech and dysmetria on finger-to-nose test on the left side. However, his gait was normal. In which of the following areas lesion has occurred?","answers":[{"option":"Right flocculonodular lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Right cerebellar hemisphere","bool":false},{"option":"Left cerebellar hemisphere","bool":true},{"option":"Fastigial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibular nucleus","bool":false}],"id":609},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A radiologist, while reading the computed tomography scan, noticed a jugular tubercle grooved by IX, X, and XI cranial nerves. This tubercle is part of which of the following bones?","answers":[{"option":"Temporal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Ethmoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital bone","bool":true},{"option":"Sphenoid bone","bool":false}],"id":610},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"An 80-year-old male came to the hospital with a head injury due to a bad fall. He had a stylomastoid fracture. Which of the following nerves is most likely to be damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibulocochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Ophthalmic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Olfactory nerve","bool":false}],"id":611},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A 45-year-old female is in recovery from a stroke. She is found to have difficulty in speech. She can write the words and can understand their meanings but is unable to produce words. Where is the cerebral cortical area responsible for the above-stated condition located?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior frontal gyrus","bool":true},{"option":"Superior frontal gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle temporal gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior temporal gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle frontal gyrus","bool":false}],"id":612},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"What are the commissural fibers associated with the olfactory pathway called?","answers":[{"option":"Hippocampal commissure","bool":false},{"option":"Corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Habenular commissure","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior commissure","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior commissure","bool":true}],"id":613},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which one of the following arteries supplies the medulla oblongata?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior communicating artery","bool":false},{"option":"Basilar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior cerebellar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior inferior cerebellar artery","bool":true}],"id":614},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following arteries supply the corpus striatum and internal capsule?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior inferior cerebellar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior communicating artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior cerebellar artery","bool":false}],"id":615},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Auditory fibers run in the lateral lemniscus terminate in which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Crus cerebri","bool":false},{"option":"Superior colliculus","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral geniculate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior colliculus","bool":true},{"option":"Medial leminiscus","bool":false}],"id":616},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is present anterior to the interventricular foramen?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior column of fornix","bool":true},{"option":"Septum pellucidum","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior end of thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior commissure","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior column of fornix","bool":false}],"id":617},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Gray rami communicans are derived from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior horn of spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Adjacent ganglion of sympathetic trunk","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral horn of spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Paravertebral ganglion","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior root ganglion","bool":false}],"id":618},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following can be caused by an infarction of the genu of the internal capsule?","answers":[{"option":"Visual impairment","bool":false},{"option":"Agitation","bool":false},{"option":"Dysarthria","bool":true},{"option":"Confusion","bool":false},{"option":"Auditory deficits","bool":false}],"id":619},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following cells line the central canal?","answers":[{"option":"Microglia","bool":false},{"option":"Multipolar neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Oligodendrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Ependymal cells","bool":true}],"id":620},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is the correct option regarding the cerebellum?","answers":[{"option":"Purkinje neurons are of bipolar variety","bool":false},{"option":"Superior cerebellar peduncle connects cerebellum to pons","bool":false},{"option":"Stellate and basket cells are present in the molecular layer","bool":true},{"option":"Molecular, granular, and pyramidal layers are present in cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Purkinje cells have scarce branching","bool":false}],"id":621},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"The cuneocerebellar pathway conveys information from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Muscles and joints of upper limb and upper part of thorax","bool":true},{"option":"Mid brain","bool":false},{"option":"Red nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Muscles and joints of trunk and lower limb","bool":false},{"option":"Muscles and joints of upper and lower limb","bool":false}],"id":622},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"During resting, the heart rate is slowed, pupils are constricted, peristalsis and glandular activity are increased, sphincters are opened, and the bladder wall is contracted. Which of the following system is activated in this state?","answers":[{"option":"Somatic nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Sympathetic nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Enteric nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Parasympathetic nervous system","bool":true},{"option":"Autonomic nervous system","bool":false}],"id":623},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Meroanencephaly is defined as the partial absence of the brain. It is caused by which of the following defects?","answers":[{"option":"Defect in regionalization","bool":false},{"option":"Disorder of myelination","bool":false},{"option":"Failure of closure of anterior neuropore","bool":true},{"option":"Failure of neural crest cells formation","bool":false},{"option":"Failure of closure of posterior neuropore","bool":false}],"id":624},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Cystic mass containing meninges with CSF only protrudes at the thoracolumbar region of a newborn. This cystic mass would be classified as which of the following defects?","answers":[{"option":"Spina bifida","bool":false},{"option":"Spina bifida occulta","bool":false},{"option":"Spina bifida aperta","bool":false},{"option":"Spina bifida cystica with meningocele","bool":true},{"option":"Spina bifida cystica with meningomylocele","bool":false}],"id":625},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Basal nuclei are a collection of cell bodies that control voluntary movements. Which of the following vesicles gives rise to basal nuclei?","answers":[{"option":"Metencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Telencephalon","bool":true},{"option":"Diencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Mesencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Myelencephalon","bool":false}],"id":626},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A vascular lesion of the primary visual area (Brodmann area 17) may cause which one of the following defects?","answers":[{"option":"Binasal hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Contralateral homonymous hemianopia with macular sparing","bool":true},{"option":"Blindness","bool":false},{"option":"Bitemporal hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Contralateral homonymous hemianopia","bool":false}],"id":627},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A 20-year-old girl presented with severe weight loss. On history, she admitted that her appetite is greatly reduced and she is experiencing sleep disturbances for the last two months. Which hypothalamic nucleus controls the appetite center?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral hypothalamic nuclei","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior hypothalamic nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Medial hypothalamic nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Paraventricular nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior hypothalamic nuclei","bool":false}],"id":628},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following tract conveys information about highly localized touch\r\nsensations and proprioception?","answers":[{"option":"Spino-reticular tract","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Spinocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal column tract","bool":true}],"id":629},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A patient loses the sensation of crude touch, while the sensation of fine touch is intact. Which of the following tracts is most likely to be damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Spinocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal column tract","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Ventral spinothalamic tract","bool":true},{"option":"Spino-reticular tract","bool":false}],"id":630},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A lesion in the dorsal column tract causes loss of proprioception resulting in severe ataxia. It can be confirmed by which of the following signs?","answers":[{"option":"Positive Romberg's test","bool":true},{"option":"Exaggerated tendon reflexes","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of tendon reflexes","bool":false},{"option":"Tremors","bool":false},{"option":"Positive Babinski's sign","bool":false}],"id":631},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A lesion in which of the following nuclei in the hypothalamus causes hypothalamic obesity?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral hypothalamic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Dorso-medial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Supra-optic nucleus nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Supra-chiasmatic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Ventromedial nucleus","bool":true}],"id":632},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following hypothalamic nuclei acts as the body's primary circadian pacemaker?","answers":[{"option":"Ventromedial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Dorso-medial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Supra-chiasmatic nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Red nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Supra-optic nucleus","bool":false}],"id":633},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is mostly associated with slow-wave sleep?","answers":[{"option":"Irregular heart rate","bool":false},{"option":"Dreaming","bool":false},{"option":"High frequency EEG waves","bool":false},{"option":"Memory","bool":false},{"option":"Sleep terrors","bool":true}],"id":634},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Prolonged rapid eye movement (REM) sleep deprivation can result in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Impaired driving","bool":false},{"option":"Teeth grinding","bool":false},{"option":"Increased appetite","bool":false},{"option":"Sleep terrors","bool":false},{"option":"Impaired memory","bool":true}],"id":635},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Maintaining working memory contents for a dozen seconds requires which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Amygdala","bool":false},{"option":"Prefrontal cortex","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Medial temporal lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocampus","bool":false}],"id":636},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Young children can immediately repeat short sentences spoken by their parents and siblings, and also produce new sentences that follow the rules of their native language. The ability to produce new, rule-governed sentences is thought to involve which kind of learning?","answers":[{"option":"Short-term","bool":false},{"option":"Explicit","bool":false},{"option":"Working","bool":false},{"option":"Long-term","bool":false},{"option":"Implicit","bool":true}],"id":637},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A 55-year-old male presents to the emergency department after a road traffic accident. Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) shows damage to the corticospinal tract on one side. Which of the following tract serves as an \"alternative pathway\" for transmitting motor signals to the spinal cord?","answers":[{"option":"Tectospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibulospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Rubrospinal tract","bool":true},{"option":"Reticulospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Olivospinal tract","bool":false}],"id":638},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"The sweat glands and piloerector muscles of hairy skin are innervated by which of the following fiber types?","answers":[{"option":"Adrenergic postganglionic sympathetic","bool":false},{"option":"Cholinergic postganglionic parasympathetic","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenergic preganglionic sympathetic","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenergic preganglionic parasympathetic","bool":false},{"option":"Cholinergic postganglionic sympathetic","bool":true}],"id":639},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which type of cholinergic receptor is found at synapses between preganglionic and postganglionic neurons of the sympathetic system?","answers":[{"option":"Muscarinic","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha","bool":false},{"option":"Beta 2","bool":false},{"option":"Nicotinic","bool":true},{"option":"Beta 1","bool":false}],"id":640},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following nerve fiber types is most sensitive to anesthetic agents?","answers":[{"option":"C fibers","bool":true},{"option":"A delta fibers","bool":false},{"option":"A gamma fibers","bool":false},{"option":"A alpha fibers","bool":false},{"option":"B fibers","bool":false}],"id":641},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which one of the following is the capability of the brain to ignore unimportant information?","answers":[{"option":"Facilitation","bool":false},{"option":"Reverberation","bool":false},{"option":"Consolidation","bool":false},{"option":"Sensitization","bool":false},{"option":"Habituation","bool":true}],"id":642},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A patient presents with the inability to interpret thoughts, although he is capable of expressing individual words or even short phrases. Which area of the brain is most likely to be affected?","answers":[{"option":"Wernicke's area","bool":true},{"option":"Angular gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Broca's area","bool":false},{"option":"Arcuate fasciculus","bool":false},{"option":"Exner's area","bool":false}],"id":643},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"During the removal of a brain tumor in a patient, a part of the brain was removed. Upon successful awakening, the patient is unable to form new memories. However, he can recall most previously learned memories satisfactorily. Which of the brain area may have been affected during the operation?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior hypothalamic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Epithalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Arcuate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocampus","bool":true}],"id":644},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following functions is the result of an increased activity of the sympathetic nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Pupillary constriction","bool":false},{"option":"Gallbladder emptying","bool":false},{"option":"Accommodation for near vision","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchiolar dilation","bool":true},{"option":"Penile erection","bool":false}],"id":645},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Long-term potentiation is identified in hippocampal mossy fibers by an increase in which of the following ions in the postsynaptic area?","answers":[{"option":"Potassium","bool":false},{"option":"Magnesium","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium","bool":true},{"option":"Sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphorus","bool":false}],"id":646},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"During an examination of a young boy, the child feels very ticklish so it becomes difficult for the doctor to examine him. Which of the following tract carries the above sensation?","answers":[{"option":"Corticospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":true},{"option":"Dorsal column medial leminiscal system","bool":false},{"option":"Spinocerebellar tract","bool":false}],"id":647},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"During suturing of a wound, a patient receives local anesthesia around the wound area. After this, he did not feel any needle pain during suturing. Which of the following option could be the reason for this?","answers":[{"option":"Blockage of voltage-gated Na‚Å∫ channels","bool":true},{"option":"Opening of ligand-gated Na‚Å∫ channels","bool":false},{"option":"Blockage of ligand-gated K‚Å∫ channels","bool":false},{"option":"Early closure of voltage-gated Na‚Å∫ channels","bool":false},{"option":"Blockage of voltage-gated K‚Å∫ channels","bool":false}],"id":648},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following sensations are relayed at the ventral posterolateral nuclei of the thalamus before reaching the post-central gyrus?","answers":[{"option":"Somatic afferents from head and arms","bool":false},{"option":"Somatic afferents from trunk and limbs","bool":true},{"option":"Visceral afferents from gut","bool":false},{"option":"Visceral afferents from gut","bool":false},{"option":"Somatic afferents from head and limbs","bool":false}],"id":649},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Secretion of melatonin by the pineal gland is regulated by which one of the following parts of the diencephalon?","answers":[{"option":"Globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Epithalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":true},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Metathalamus","bool":false}],"id":650},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is the rate-limiting enzyme of acetylcholine synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Phenylalanine hydroxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Choline acetyl transferase","bool":true},{"option":"Tyrosine hydroxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Aminotransferase","bool":false},{"option":"Choline esterase","bool":false}],"id":651},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"What is the reason that brain tissue cannot utilize fatty acids for energy?","answers":[{"option":"Enzymes of beta-oxidation are present in the brain","bool":false},{"option":"They are not found in brain tissue","bool":false},{"option":"They cannot pass through blood-brain barrier","bool":false},{"option":"Fatty acids are attached with albumin in blood","bool":true},{"option":"They are utilized in ganglioside formation","bool":false}],"id":652},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A compound that is synthesized in a neuron, has a receptor in vicinity, and has agonists and antagonists defines which of the following terms?","answers":[{"option":"Neurohormone","bool":false},{"option":"Neuromediator","bool":false},{"option":"Neuropeptide","bool":false},{"option":"Neurochemical mediator","bool":false},{"option":"Neurotransmitter","bool":true}],"id":653},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Practicing a healthy lifestyle by eating a diet rich in fruits and vegetables, and maintaining a healthy weight for the prevention of hypertension and stroke is advised by physicians. Which one of the following preventions is applied here?","answers":[{"option":"Secondary","bool":false},{"option":"Quarternary","bool":false},{"option":"Primary","bool":true},{"option":"Primordial","bool":false},{"option":"Tertiary","bool":false}],"id":654},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A surgeon working in a private rehabilitation facility encounters a patient with a certain tumor that responds only to radiotherapy and surgery. The surgeon is enthusiastic to perform the surgery and proceeds to convince the patient to perform the surgery despite the lack of evidence of surgery being the better option. Which of the following principles of ethical communication has the surgeon breached in the above scenario?","answers":[{"option":"Beneficence","bool":false},{"option":"Honesty and truthfulness","bool":true},{"option":"Equity and justice","bool":false},{"option":"Active listening","bool":false},{"option":"Empathy","bool":false}],"id":655},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following statements is correct regarding the mu receptor stimulation?","answers":[{"option":"Analgesia (spinal)","bool":false},{"option":"Sedation","bool":false},{"option":"Miosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hallucinations","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory depression","bool":true}],"id":656},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A 39-year-old woman has had a severe headache for 3 days. On physical examination,\r\nshe is afebrile and normotensive. Fundoscopic examination shows papilledema on the\r\nright. One day later, she has right pupillary dilation and impaired ocular movement. Which of the following lesions best explains these findings?","answers":[{"option":"Transtentorial medial temporal herniation","bool":true},{"option":"Ruptured middle cerebral berry aneurysm","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic subdural hematoma","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal lobe abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocephalus ex vacuo","bool":false}],"id":657},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"An 85-year-old male is in a coma in a hospital. His daughter makes all the decisions regarding his treatment on his behalf. Which of the following options best describes the type of consent in this scenario?","answers":[{"option":"Surrogate consent","bool":true},{"option":"Expressed consent","bool":false},{"option":"Informed consent","bool":false},{"option":"Opt-out consent","bool":false},{"option":"Implied consent","bool":false}],"id":658},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A 15-year-old girl presented to the outpatient department with complaints of headaches for the past 8 months. Over a 2-week period, she has a generalized seizure. On physical examination, there is no papilledema or movement disorder. Computed tomography (CT) scan of the head shows a 2 cm mass in the right frontal lobe and shows evidence of recent and remote hemorrhage. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Organizing abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Arteriovenous malformation","bool":true},{"option":"Prior head trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Ruptured saccular aneurysm","bool":false},{"option":"Angiosarcoma","bool":false}],"id":659},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is a modifiable risk factor for stroke?","answers":[{"option":"Genetics","bool":false},{"option":"Obesity","bool":true},{"option":"Gender","bool":false},{"option":"Family history","bool":false},{"option":"Age","bool":false}],"id":660},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Peripheral nerves are often damaged in many different forms of different vasculitis including polyarteritis nodosa (PAN), Churg-Strauss syndrome, and Wegener‚Äôs granulomatosis. Which of the following is the most common clinical picture in these disorders?","answers":[{"option":"Loss of sensation in limbs","bool":false},{"option":"Autonomic neuropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Combination neuropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Mononeuritis multiplex","bool":true},{"option":"Polyneuropathy","bool":false}],"id":661},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"As a medical professional, you have to come up with ideas for research that are original, unique, new, and relevant to your field of practice. This involves creative thinking. Which of the following will you follow?","answers":[{"option":"Preparation, accommodation, assimilation, centration, egocentrism","bool":false},{"option":"Incubation, preparation, revision, accommodation, centration","bool":false},{"option":"Assimilation, centration, egocentrism, incubation, revision","bool":false},{"option":"Preparation, incubation, illumination, evaluation, implementation","bool":true},{"option":"Accommodation, centration, egocentrism, incubation, revision","bool":false}],"id":662},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Ali saw a snake and he started trembling. The statement that Ali is afraid because he trembled is better explained by which of the following theories?","answers":[{"option":"Cannon-Bard theory","bool":false},{"option":"James-Lange theory","bool":true},{"option":"Darwin's theory","bool":false},{"option":"Two-factor theory","bool":false},{"option":"Appraisal theory","bool":false}],"id":663},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Destructive lesion of the Wernicke's area results in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Global aphasia","bool":false},{"option":"Astereognosis","bool":false},{"option":"Agraphia","bool":false},{"option":"Receptive aphasia","bool":true},{"option":"Expressive aphasia","bool":false}],"id":664},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which nerve exits the skull from the internal acoustic meatus along with the vestibulocochlear nerve (CN VIII)?","answers":[{"option":"Vagus nerve (CN X)","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve (CN VII)","bool":true},{"option":"Trigeminal nerve (CN V)","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve (CN IX)","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nerve (CN VI)","bool":false}],"id":665},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"What is the absolute contraindication of magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)?","answers":[{"option":"Allergies","bool":false},{"option":"Dyspnea","bool":false},{"option":"Claustrophobia","bool":false},{"option":"Indwelling cardiac pace maker","bool":true},{"option":"Movement Disorders","bool":false}],"id":666},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A 25-year-old male is brought to the emergency department with complaints of all four\r\nlimbs weakness for 3 days with a history of diarrhea 3 weeks before. On examination, he has flaccid areflexic quadriparesis and the sensations are intact with downgoing plantar. What should be the diagnostic investigation in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Nerve conduction studies","bool":true},{"option":"Serum electrolytes","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrospinal fluid detailed report (CSF DR)","bool":false},{"option":"MRI cervical spines","bool":false},{"option":"CT brain","bool":false}],"id":667},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A 20-year-old male presented to the neurology outpatient department with complaints of bilateral lower limb weakness and urinary incontinence for the last 4 days. On examination, he had decreased power in both lower limbs with increased tone, brisk reflex, and upgoing plantar. The sensory level was found at the xiphisternum. What is the most likely neurological localization in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Peripheral nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Brain stem","bool":false},{"option":"Muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior horn cells","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":true}],"id":668},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Vitamin K reverses the overdose of which of the following agents?","answers":[{"option":"Warfarin","bool":true},{"option":"Unfractionated heparin","bool":false},{"option":"Clopidogrel","bool":false},{"option":"Eptifibatide","bool":false},{"option":"Tirofiban","bool":false}],"id":669},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"What is the major advantage of magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) over computed tomography (CT) scan?","answers":[{"option":"Quick modality","bool":false},{"option":"Does not require any prior preparation","bool":false},{"option":"Superior in detection of calcified lesions","bool":false},{"option":"Use of ionization radiation","bool":false},{"option":"Excellent soft tissue imaging with high contrast sensitivity","bool":true}],"id":670},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A 35-year-old housewife presents to the neurology clinic for evaluation of persistent headache and vomiting for one week with intermittent clouding of consciousness and confusion. She had a prior history of weight loss and fever for the past two months. Two years back, she was treated for pulmonary tuberculosis and became asymptomatic. On examination, signs of meningeal irritation are positive with bilateral papilledema. MRI brain contrast suggests central nervous system tuberculosis. Cerebrospinal fluid detailed report is awaited. What is the most appropriate next step in the management of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Start anti-tuberculous therapy","bool":true},{"option":"Start anti-fungals","bool":false},{"option":"Start steroids","bool":false},{"option":"Wait for CSF report","bool":false},{"option":"Get an EEG done","bool":false}],"id":671},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A child is brought to the emergency room with complaints of severe vomiting and seizures. A radiologic scan revealed dilation of the fourth ventricle. Which of the following structures form(s) the floor of the fourth ventricle?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior surface of the pons and medulla","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior cerebellar peduncle","bool":false},{"option":"Superior cerebellar peduncle","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior surface of cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Superior and inferior medullary velum","bool":false}],"id":672},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A 55-year-old male patient presents to the neurology clinic with the complaint of not being able to acknowledge the left side of his body. He does not wash, shave, or use the left side of his body. A lesion in which of the following areas of the cerebral cortex is the most likely cause for this deficit in the patient?","answers":[{"option":"Primary somesthetic area","bool":false},{"option":"Prefrontal gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary somesthetic area","bool":false},{"option":"Precentral gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Somesthetic association area","bool":true}],"id":673},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following conditions is associated with low levels of gamma-aminobutyric acid (GABA)?","answers":[{"option":"Attention deficit hyperactivity disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Increased pain sensation","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral palsy","bool":false},{"option":"Epilepsy","bool":false},{"option":"Anxiety","bool":true}],"id":674},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following statements distinguishes the optic nerve from the optic tract?","answers":[{"option":"Optic nerve is a part of peripheral nervous system while optic tract is a part of central nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve has only ipsilateral fibers while optic tract has only contralateral fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve has Schwann cells while optic tract has oligodendrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve is unmyelinated while optic tract is myelinated","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve has only ipsilateral fibers while the optic tract has both ipsilateral and contralateral fibers","bool":true}],"id":675},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A 35-year-old man is brought to the emergency room after he suffers a head injury in a road traffic accident. It is observed that he has flailing movement in his left upper limb. Which of the following structures is the most likely site of lesion in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":true}],"id":676},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A 42-year-old woman suffered a head injury in a road traffic accident. She was brought to the emergency room and underwent an MRI scan, which revealed a hemorrhage in the inferior frontal gyrus. Which of the following symptoms is the most likely manifestation of a lesion in this area of the cerebral cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Inability to speak whole words","bool":true},{"option":"Paralysis of pharynx and larynx","bool":false},{"option":"Paralysis of the upper limb","bool":false},{"option":"Deviation of the eyes to side of lesion","bool":false},{"option":"Inability to grasp objects with her hands","bool":false}],"id":677},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"The craniosacral outflow constitutes the parasympathetic nervous system. The parasympathetic fibers of which of the following nerves control the pupillary and accommodation reflexes?","answers":[{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglossal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":true}],"id":678},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A 45-year-old woman suffers from a stroke and has difficulty with speech. She can write and understand speech but is unable to produce any words. The area affected in this case is located in which of the following gyri of the cerebral cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Precentral gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior frontal gyrus","bool":true},{"option":"Superior temporal gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior frontal gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle frontal gyrus","bool":false}],"id":679},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following types of neurons innervate extrafusal muscle fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Alpha motor neurons","bool":true},{"option":"A-delta neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Gamma motor neurons","bool":false},{"option":"C type nerve fibers","bool":false},{"option":"A-beta neurons","bool":false}],"id":680},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following types of nerve fibers innervate Golgi tendon organs?","answers":[{"option":"Ib sensory afferents","bool":true},{"option":"II sensory afferents","bool":false},{"option":"III sensory afferents","bool":false},{"option":"IV sensory afferents","bool":false},{"option":"Ia sensory afferents","bool":false}],"id":681},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is an opioid receptor antagonist used as a drug for opioid overdose and toxicity?","answers":[{"option":"Nalbuphine","bool":false},{"option":"Naloxone","bool":true},{"option":"Buprenorphine","bool":false},{"option":"Morphine","bool":false},{"option":"Fentanyl","bool":false}],"id":682},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following neurotransmitters equally excites both alpha and beta-adrenergic receptors?","answers":[{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":true},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false}],"id":683},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A 55-year-old man with a history of resting tremors in his right hand dies in a road traffic accident and undergoes an autopsy. His neurological examination is likely to reveal degeneration of neurons in which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Left corpus striatum","bool":false},{"option":"Left globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Left substantia nigra","bool":true},{"option":"Right globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Right substantia nigra","bool":false}],"id":684},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following statements correctly describes the main function of the blood-brain barrier?","answers":[{"option":"Detects changes in the chemical composition of blood","bool":false},{"option":"Secretes neurotransmitters","bool":false},{"option":"Supplies nutrition to and prevents hazardous substances from reaching the brain","bool":true},{"option":"Acts as a shock absorber","bool":false},{"option":"Secretes cerebrospinal fluid (CSF)","bool":false}],"id":685},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A child suffers from non-communicating hydrocephalus. Which of the following is a characteristic of non-communicating hydrocephalus?","answers":[{"option":"Post-hemorrhagic","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased absorption of CSF","bool":false},{"option":"Blockage of cerebral aqueduct","bool":true},{"option":"Post-infectious","bool":false},{"option":"Increased absorption of CSF","bool":false}],"id":686},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A 65-year-old male suffers from a cerebrovascular accident. An MRI scan reveals a lesion in the left internal capsule. Which of the following signs or symptoms is most likely to be observed in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Flaccid paralysis in left leg","bool":false},{"option":"Flaccid paralysis in right leg","bool":false},{"option":"Spastic paralysis in right leg","bool":true},{"option":"Hyporeflexia in left leg","bool":false},{"option":"Spastic paralysis in left leg","bool":false}],"id":687},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following opioid drugs is used to treat diarrhea?","answers":[{"option":"Loperamide","bool":true},{"option":"Levorphanol","bool":false},{"option":"Morphine","bool":false},{"option":"Naloxone","bool":false},{"option":"Methadone","bool":false}],"id":688},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following Brodmann's areas corresponds to the motor speech area of Broca?","answers":[{"option":"Brodmann area 44","bool":true},{"option":"Brodmann area 7","bool":false},{"option":"Brodmann area 17","bool":false},{"option":"Brodmann area 22","bool":false},{"option":"Brodmann area 41","bool":false}],"id":689},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A 67-year-old male patient presents to the clinic with complaints of not being able to shrug his shoulders and move his head from side to side over the last few days. Which of the following nerves is most likely to be damaged in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglossal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":true}],"id":690},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following disorders is characterized by excessive daytime sleepiness and sudden loss of muscle tone?","answers":[{"option":"Epilepsy","bool":false},{"option":"Somnolence","bool":false},{"option":"Cataplexy","bool":false},{"option":"Alzheimer's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Narcolepsy","bool":true}],"id":691},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following cell structures constitute the white matter of the central nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Cell bodies only","bool":false},{"option":"Axons and dendrites","bool":false},{"option":"Cell bodies and dendrites","bool":false},{"option":"Axons only","bool":false},{"option":"Axons and glial cells","bool":true}],"id":692},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following terms correctly describes the diphtheria toxin?","answers":[{"option":"Exotoxin","bool":true},{"option":"Neurotoxin","bool":false},{"option":"Endotoxin","bool":false},{"option":"Enterotoxin","bool":false},{"option":"Cytotoxin","bool":false}],"id":693},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is the most appropriate intervention after a child has been diagnosed with paralytic poliomyelitis?","answers":[{"option":"Awareness","bool":false},{"option":"Vaccination","bool":false},{"option":"Nutritional supplementation","bool":false},{"option":"Rehabilitation","bool":true},{"option":"Health education","bool":false}],"id":694},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"While operating on the pituitary gland, a surgeon tries to secure the optic chiasma. Which of the following structures separates the pituitary gland from the optic chiasm?","answers":[{"option":"Diaphragmatic sellae","bool":true},{"option":"Dorsum sellae","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculum sellae","bool":false},{"option":"Cavernous sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenoidal sinus","bool":false}],"id":695},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which part of the nervous system consists of two ganglionated nerve trunks extending the entire length of the vertebral column on both sides?","answers":[{"option":"Sympathetic nervous system","bool":true},{"option":"Parasympathetic nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Somatic nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Enteric nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Autonomic nervous system","bool":false}],"id":696},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following structures connects Wernicke's area to Broca's area?","answers":[{"option":"Internal capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Habenular commissure","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior commissure","bool":false},{"option":"Arcuate fasciculus","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior commissure","bool":false}],"id":697},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A 56-year-old woman presents to the outpatient clinic with the complaint of not being able to understand spoken language. She can, however, interpret written symbols and speech. Which of the following areas of the cerebral cortex is most likely to be damaged in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Wernicke's area","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary auditory area","bool":true},{"option":"Primary visual area","bool":false},{"option":"Primary auditory area","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary visual area","bool":false}],"id":698},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is an active efflux transporter in the blood-brain barrier?","answers":[{"option":"GLUT-1","bool":false},{"option":"GLUT-3","bool":false},{"option":"P-glycoprotein","bool":true},{"option":"GLUT-4","bool":false},{"option":"SGLT-2","bool":false}],"id":699},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Heparin binds to which of the following molecules to produce its anti-coagulant effect?","answers":[{"option":"Protein C","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-thrombin III","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin K","bool":false},{"option":"Von Willebrand factor","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinogen","bool":false}],"id":700},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A 55-year-old woman presents to the emergency room with a head injury following a road traffic accident. MRI scans reveal damage to the periaqueductal gray area of the midbrain. A lesion in this area is most likely to result in which of the following signs or symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Increased daytime drowsiness","bool":false},{"option":"Increased alertness and consciousness","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of endogenous pain suppression","bool":true},{"option":"Loss of conscious control of respiration from cerebral cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of coordination in the movement of the head and neck","bool":false}],"id":701},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"Which of the following parts of the cerebellum is involved in planning and coordinating movements?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral zone and dentate nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Intermediate zone and interposed nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Vermis and interposed nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Vermis and fastigial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral zone and fastigial nucleus","bool":false}],"id":702},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A child is born with agenesis of the corpus callosum which is a major commissural fiber. Which of the following findings is most likely to be seen in radiological scans of this child's brain?","answers":[{"option":"Deformed tapetum","bool":false},{"option":"Deformed internal capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Prominent forceps minor","bool":false},{"option":"Deformed lateral ventricles","bool":true},{"option":"Prominent forceps major","bool":false}],"id":703},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2022"],"question":"A 55-year-old man presents to the neurology clinic with the complaint of right-sided weakness of the body and left-sided weakness of the face with the tongue deviating to the left upon protrusion. Which of the following structures is most likely to be affected in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":true}],"id":704},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following veins is not a tributary of the cavernous sinus?","answers":[{"option":"Straight sinus","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior ophthalmic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Central vein of retina","bool":false},{"option":"Superior ophthalmic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenoparietal sinus","bool":false}],"id":705},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following veins drains into the superior sagittal sinus?","answers":[{"option":"Deep middle cerebral veins","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial middle cerebral veins","bool":false},{"option":"Striate veins","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cerebral veins","bool":false},{"option":"Superior cerebral veins","bool":true}],"id":706},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following cranial nerves does not originate at the pontomedullary junction of the brainstem?","answers":[{"option":"Olfactory nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibulocochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Nervus intermedius","bool":false}],"id":707},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following arteries is not a part of the circle of Willis?","answers":[{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior communicating artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior communicating artery","bool":false}],"id":708},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following statements regarding the long association fibers is incorrect?","answers":[{"option":"Lie deep beneath the cerebral cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Superior longitudinal fasciculus is the largest bundle of nerve fibers","bool":false},{"option":"They connect adjacent gyri","bool":true},{"option":"The cingulum is an example of long association fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Composed of white matter","bool":false}],"id":709},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 44-year-old patient presents to the outpatient clinic with the complaint of being unable to recall any recently occurring events. Which of the following brain structures is responsible for converting short-term memory into long-term memory?","answers":[{"option":"Indusium griseum","bool":false},{"option":"Fornix","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocampus","bool":true},{"option":"Parahippocampal gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Prefrontal cortex","bool":false}],"id":710},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 67-year-old male patient admitted to the neurology ward is observed to have intention tremor and cerebellar ataxia. Radiological scans reveal a pontine infarct. Which of the following fibers is most likely damaged in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Corticopontocerebellar tract","bool":true},{"option":"Parasympathetic fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Auditory fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Sympathetic fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Corticospinal tract","bool":false}],"id":711},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following is not a feature of postganglionic neurons of the sympathetic nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Are short in length","bool":true},{"option":"The cell bodies of postganglionic neurons are in autonomic ganglia located peripherally","bool":false},{"option":"Originate away from the effector organs","bool":false},{"option":"Noradrenergic","bool":false},{"option":"Unmyelinated","bool":false}],"id":712},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 62-year-old male patient is diagnosed with early-stage Parkinson's disease. The neurological examination reveals a slight resting tremor of the left hand, slow gait, and lack of the normal range of facial expression. Which of the following is the most likely site of the degenerative changes at this stage of the patient's disease?","answers":[{"option":"Right substantia niagra","bool":true},{"option":"Right globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Bilateral substantia niagra","bool":false},{"option":"Left globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Left substantia niagra","bool":false}],"id":713},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following structures forms the anterior boundary of the interventricular foramen of Monro?","answers":[{"option":"Crura of fornix","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior column of fornix","bool":false},{"option":"Body of fornix","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior column of fornix","bool":true},{"option":"Fimbria of fornix","bool":false}],"id":714},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 50-year-old male patient undergoes a CT scan which reveals a tumor of the midbrain. It shows symmetrical distension of the lateral ventricles and the third ventricle. Which of the following structures is most likely obstructed by the tumor in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Central canal","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral aqueduct","bool":true},{"option":"Foramen of Magendie","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen of Monroe","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen of Luschka","bool":false}],"id":715},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 53-year-old patient was brought to the emergency department after a fall. MRI scan reveals a slipped disc at the L3 level. Neurological examination shows that the patient has a bilateral loss of pain, temperature, and light touch sensation below the level of the lesion, bilateral lower motor neuron paralysis in the segment of the lesion, and bilateral spastic paralysis below the level of the lesion. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Syringomyelia","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cord syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Brown-S√©quard syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Central cord syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Complete cord transection syndrome","bool":false}],"id":716},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"The sensation of discriminative touch, vibratory sense, and conscious muscle joint proprioception of the lower limbs passes from the posterior root ganglia to the postcentral gyrus through which of the following pathways?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic and spinal lemniscus pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic and spinal lemniscus pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Fasciculus gracilis and spinal lemniscus pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic and medial lemniscus pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Fasciculus gracilis and medial lemniscus pathway","bool":true}],"id":717},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following embryological structures gives rise to the dorsal sensory horn of the spinal cord?","answers":[{"option":"Roof plate","bool":false},{"option":"Alar plate","bool":true},{"option":"Floor plate","bool":false},{"option":"Marginal layer","bool":false},{"option":"Basal plate","bool":false}],"id":718},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A parasympathetic nerve arising from the brainstem influences the lungs. The cell body of this nerve lies in which of the following nuclei?","answers":[{"option":"Dorsal nucleus of vagus","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior salivatory nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior salivatory nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimatory nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Edinger-Westphal nucleus","bool":false}],"id":719},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 24-year-old patient presents to the emergency department after a road accident with complaints of headache, nausea, vomiting & an altered level of consciousness. An X-ray of the skull reveals a fracture of the cribriform plate of the ethmoid bone. Which of the following cranial nerves passes through the foramina of this fractured bone?","answers":[{"option":"CN IV","bool":false},{"option":"CN V","bool":false},{"option":"CN II","bool":false},{"option":"CN III","bool":false},{"option":"CN I","bool":true}],"id":720},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"During a routine examination of a newborn baby in the pediatric clinic, the physician notices a depression of the anterior fontanelle (membranous gap in between bones of the skull). The depressed fontanelle lies between which of the following bones?","answers":[{"option":"Parietal and temporal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal and petrous part of temporal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal and mastoid part of temporal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal and parietal bone","bool":true},{"option":"Parietal and occipital bone","bool":false}],"id":721},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A patient who suffered from a road traffic accident is brought to the emergency room with a skull fracture involving bones of the anterior cranial fossa. Which of the following skull bones is most likely to be fractured in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Clivius","bool":false},{"option":"Lesser wings of sphenoid","bool":true},{"option":"Parietal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Greater wings of sphenoid","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal bone","bool":false}],"id":722},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A diabetic patient is observed to have mydriasis while undergoing an examination in an ophthalmology clinic. All other eye movements are normal. The nerve most likely affected in this case arises from which of the following brain stem nuclei?","answers":[{"option":"Superior salivatory nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus Ambiguus","bool":false},{"option":"Motor nucleus of CN III","bool":false},{"option":"Edinger-Westphal nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Spinal nucleus of CN V","bool":false}],"id":723},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A neonate is diagnosed with obstructive hydrocephalus. The parents were counseled and told that this condition is due to the blockage of a conduit between two ventricles of the brain. Which of the following is the most likely conduit obstructed in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Foramen of Monro","bool":false},{"option":"Paired foramen of Luschka","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen of Magendie","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen of Luschka","bool":false},{"option":"Aqueduct of Sylvius","bool":true}],"id":724},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"An unconscious male patient is brought to the emergency room. An MRI of the brain is performed and reveals infarction of the medial surface of the cerebral hemispheres. Which of the following cortical areas is likely to be affected in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Superior parietal lobule","bool":false},{"option":"Superior temporal gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle frontal gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior frontal gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Paracentral lobule","bool":true}],"id":725},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A patient suffers from a gunshot wound injuring his spinal cord on the left side. The patient now has loss of pain and temperature sensation on the right side of the body. Which of the following tracts is likely to be affected in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Left anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Left lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":true},{"option":"Dorsal column medial lemniscus pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Right lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Right anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false}],"id":726},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A cross-section of the cerebellum shows the cerebellar nuclei embedded in the white matter which is surrounded by the cortex. Which of the following nuclei is located most medially?","answers":[{"option":"Emboliform","bool":false},{"option":"Globose","bool":false},{"option":"Dentate","bool":false},{"option":"Putamen","bool":false},{"option":"Fastigial","bool":true}],"id":727},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"During a lecture on the basal nuclei, the professor mentions a part of the corpus striatum which is associated with the lateral ventricle medially and the internal capsule laterally. Which of the following structures of the corpus striatum is being mentioned?","answers":[{"option":"Caudate nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Claustrum","bool":false},{"option":"Putamen","bool":false},{"option":"Amygdaloid nucleus","bool":false}],"id":728},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"The two parietal bones form the sides and the roof of the skull and articulate with each other in the midline. Which of the following sutures is present between these bones?","answers":[{"option":"Sphenofrontal suture","bool":false},{"option":"Coronal suture","bool":false},{"option":"Lambdoid suture","bool":false},{"option":"Sagittal suture","bool":true},{"option":"Squamous suture","bool":false}],"id":729},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Within the cerebellar cortex, a basket-like nest is formed around the soma of which of the following cells?","answers":[{"option":"Basket cells","bool":false},{"option":"Stellate cells","bool":false},{"option":"Granule cells","bool":false},{"option":"Pyramidal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Purkinje cells","bool":true}],"id":730},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"The cerebellar cortex is composed of three layers. Which of the following layers is a synaptic zone that is mainly composed of dendritic arborizations of Purkinje cells?","answers":[{"option":"Pyramidal cell layer","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Purkinje cell layer","bool":false},{"option":"Granular cell layer","bool":false},{"option":"Molecular layer","bool":true}],"id":731},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"During the development of the spinal cord, the central canal is lined by three layers. Which of the three layers contains cell bodies of neurons?","answers":[{"option":"Ependymal layer","bool":false},{"option":"Marginal layer","bool":false},{"option":"Alar plate","bool":false},{"option":"Mantle layer","bool":true},{"option":"Ventricular layer","bool":false}],"id":732},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"During the 5th week of development, five brain swellings appear. These include the telencephalon, diencephalon, mesencephalon, metencephalon, and myelencephalon. The mesencephalon gives rise to which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebrum","bool":false}],"id":733},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"The speed of a nerve impulse is independent of which of the following factors?","answers":[{"option":"Diameter of nerve fiber","bool":false},{"option":"Physiological condition of the nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of myelin","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of neurolemmocyte","bool":false},{"option":"Length of nerve fiber","bool":true}],"id":734},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 20-year-old male was walking barefoot when he suddenly withdrew his leg when he accidentally stepped on a nail. Which of the following reflexes is responsible for activating the antagonistic contralateral extensor muscles in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Crossed extensor reflex","bool":true},{"option":"Plantar reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Stretch reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Babinski reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Visceral reflex","bool":false}],"id":735},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"During a study, the response of a particular reflex is inhibited for a while and then released suddenly, resulting in a response that is stronger than normal. This is known as which of the following properties of a reflex?","answers":[{"option":"Central delay","bool":false},{"option":"Rebound phenomenon","bool":true},{"option":"Habituation","bool":false},{"option":"Summation","bool":false},{"option":"Reciprocal innervation","bool":false}],"id":736},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 55-year-old male presented to the neurology clinic with the complaint of excessive daytime sleepiness. He was advised to undergo a sleep study. Just after midnight, the lab technician notices the EEG wave showing K complexes and sleep spindles. Which of the following stages of sleep is the patient in at that moment?","answers":[{"option":"Stage 3 (N3) of NREM sleep","bool":false},{"option":"Stages 1-3 of NREM sleep","bool":false},{"option":"Stage 4 REM sleep","bool":false},{"option":"Stage 2 (N2) of NREM sleep","bool":true},{"option":"Stage 1 (N1) of NREM sleep","bool":false}],"id":737},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following neurotransmitters is released by the Raphe neurons nerve endings is associated with the induction of sleep?","answers":[{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"GABA","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":true}],"id":738},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following parts of the cerebellum is involved in the planning of sequential movements?","answers":[{"option":"Spinocerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Intermediate zone","bool":false},{"option":"Flocculonodular lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Vermis","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral zone","bool":true}],"id":739},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following cerebellar disorders results in an inability to combine the various components of a movement to create a smooth action?","answers":[{"option":"Asynergia","bool":true},{"option":"Ataxia","bool":false},{"option":"Dysmetria","bool":false},{"option":"Asthenia","bool":false},{"option":"Dysdiadochokinesia","bool":false}],"id":740},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following nuclei of the basal ganglia receives input from the sub-thalamus via the indirect pathway?","answers":[{"option":"Substantia niagra","bool":false},{"option":"Lentiform nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Caudate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Globus pallidus internus","bool":true},{"option":"Putamen","bool":false}],"id":741},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 66-year-old male patient suffers from a cerebrovascular accident resulting in a complete loss of sensation on the right side of the body sparing the head and face. Which of the following nuclei of the thalamus is most likely to be affected by this lesion?","answers":[{"option":"Ventral anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Ventral posterolateral","bool":true},{"option":"Ventral lateral","bool":false},{"option":"Ventral posteromedial","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral geniculate","bool":false}],"id":742},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following brain waves are most likely to be present in the EEG of a healthy sleeping person and a brain-damaged awake person?","answers":[{"option":"Alpha waves","bool":false},{"option":"Gamma waves","bool":false},{"option":"Beta waves","bool":false},{"option":"Theta waves","bool":false},{"option":"Delta waves","bool":true}],"id":743},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 40-year-old woman suffers from a cut injuring a peripheral nerve. The distance between the two ends of the damaged nerve is less than 3 mm. Which of the following cells is responsible for the regeneration of this nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Oligodendrocyte","bool":false},{"option":"Ependymal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Microglia","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Schwaan cells","bool":true}],"id":744},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A neurologist plans to conduct a study on the properties of sensory neurons. Which of the following types of neurons is most appropriate for this study?","answers":[{"option":"Motor neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Bipolar neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Multipolar neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Unipolar neurons","bool":true},{"option":"Interneurons","bool":false}],"id":745},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 2-year-old boy developed flaccid paralysis after being infected with poliovirus. Poliovirus enters the central nervous system from peripheral nerves and reaches the soma by retrograde transport. Which of the following proteins is used by the virus to reach the cell body?","answers":[{"option":"Kinesin","bool":false},{"option":"Synaptobrevin","bool":false},{"option":"Synaptotagmin","bool":false},{"option":"Syntaxin","bool":false},{"option":"Dynein","bool":true}],"id":746},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"In an experimental lab, multiple stimuli from different neurons are applied to a post-synaptic neuron simultaneously to generate an action potential. Which one of the following phenomena of a synapse is displayed here?","answers":[{"option":"Presynaptic inhibition","bool":false},{"option":"Divergence","bool":false},{"option":"Spatial summation","bool":true},{"option":"Convergence","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal summation","bool":false}],"id":747},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following types of inhibition is mediated by inhibitory interneurons in the spinal cord and tends to produce the effect of lateral inhibition?","answers":[{"option":"Presynaptic inhibition","bool":false},{"option":"Renshaw cell inhibition","bool":true},{"option":"Reciprocal inhibition","bool":false},{"option":"Postsynaptic inhibition","bool":false},{"option":"Indirect inhibition","bool":false}],"id":748},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 42-year-old jackhammer operator presents in the neurology clinic with decreased sensitivity to high-frequency vibrations in the non-hairy skin of his hands. Which of the following receptors is most likely affected in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Ruffini endings","bool":false},{"option":"Hair sensory fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Pacinian corpuscles","bool":true},{"option":"Merkel discs","bool":false},{"option":"Free nerve endings","bool":false}],"id":749},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"The brain can distinguish between the strengths of light touch and sustained pressure during sensory encoding. Which of the following properties is responsible for this action of the brain?","answers":[{"option":"Type of stimulus","bool":false},{"option":"Frequency of action potential","bool":false},{"option":"Location of receptor","bool":true},{"option":"Duration of stimulus","bool":false},{"option":"Area of receptive field","bool":false}],"id":750},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 32-year-old male presents to the emergency department with head trauma after he fell from a ladder. A physician shines a flashlight into the patient's eyes and observes that the pupillary reflexes are normal. This reflex is used to test the functioning of which of the following structures of the brain?","answers":[{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":true},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Motor cortex","bool":false}],"id":751},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"The lateral lemniscus is part of a pathway carrying which of the following sensations?","answers":[{"option":"Temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Touch","bool":false},{"option":"Auditory","bool":true},{"option":"Pain","bool":false},{"option":"Proprioception","bool":false}],"id":752},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 72-year-old female patient presents to the outpatient clinic with the complaint of being unable to raise her shoulders and turn her head. Investigations reveal a lesion in the medulla. Which of the following cranial nerves is most likely to be affected by this lesion?","answers":[{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglossal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false}],"id":753},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following functions of the brain is affected when there is damage to the peri-aqueductal gray area of the midbrain?","answers":[{"option":"Arousal and alertness of the cerebral cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Control of respiratory movements","bool":false},{"option":"Coordination of head and neck movements","bool":false},{"option":"Maintenance of postural muscle tone","bool":false},{"option":"Endogenous built-in pain suppression","bool":true}],"id":754},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 60-year-old male patient is suspected to be suffering from impairment of the otolith organs based on a detailed neurological examination and a CT scan. Which of the following functions is most likely to be disturbed in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Prediction of disequilibrium of body with a sudden turn","bool":false},{"option":"Elicitation of the vestibulo-ocular reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Rotation of head to one side","bool":false},{"option":"Recognition of angular acceleration of head","bool":false},{"option":"Detection of the position of the head with respect to gravity","bool":true}],"id":755},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"In an animal laboratory, the change in the behavior of a monkey is observed. The monkey has a loss of fear, forgetfulness, and the tendency to place everything in its mouth. Ablation of which of the following structures of the limbic system is the most likely cause for these behavioral changes?","answers":[{"option":"Cingulate gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Prefrontal cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocampus","bool":false},{"option":"Amygdala","bool":true}],"id":756},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 45-year-old male presented to a neurology clinic with complaints of spontaneous and continuous writhing movement of hands, an arm, and face. MRI scans reveal a lesion of the globus pallidus. The patient is manifesting which of the following signs in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Parkinson's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Nystagmus","bool":false},{"option":"Athetosis","bool":true},{"option":"Chorea","bool":false},{"option":"Hemiballismus","bool":false}],"id":757},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"The myelin sheath of the neurons is altered due to the formation of plaques in which of the following disorders of the nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Epilepsy","bool":false},{"option":"Parkinson's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral palsy","bool":false},{"option":"Neurosyphilis","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple sclerosis","bool":true}],"id":758},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following cranial nerves are a part of the parasympathetic nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"III, V, IX, and X","bool":false},{"option":"III, IV, VII, and IX","bool":false},{"option":"V, IX, X, and XII","bool":false},{"option":"IV, V, IX, and X","bool":false},{"option":"III, VII, IX, and X","bool":true}],"id":759},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Before a minor surgical procedure, a local anesthetic is injected by the surgeon to ensure that the patient feels no pain. Which of the following nerve fibers is most likely to be blocked by the local anesthetic?","answers":[{"option":"Type B fibers","bool":false},{"option":"A alpha fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Type C fibers","bool":true},{"option":"A beta fibers","bool":false},{"option":"A gamma fibers","bool":false}],"id":760},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following substances is released by interneurons in the dorsal horn of the spinal cord to inhibit ascending pain signals?","answers":[{"option":"Serotonin","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":false},{"option":"GABA","bool":false},{"option":"Enkephalin","bool":true},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false}],"id":761},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"During voluntary movements, the Golgi tendon organs are involved in providing which of the following information to the central nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Tension developed in the muscle being moved","bool":true},{"option":"Activity of type 1a nerve fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Change in the joint angle produced by movement","bool":false},{"option":"Length of the muscle being moved","bool":false},{"option":"Velocity of movement","bool":false}],"id":762},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following hormones or factors is responsible for inhibiting the action of leptin on the ventromedial nucleus of the hypothalamus and stimulating the lateral hypothalamic nucleus producing a sense of hunger?","answers":[{"option":"Ghrelin","bool":true},{"option":"Stretch of the Gastrointestinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Œ±-MSH","bool":false},{"option":"Leptin","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin","bool":false}],"id":763},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following mechanisms is involved in the conversion of short-term memory to long-term memory?","answers":[{"option":"Post-tetanic potentiation","bool":false},{"option":"Circuit of reverberating neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Long-term potentiation","bool":true},{"option":"Habituation","bool":false},{"option":"Sensitization","bool":false}],"id":764},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 45-year-old male patient suffering from a head injury undergoes a neurological examination. The neurologist observes that the patient can understand both spoken and written words but his speech is slow, poorly articulated, and requires significant effort. Which of the following areas of the cerebral cortex is most likely to be damaged in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Arcuate fasciculus","bool":false},{"option":"Somatosensory area","bool":false},{"option":"Angular gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Wernicke's area","bool":false},{"option":"Broca's area","bool":true}],"id":765},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"The deficiency of which of the following vitamins is marked by anemia, impaired neurotransmitter production, increased homocysteine levels, and neuronal demyelination?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin B2","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B3","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B6","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B12","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin B1","bool":false}],"id":766},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following vitamins is required for the synthesis of neurotransmitters like dopamine, serotonin, and GABA?","answers":[{"option":"Thiamine","bool":false},{"option":"Niacin","bool":false},{"option":"Pyridoxine","bool":true},{"option":"Riboflavin","bool":false},{"option":"Cyanocobalamin","bool":false}],"id":767},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"In the blood-brain barrier, the endothelial cells are tightly packed together by means of tight junctions that are formed by which of the following specialized transmembrane proteins?","answers":[{"option":"Glycophorins","bool":false},{"option":"Claudins","bool":true},{"option":"Integrins","bool":false},{"option":"Selectins","bool":false},{"option":"Rhodopsins","bool":false}],"id":768},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following compounds crosses the blood-brain barrier by means of receptor-mediated transcytosis?","answers":[{"option":"Leucine","bool":false},{"option":"Free fatty acids","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin","bool":true},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylalanine","bool":false}],"id":769},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Parkinson's disease is associated with the loss of specific neurons containing which of the following neurotransmitters?","answers":[{"option":"Dopamine","bool":true},{"option":"GABA","bool":false},{"option":"Indolamines","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false}],"id":770},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A cobweb coagulum is a characteristic finding on CSF examination in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Viral meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Subarachnoid hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Brain tumour","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculous meningitis","bool":true}],"id":771},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 39-year-old female patient presents to the outpatient department with a severe headache for the last 3 days. On physical examination, she is afebrile and normotensive. Fundoscopic examination shows papilledema in the right eye. She was admitted to the hospital for further testing. A day later, she develops right pupillary dilation with impaired ocular movement. These findings are best explained by which of the following lesions?","answers":[{"option":"Subdural hematoma","bool":false},{"option":"Transtentorial medial temporal herniation","bool":true},{"option":"Frontal lobe abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Ruptured berry aneurysm","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocephalus","bool":false}],"id":772},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A female infant born after a full-term pregnancy weighing 3.4kg has an enlarged head with the occipitofrontal circumference (OFC) being 49.5 cm. A cranial ultrasound reveals bilateral ventriculomegaly. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hydrocephalus","bool":true},{"option":"Herniation","bool":false},{"option":"Encephalitis","bool":false},{"option":"Meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral edema","bool":false}],"id":773},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 35-year-old male who has a history of HIV is admitted to the neurology ward with signs and symptoms of encephalitis. Which of the following is a characteristic histopathological finding of HIV encephalitis?","answers":[{"option":"Microglial nodules","bool":false},{"option":"Eosinophilia","bool":false},{"option":"Microglial nodules and multinucleated giant cells","bool":true},{"option":"Gliosis","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophil infiltration","bool":false}],"id":774},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following is not a risk factor for encephalitis?","answers":[{"option":"People with a weak immune system","bool":false},{"option":"People with a strong immune system","bool":true},{"option":"Children under the age of 1 year","bool":false},{"option":"HIV infection","bool":false},{"option":"Older age","bool":false}],"id":775},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 50-year-old female patient who is a known case of an autoimmune disorder visits the neurology clinic with complaints of fatigue, tingling, numbness, muscle weakness, and muscle spasms. CSF analysis reveals oligoclonal bands. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Multiple sclerosis","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebral edema","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral herniation","bool":false},{"option":"Central pontine myelinolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Subdural hematoma","bool":false}],"id":776},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 5-month-old boy is brought to the outpatient clinic with complaints of global developmental delay, generalized weakness of the body, and jerky eye movement. There is also a family history of his 5-year-old  brother having the same complaints. MRI scans of the brain reveal symmetrical lesions. Genetic studies reveal a mutation in the ABCD1 gene located at the X chromosome. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Canavan disease","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenoleukodystrophy","bool":true},{"option":"Alexander disease","bool":false},{"option":"Metachromatic leukodystrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple sclerosis","bool":false}],"id":777},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 5-year-old boy is admitted to the neurology ward with complaints of headache, photophobia, and neck rigidity. He is a suspected case of meningitis. Which of the following is the best diagnostic investigation for meningitis?","answers":[{"option":"CSF analysis","bool":true},{"option":"Urine test","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"MRI brain","bool":false}],"id":778},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 1-year-old girl is diagnosed with bacterial meningitis. Which of the following findings in the CSF analysis are suggestive of bacterial meningitis?","answers":[{"option":"Increased glucose content in CSF","bool":false},{"option":"100-2000 polymorphs","bool":true},{"option":"No lymphocytes and polymorphs","bool":false},{"option":"Clear CSF","bool":false},{"option":"100-500 lymphocytes","bool":false}],"id":779},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A young male patient presents to the emergency department in an unconscious state. The parents give a history of him swimming in a pool for the last few days. CSF analysis reveals small flask-shaped amoeba. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Naegleria fowleri","bool":true},{"option":"Acanthamoeba","bool":false},{"option":"Cysticercosis","bool":false},{"option":"Candida albicans","bool":false},{"option":"Prion disease","bool":false}],"id":780},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 60-year-old male patient with a history of hypertension for the last 10 years is brought to the emergency department in an unconscious state. History also reveals that the patient is non-compliant with his medication for hypertension. MRI and CT scan brain show a lobar hemorrhage. Which of the following is the most likely cause of this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Arteriovenous malformation","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral amyloid angiopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":true}],"id":781},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following is an inhibitory neurotransmitter that causes hyperpolarization of neurons?","answers":[{"option":"Glutamate","bool":false},{"option":"GABA (gamma aminobutyric acid)","bool":true},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false}],"id":782},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"The analgesic properties of opioids are primarily mediated by which of the following receptors?","answers":[{"option":"Adrenergic receptor","bool":false},{"option":"Kappa receptor","bool":false},{"option":"Mu receptor","bool":true},{"option":"Delta receptor","bool":false},{"option":"Cholinergic receptor","bool":false}],"id":783},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 36-year-old man is hired as a laboratory worker and he will be handling Rabies related viruses and vaccines. Which of the following vaccines is he advised to get?","answers":[{"option":"Pre-exposure prophylaxis","bool":true},{"option":"H-RIG (human rabies immunoglobulin)","bool":false},{"option":"Post-exposure prophylaxis","bool":false},{"option":"E-RIG (equine rabies immunoglobulin)","bool":false},{"option":"Tetanus","bool":false}],"id":784},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"A 32-year-old mother of two children visits a primary healthcare center with complaints of feeling sad, irritable, and empty, and often finds herself crying for no reason for the past three months. She has a loss of interest in all activities and finds it really hard to carry out her daily activities. She feels as if she would be better off dead and even has thoughts about taking her life at times. Which one of the following disorders is she most likely suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Schizophrenia","bool":false},{"option":"Bipolar disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Post-traumatic stress disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Anxiety","bool":false},{"option":"Depression","bool":true}],"id":785},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Which of the following terms refers to the constant presence of a disease or infectious agent within its usual or expected frequency in a given geographical area or population group?","answers":[{"option":"Sporadic","bool":false},{"option":"Epidemic","bool":false},{"option":"Incidence","bool":false},{"option":"Prevalence","bool":false},{"option":"Endemic","bool":true}],"id":786},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"Polic is now endemic in only 2 countries; Pakistan and Afghanistan. Two very effective polio vaccines, the oral and injectable vaccines are being given in the EPI program, and in addition, special immunization campaigns are repeatedly conducted all over Pakistan to eradicate polio. In the routine EPI schedule, which of the following is the correct age for the administration of the injectable polio vaccine (IPV)?","answers":[{"option":"10 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"9 months","bool":false},{"option":"14 weeks and 9 months","bool":true},{"option":"14 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"6 weeks","bool":false}],"id":787},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"John diverts his attention to stop thinking about disturbing events in order to prevent himself from experiencing any overwhelming negative emotions. Which of the following term best corresponds to this strategy?","answers":[{"option":"Cognitive reappraisal","bool":false},{"option":"Antecedent based strategies","bool":true},{"option":"Response focused strategies","bool":false},{"option":"Situation selection","bool":false},{"option":"Response modulation","bool":false}],"id":788},{"info":["2nd-year/neuroscience/compiled","2nd-year/neuroscience/2023"],"question":"During a flood, a mental health professional is given the responsibility to provide psychological first aid and conduct crisis intervention. Which of the following is the 7th and last stage of the crisis intervention model?","answers":[{"option":"Develop and formulate an action plan","bool":false},{"option":"Plan and conduct a crisis intervention","bool":false},{"option":"Generate and explore alternatives","bool":false},{"option":"Establish follow-up plan and agreement","bool":true},{"option":"Deal with feelings and emotions","bool":false}],"id":789}]
export default arr